[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "Which of the following language is MongoDB written in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Javascript",
            "b) C",
            "c) C++",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MongoDB (from humongous) is a cross-platform document-oriented database."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB is classified as a NoSQL database",
            "b) MongoDB favours XML format more than JSON",
            "c) MongoDB is column oriented database store",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB supports JSON format compared to XML."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "Which of the following format is supported by MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL",
            "b) XML",
            "c) BSON",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB eschews the traditional table-based relational database structure in favor of JSON-like documents with dynamic schemas."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "MongoDB Queries can return specific fields of documents which also include user-defined __________ functions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Javascript",
            "b) C",
            "c) C++",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB supports search by field, range queries, regular expression searches."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Secondary indices are not available in MongoDB",
            "b) MongoDB supports search by field, range queries, regular expression searches",
            "c) MongoDB can store the business subject in the minimal number of documents",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Any field in a MongoDB document can be indexed."
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "Initial release of MongoDB was in the year?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2000",
            "b) 2005",
            "c) 2009",
            "d) 2011"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB is developed by the software company 10gen in October 2007 as a component of a planned platform as a service product."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "MongoDB has been adopted as ________ software by a number of major websites and services.",
        "Options": [
            "a) frontend",
            "b) backend",
            "c) proprietary",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB is the most popular NoSQL database system."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "MongoDB is a _________ database that provides high performance, high availability, and easy scalability.",
        "Options": [
            "a) graph",
            "b) key value",
            "c) document",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Documents (objects) map nicely to programming language data types."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "Dynamic schema in MongoDB makes ____________ easier for applications.",
        "Options": [
            "a) inheritance",
            "b) polymorphism",
            "c) encapsulation",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Relational databases require that schemas be defined before you can add data."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "With ________ MongoDB supports a complete backup solution and full deployment monitoring.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MMS",
            "b) AMS",
            "c) CMS",
            "d) DMS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MMS stands for MongoDB Management Service and is available to all users in the cloud and on-premises as part of MongoDB Standard and Enterprise Subscriptions."
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "MongoDB provides high ____________  with replica sets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) performance",
            "b) availability",
            "c) scalability",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A replica set consists of two or more copies of the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB cannot be used as a file system",
            "b) MongoDB can run over single servers only",
            "c) Embedded documents and arrays reduce need for joins",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB can run over multiple servers, balancing the load and/or duplicating data to keep the system up and running in case of hardware failure."
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "___________ replicas maintain a copy of the data on the primary using built-in replication.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Primary",
            "b) Secondary",
            "c) Backup",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a primary replica fails, the replica set automatically conducts an election process to determine which secondary should become the primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "MongoDB scales horizontally using _________ for load balancing purpose.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Replication",
            "b) Partitioning",
            "c) Sharding",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The user chooses a shard key, which determines how the data in a collection will be distributed."
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Each replica set member will act in the role of primary replica only",
            "b) The primary replica performs all writes and reads by default",
            "c) Secondaries can also perform read operations, but the data is eventually consistent by default",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Each replica set member may act in the role of the primary or secondary replica at any time."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "MongoDB can be used as a ____________ taking advantage of load balancing and data replication features over multiple machines for storing files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) AMS",
            "b) CMS",
            "c) File system",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The data is split into ranges (based on the shard key) and distributed across multiple shards."
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "_____________ can be used for batch processing of data and aggregation operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hive",
            "b) MapReduce",
            "c) Oozie",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The aggregation framework enables users to obtain the kind of results for which the SQL GROUP BY clause is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "MongoDB supports fixed-size collections called ____________ collections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) capped",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This type of collection maintains insertion order and, once the specified size has been reached, behaves like a circular queue."
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "MongoDB uses a ____________ lock that allows concurrent read access to a database but exclusive write access to a single write operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) readers",
            "b) readers-writer",
            "c) writer",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Before version 2.2, this lock was implemented on a per-mongod basis. Since version 2.2, the lock has been implemented at the database level."
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "Which of the following sorting is not supported by MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) collation",
            "b) collection",
            "c) heap",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB does not support collation-based sorting and is limited to byte-wise comparison via memcmp."
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a NoSQL database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server",
            "b) MongoDB",
            "c) Cassandra",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Microsoft SQL Server is a relational database management system developed by Microsoft."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Documents can contain many different key-value pairs, or key-array pairs, or even nested documents",
            "b) MongoDB has official drivers for a variety of popular programming languages and development environments",
            "c) When compared to relational databases, NoSQL databases are more scalable and provide superior performance",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are also a large number of unofficial or community-supported drivers for other programming languages and frameworks."
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a NoSQL Database Type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL",
            "b) Document databases",
            "c) JSON",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Document databases pair each key with a complex data structure known as a document."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a wide-column store?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cassandra",
            "b) Riak",
            "c) MongoDB",
            "d) Redis"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Wide-column stores such as Cassandra and HBase are optimized for queries over large datasets, and store columns of data together, instead of rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Non Relational databases require that schemas be defined before you can add data",
            "b) NoSQL databases are built to allow the insertion of data without a predefined schema",
            "c) NewSQL databases are built to allow the insertion of data without a predefined schema",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There’s also no way, using a relational database, to effectively address data that’s completely unstructured or unknown in advance."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "“Sharding” a database across many server instances can be achieved with _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) LAN",
            "b) SAN",
            "c) MAN",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: “Sharding” a database across many server instances can be achieved with SQL databases, but usually is accomplished through SANs and other complex arrangements for making hardware act as a single server."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "Most NoSQL databases support automatic __________ meaning that you get high availability and disaster recovery.",
        "Options": [
            "a) processing",
            "b) scalability",
            "c) replication",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The storage environment is essentially virtualized from the developer’s perspective."
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "Which of the following are the simplest NoSQL databases?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Key-value",
            "b) Wide-column",
            "c) Document",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Every single item in the database is stored as an attribute name (or “key”), together with its value in Key-value stores."
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "________ stores are used to store information about networks, such as social connections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Key-value",
            "b) Wide-column",
            "c) Document",
            "d) Graph"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Graph stores include Neo4J and HyperGraphDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "NoSQL databases is used mainly for handling large volumes of ______________ data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) unstructured",
            "b) structured",
            "c) semi-structured",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB is an a typical choice for unstructured data storage."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "What is the interactive shell for MongoDB called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongo",
            "b) mongodb",
            "c) dbmong",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Interactive shell lets developers view, insert, remove, and update data in their databases, as well as get replication information, set up sharding, shut down servers, execute JavaScript, and more."
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Humon.io is a Web based GUI for MongoDB",
            "b) Mongo3 is a java-based GUI",
            "c) NoSQL Manager for MongoDB is an MS Windows GUI application for MongoDB management with Shell",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: NoSQL Manager for MongoDB is similar to MMS."
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "Administrative information in MongoDB can also be accessed through _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) dashboard",
            "b) web interface",
            "c) psql shell",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Web interface is a simple webpage that serves information about the current server status. By default, this interface is 1000 ports above the database port (28017)."
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "Which of the following is web-based client software for MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BI Studio",
            "b) Database Master",
            "c) Fang of Mongo",
            "d) Mongo3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Futon4Mongo is a clone of the CouchDB-Futon-Web-Interface for MongoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoHub is a native OS-X-application for MongoDB management",
            "b) Cassandra is most popular for its document stores management system",
            "c) MongoDB is the fourth most popular type of database management system",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB is most popular for document stores."
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "___________ provides statistics on the per-collection level.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongosniff",
            "b) mongotop",
            "c) mongooplog",
            "d) mongofiles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongotop is a command-line tool providing a method to track the amount of time a MongoDB instance spends reading and writing data."
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "___________ is a command-line tool that displays a summary list of status statistics for a currently running MongoDB instance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostat",
            "b) mongotop",
            "c) mongooplog",
            "d) mongofiles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It describes how many inserts, updates, removes, queries, and commands were performed, as well as what percentage of the time the database was locked and how much memory it is using."
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "mongostat tool is similar to the UNIX/Linux _________ utility.",
        "Options": [
            "a) stats",
            "b) vim",
            "c) vmstat",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: vmstat is a computer system monitoring tool that collects and displays summary information about operating system memory, processes, interrupts, paging and block I/O."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "Which of the following tool is similar to the UNIX/Linux top utility?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongosniff",
            "b) mongotop",
            "c) mongooplog",
            "d) mongofiles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By default, mongotop returns values every second."
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "mongosniff requires the ___________ network library and is only available for Unix-like systems.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Wirecap",
            "b) Libpcap",
            "c) Wcap",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A cross-platform alternative is an open source Wireshark packet analyzer which has full support for the MongoDB wire protocol."
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "Which of the following provides low-level tracing/sniffing view into database activity?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongosniff",
            "b) mongotop",
            "c) mongooplog",
            "d) mongofiles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: mongosniff is a command-line tool providing a sniffing view into database activity by monitoring network traffic going to and from MongoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB supports a “standalone” or single-instance operation",
            "b) Sharded clusters provide high performance replication with automated failover",
            "c) Replica sets make it possible to partition large data sets over many machines transparently to the users",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB users combine replica sets and sharded clusters to provide high levels redundancy for large data sets transparently for applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "Which of the following is simplest tool for installation of MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongorestore",
            "b) mongooplog",
            "c) mongodump",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongooplog is a simple tool that polls operations from the replication oplog of a remote server."
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "Which of the following network analyzer fully supports MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Wireshark",
            "b) Riakshark",
            "c) Snort",
            "d) Suricata"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Wireshark is cross platform and open source network sniffer."
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BSON is difficult to code and manage",
            "b) MongoDB stores data in JSON documents",
            "c) JSON provides a rich data model that seamlessly maps to native programming language types",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: BSON is easy to code and manage."
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": " ___________ manipulate files stored in your MongoDB instance in GridFS.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongorestore",
            "b) mongofiles",
            "c) mongosupport",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongofiles provides an interface between objects stored in your file system and GridFS."
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "__________ is a command-line utility to import content from a JSON, CSV, or TSV.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongorestore",
            "b) mongofiles",
            "c) mongosupport",
            "d) mongoimport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Import content from a JSON, CSV, or TSV export is created by mongoexport."
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used for creating a binary export of the contents of a Mongo database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongodump",
            "b) mongofiles",
            "c) mongosupport",
            "d) mongoimport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: mongodump is a utility for creating a binary export of the contents of a database."
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "Which of the following tool can be used to reload a database dump?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongorestore",
            "b) mongofiles",
            "c) mongosupport",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The mongorestore program writes data from a binary database dump created by mongodump to a MongoDB instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "_____________ is a native OS-X-application for MongoDB management.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Opricot",
            "b) MongoHub",
            "c) UMongo",
            "d) 3T MongoChe"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Opricot is a browser-based MongoDB-Shell, implemented in PHP."
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a metapackage for enterprise?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongodb-enterprise",
            "b) mongodb-enterprise-server",
            "c) mongodb-enterprise-mongos",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: mongodb-enterprise is a metapackage that will automatically install the four component packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB provides packages of the officially supported MongoDB Enterprise builds in it’s own repository",
            "b) mongodb-enterprise-tool package contains the mongo shell",
            "c) mongodb-enterprise-shell package contains the mongo tools",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This repository provides the MongoDB Enterprise distribution in many packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "______ package contains the mongod daemon and associated configuration and init scripts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongodb-enterprise",
            "b) mongodb-enterprise-server",
            "c) mongodb-enterprise-mongos",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongodb-enterprise-mongos package contains the mongos daemon."
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a part of mongodb-enterprise-tools?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongodump",
            "b) mongotop",
            "c) mongodown",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: mongodb-enterprise-tools package contains the following MongoDB tools: mongoimport bsondump, mongodump, mongoexport, mongofiles, mongoimport, mongooplog, mongoperf, mongorestore, mongostat, and mongotop."
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) As of version 2.0.0, there are no control scripts for mongos",
            "b) The mongodb-enterprise package includes various control scripts, including the init script /etc/rc.d/init.d/mongod",
            "c) You must configure SELinux to allow MongoDB to start on Red Hat Linux-based systems",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: As of version 3.0.0, there are no control scripts for mongos.The mongos process is used only in sharding."
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "MongoDB only provides Enterprise packages for Ubuntu ________ LTS.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13.04",
            "b) 12.10",
            "c) 12.04",
            "d) 13.10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The package structure and names have changed as of version 2.6."
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the Ubuntu package management tool?",
        "Options": [
            "a) wapt",
            "b) dpkg",
            "c) capt",
            "d) wat"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Ubuntu package management tools (i.e. dpkg and apt) ensure package consistency and authenticity by requiring that distributors sign packages with GPG keys."
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "Command to install the latest stable version of MongoDB Enterprise in Ubuntu is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sudo apt-get install mongodb",
            "b) sudo apt-get install mongodb-enterprise",
            "c) sudo apt-get install mongodb-ent",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To install a specific release of MongoDB Enterprise, specify each component package individually and append the version number to the package name."
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "mongod process is stopped by issuing which of the following command?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sudo service mongod start",
            "b) sudo service mongod stop",
            "c) sudo service mongod restart",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To stop MongoDB, press Control+C in the terminal where the mongod instance is running."
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "____________ package contains the mongo shell.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongodb-enterprise",
            "b) mongodb-enterprise-server",
            "c) mongodb-enterprise-shell",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: mongodb-enterprise-mongos package contains the mongos daemon."
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "To install the latest stable version of MongoDB on SUSE, issue ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sudo zypper install mongodb-enterprise",
            "b) sudo zypper update mongodb-enterprise",
            "c) sudo zyp install mongodb-enterprise",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you install the packages, you choose whether to install the current release or a previous one. This step provides the commands for both."
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB can be installed on SUSE which is a Linux flavour",
            "b) MongoDB Enterprise is available on select platforms and contains support for several features related to security and monitoring",
            "c) A commercial edition of MongoDB that includes additional features",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MongoDB is a server process that runs on Linux, Windows and OS X."
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "The MongoDB instance stores its _________ files in /var/lib/mongo by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) log",
            "b) data",
            "c) replica",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can specify alternate log and data file directories in /etc/mongod.conf."
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "The MongoDB process listens on port _________ by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 27017",
            "b) 27170",
            "c) 27107",
            "d) 26017"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Clients connect to the MongoDB process, optionally authenticate themselves if security is turned on, and perform a sequence of actions, such as inserts, queries and updates."
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If you change the user that runs the MongoDB process, you must modify the access control rights",
            "b) The MongoDB instance stores its data files in /var/log/mongodb by default",
            "c) MongoDB uses memory mapped files for data management for efficiency",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MongoDB instance stores its data files in /var/lib/mongo and its log files in /var/log/mongodb by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "Which of the following file is a MongoDB configuration file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongodb.conf",
            "b) mongod.conf",
            "c) mongodb.con",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Enterprise packages include an example SNMP configuration file named mongod.conf."
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "User account running mongod has _______ permissions for the directory.",
        "Options": [
            "a) write only",
            "b) read only",
            "c) read and write",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To run MongoDB, run the mongod process at the system prompt."
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "___________ allows you to scale your cluster linearly by adding more machines.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vertical sharding",
            "b) Autosharding",
            "c) Horizontal sharding",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is possible to increase capacity without any downtime, which is very important on the web when load can increase suddenly and bringing down the website for extended maintenance can cost your business large amounts of revenue."
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "MongoDB is installed unattended on Windows from the command line using ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) msi.exe",
            "b) msiexec.exe",
            "c) exec.exe",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB requires a data directory to store all data. MongoDB’s default data directory path is \\data\\db."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "Sometimes mongod.exe is visible on public networks without running in _________ Mode with the auth setting.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Permanent",
            "b) Secure",
            "c) Primary",
            "d) Protected"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB is designed to be run in trusted environments, and the database does not enable “Secure Mode” by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "____________ does not dump the content of the local database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongoshell",
            "b) mongodump",
            "c) mongolocaldump",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongodump can read data from either mongod or mongos instances, in addition to reading directly from MongoDB data files without an active mongod."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The data format used by mongodump from version 2.2 or later is incompatible with earlier versions of mongod",
            "b) The replica role confers no additional access, in keeping with the policy of least privilege",
            "c) To backup a given database’s users, you must have the replace action on the admin database’s admin.system.users collection",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Do not use recent versions of mongodump to back up older data stores."
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "To backup all the databases in a cluster via mongodump, you should have the ___________ role.",
        "Options": [
            "a) restore",
            "b) backup",
            "c) replication",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The backup role provides the required privileges for backing up all databases. "
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "___________ is a routing service for MongoDB shard configurations that processes queries from the application layer.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongos",
            "c) mongocon",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: From the perspective of the application, a mongos instance behaves identically to any other MongoDB instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To backup a given database, you must have read access on the database",
            "b) The backup role confers no additional access, in keeping with the policy of least privilege",
            "c) mongodumplocal overwrites output files if they exist in the backup data folder",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To backup the system.profile collection, which is created when you activate database profiling, you must have additional read access on this collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "__________  sends all diagnostic logging information to a log file instead of to standard output or to the host’s syslog system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) syspath",
            "b) syslog",
            "c) logpath",
            "d) syspathlog"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: By default, MongoDB overwrites the log file when the process restarts."
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "___________ is the primary daemon process for the MongoDB system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongos",
            "b) mongod",
            "c) logpath",
            "d) syspathlog"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It handles data requests, manages data access, and performs background management operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "__________ is a diagnostic tool for inspecting BSON files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) jsondump",
            "b) bsondump",
            "c) bsondumpjson",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The bsondump converts BSON files into human-readable formats, including JSON."
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a utility to check disk I/O performance independently of MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongoperf",
            "b) mongoio",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Specify options to mongoperf using a JavaScript document."
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "____________ utility makes it possible to manipulate files stored in your MongoDB instance in GridFS objects from the command line.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongoperf",
            "b) mongoio",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) mongofiles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All mongofiles commands have the following form:mongofiles <options> <commands> <filename>. "
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "__________ is a part of the standard MongoDB distribution and provides a full JavaScript environment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongodb",
            "c) mongo",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: mongo provides complete access to the JavaScript language and all standard functions as well as a full database interface for MongoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MMS provides backup and monitoring",
            "b) MongoDB can also be configured for data replication",
            "c) MMS is available to all users in the cloud and on-premises as part of MongoDB Standard and Enterprise Subscriptions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MongoDB is limited to a total data size of about 2GB for all databases in 32-bit mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "mongo looks for a database server listening on port 27017 on the ________ interface.",
        "Options": [
            "a) web",
            "b) localhost",
            "c) web host",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To connect to a server on a different port or interface, use the –port and –host options."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "After starting the mongo shell, your session will use the ________ database by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongo",
            "b) master",
            "c) test",
            "d) primary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: At any time, db operation at the mongo shell is used to report the name of the current database.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB works right out of the box, and you can dive right into developing your application, instead of spending a lot of time fine-tuning obscure database configurations",
            "b) MongoDB works hard to be very easy to install, configure, maintain, and use",
            "c) MongoDB does not provide a lot of the features of a traditional RDBMS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB focuses on flexibility, power, speed, and ease of use."
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "___________ command display the list of databases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) show db",
            "b) show dbs",
            "c) show data",
            "d) display dbs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Show dbs print a list of all databases on the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation is used to switch to new database mydb?",
        "Options": [
            "a) use dbs",
            "b) use db",
            "c) use mydb",
            "d) use mydbs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: .Confirm that your session has the mydb database as context, by checking the value of the db object, which returns the name of the current database."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "Which of the following also returns a list of databases?",
        "Options": [
            "a) show databases",
            "b) show database",
            "c) display dbs",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: show databases is new in version 2.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "Command to check existence of collection is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) show collection",
            "b) show collections",
            "c) show collect",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mongo shell will return the list of the collections in the current database."
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is used to query documents in collections?",
        "Options": [
            "a) find",
            "b) move",
            "c) shell",
            "d) replace"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The find() method with no parameters returns all documents from a collection and returns all fields for the documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "When you query a collection, MongoDB returns a ________ object that contains the results of the query.",
        "Options": [
            "a) row",
            "b) cursor",
            "c) colums",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mongo shell then iterates over the cursor to display the results."
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A database is a set of key-value pairs",
            "b) A MongoDB deployment hosts a number of databases",
            "c) A document holds a set of collections",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A database holds a set of collections. A collection holds a set of documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "Which of the following method returns true if the cursor has documents?",
        "Options": [
            "a) hasMethod()",
            "b) hasNext()",
            "c) hasDoc()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: hasNext() returns true if the cursor returned by the db.collection.find() query can iterate further to return more documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "____________ method renders the document in a JSON-like format.",
        "Options": [
            "a) displayjson",
            "b) print",
            "c) printjson",
            "d) printdoc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: printjson() operation displays all documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Documents have static schema in MongoDB",
            "b) Eventually-consistent reads can be distributed over replicated servers",
            "c) Indexes can include keys from embedded documents and arrays",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Dynamic schema means that documents in the same collection do not need to have the same set of fields or structure, and common fields in a collection’s documents may hold different types of data."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is called while accessing documents using the array index notation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) cur.toArray()",
            "b) cursor.toArray()",
            "c) doc.toArray()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The toArray() method returns an array that contains all the documents from a cursor."
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "The mongo shell and the drivers provide several cursor methods that call on the cursor returned by the _______ method to modify its behavior.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cursor()",
            "b) find()",
            "c) findc()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The method iterates completely the cursor, loading all the documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "Which of the following method corresponds to Order by clause in SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sort()",
            "b) order()",
            "c) orderby()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The sort() method orders the documents in the result set."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "The __________ method limits the number of documents in the result set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) limit()",
            "b) limitOf()",
            "c) limitBy()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: limit() corresponds to the LIMIT statement in SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "Which of the following line skips the first 5 documents in the bios collection and returns all remaining documents?",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.bios.find().limit( 5 )",
            "b) db.bios.find().skip( 1 )",
            "c) db.bios.find().skip( 5 )",
            "d) db.bios.find().sort( 5 )"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The skip() method controls the starting point of the results set."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Collection is a group of MongoDB documents",
            "b) MongoDB is an open-source document database, and leading NoSQL database",
            "c) Collections do not enforce a schema",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: From the mongo shell, use the for loop. If the testData collection does not exist, MongoDB will implicitly create the collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "Which of the following method returns a cursor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) find",
            "b) sort",
            "c) skip",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Documents within a collection can have different fields."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database is a physical container for collections",
            "b) A single MongoDB server typically has single databases",
            "c) Collection is the equivalent of an RDBMS table",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The find() method returns a cursor. To iterate the cursor and return more documents, type it in the mongo shell."
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "_id is a ________ bytes hexadecimal number which assures the uniqueness of every document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: insertData() JavaScript function that follows creates new data for use in testing or training by either creating a new collection or appending data to an existing collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement will insert 400 documents in to the testData collection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) insertData(\"test\", \"testData\", 200)",
            "b) insertData(\"test\", \"testData\", 400)",
            "c) insertData(\"test\", \"testData\", 600)",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A single MongoDB server typically has multiple databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "The mongo shell loads and parses the ___________ file on startup.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongo.js",
            "b) mongoc.js",
            "c) mongorc.js",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can provide _id while inserting the document."
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "To iterate the cursor and return more documents, type _________ in the mongo shell.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cursor",
            "b) it",
            "c) next",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the collection and database do not exist, MongoDB creates them implicitly before inserting documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "Which of the following key is used to denote uniqueness in the collection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) _id",
            "b) id",
            "c) id_",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Store the function in your .mongorc.js file."
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "A query may include a ___________ that specifies the fields from the matching documents to return.",
        "Options": [
            "a) selection",
            "b) projection",
            "c) union",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Queries specify criteria, or conditions, that identify the documents that MongoDB returns to the clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Secondary indexes allow applications to store a view of a portion of the collection in an efficient data structure",
            "b) MongoDB has full support for secondary indexes",
            "c) Most indexes store an ordered representation of all values of a field or a group of fields",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Secondary indexes are used to enhance the performance of common queries and updates."
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "MongoDB stores all documents in _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) tables",
            "b) collections",
            "c) rows",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Collections are analogous to a table in relational databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "In MongoDB _________ operations modify the data of a single collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CRUD",
            "b) GRID",
            "c) READ",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Data modification refers to operations that create, update, or delete data."
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Indexes cannot enforce uniqueness in collection",
            "b) CRUD stands for create, read, update, and delete",
            "c) CRUD application is the most simplest application",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Indexes may also enforce uniqueness, store objects in a geospatial representation, and facilitate text search."
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation adds a new document to the users collection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) add",
            "b) insert",
            "c) truncate",
            "d) drop"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For the update and delete operations, you can specify the criteria to select the documents to update or remove."
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "Which of the following preference determines how the client direct read operations to the set?",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) update",
            "d) delete"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For replica sets and sharded clusters with replica set components, applications specify read preferences."
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "Applications can also control the behavior of write operations using _______ concern.",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) truncate",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Write concern semantics allow clients to specify the assurance that MongoDB provides when reporting on the success of a write operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "MongoDB process collection of documents using _________ operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hbase",
            "b) Hive",
            "c) Map-reduce",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In addition to the basic queries, MongoDB provides several data aggregation features."
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "Which of the following pipeline is used for aggregation in MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) data processing",
            "b) information processing",
            "c) knowledge processing",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB can return counts of the number of documents that match a query, or return the number of distinct values for a field."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "The order of documents returned by a query is not defined unless you specify a ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) sortfind()",
            "b) sortelse()",
            "c) sort()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can modify the query to impose limits, skips, and sort orders."
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Queries specify criteria, or conditions, that identify the documents that MongoDB returns to the clients",
            "b) Write operations, or queries, retrieve data stored in the database",
            "c) The selection limits the amount of data that MongoDB returns to the client over the network",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MongoDB, queries select documents from a single collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "In aggregation pipeline, the _______ pipeline stage provides access to MongoDB queries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $catch",
            "b) $match",
            "c) $batch",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Operations that modify existing documents (i.e. updates) use the same query syntax as queries to select documents to update."
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "Which of the following method returns one document?",
        "Options": [
            "a) findOne()",
            "b) findOne1()",
            "c) selectOne()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB provides a db.collection.findOne() method as a special case of find() that returns a single document."
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sort() modifier sorts the results by age in ascending order",
            "b) Queries in MongoDB return all fields in all matching documents by default",
            "c) To scale the amount of data that MongoDB sends to applications, include a projection in the queries.",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: By projecting results with a subset of fields, applications reduce their network overhead and processing requirements."
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the second argument to projection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) findOne()",
            "b) findOne1()",
            "c) selectOne()",
            "d) find()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Projections are the second argument to the find() method, which specifies a list of fields to return or list fields to exclude in the result documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "Which of the following query selects documents in the records collection that match the condition { “user_id”: { $lt: 42 } }?",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.records.findOne( { “user_id”: { $lt: 42 } }, { “history”: 0 } )",
            "b) db.records.find( { “user_id”: { $lt: 42 } }, { “history”: 0 } )",
            "c) db.records.findOne( { “user_id”: { $lt: 42 } }, { “history”: 1 } )",
            "d) db.records.select( { “user_id”: { $lt: 42 } }, { “history”: 0 } )"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Query uses the projection { “history”: 0 } to exclude the history field from the documents in the result set."
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "Which of the following functionality is used for aggregation framework?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $match",
            "b) $project",
            "c) $projectmatch",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For related projection functionality in the aggregation framework pipeline, use the $project pipeline stage."
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "To suppress the _id field from the result set, specify _________ in the projection document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) _id: 1",
            "b) _id: 0",
            "c) _id: it",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By default, the _id field is included in the results."
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a projection operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $slice",
            "b) $elemMatch",
            "c) $",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: For fields that contain arrays, MongoDB provides the following projection operators: $elemMatch, $slice, and $."
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "Which of the following flag can be set by mongo shell?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Timeout",
            "b) noTimeout",
            "c) Time",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By default, the server will automatically close the cursor after 10 minutes of inactivity or if client has exhausted the cursor."
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Intervening read operations on a document may result in a cursor that returns a document more than once if that document has changed",
            "b) The MongoDB server returns the query results in batches",
            "c) Subsequent batch size is 50 megabytes",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For most queries, the first batch returns 101 documents or just enough documents to exceed 1 megabyte."
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "Which of the following will display complete list of available cursor flags?",
        "Options": [
            "a) cursor.Option()",
            "b) cursor.addOption()",
            "c) cursor.addOptions()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You should either close the cursor manually or exhaust the cursor."
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "To describe the message structure, a ________ like struct is used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pascal",
            "b) C++",
            "c) C",
            "d) Java"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The standard message header is typed as MsgHeader. Integer constants are in capitals (e.g. ZERO for the integer value of 0)."
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The MongoDB Wire Protocol is a simple socket-based, request-response style protocol",
            "b) For queries that include a sort operation without an index, the server must load all the documents in memory to perform the sort before returning any results",
            "c) Clients communicate with the database server through a regular TCP/IP socket",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: As you iterate through the cursor and reach the end of the returned batch, if there are more results, cursor.next() will perform a getmore operation to retrieve the next batch."
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "______________ specifies the number of documents to return in each batch of the response from the MongoDB instance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cursor.batchSize(size)",
            "b) cursor.Size(size)",
            "c) cursor.batch(size)",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Specifying 1 or a negative number is analogous to using the limit() method."
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "The __________ method returns a document that includes a metrics field.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.serverStats()",
            "b) db.serverStatus()",
            "c) db.status()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The metrics field contains a cursor with number of timed out cursors since the last server restart."
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "____________ is a client or database-generated identifier that uniquely identifies this message.",
        "Options": [
            "a) messageLength",
            "b) responseTo",
            "c) requestID",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For the case of client-generated messages, it will be returned in the responseTo field of the OP_REPLY message. "
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "Which of the following operator is not very selective?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $nine",
            "b) $nin",
            "c) $ain",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The inequality operators $nin and $ne are not very selective since they often match a large portion of the index."
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "An index cannot cover a query on a _______ collection when run against a mongos if the index does not contain the shard key.",
        "Options": [
            "a) vertical",
            "b) sharded",
            "c) horizontal",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB can both match the query conditions and return the results using only the index."
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "___________ concern describes the guarantee that MongoDB provides when reporting on the success of a write operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Write",
            "b) Read",
            "c) Update",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The strength of the write concerns determine the level of guarantee."
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Read operations on sharded clusters are most efficient when directed to a specific shard",
            "b) Sharded clusters allow you to partition a data set among a cluster of mongod instances in a way that is nearly transparent to the application",
            "c) For a sharded cluster, applications issue operations to one of the mongos instances associated with the cluster",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Queries to sharded collections should include the collection’s shard key."
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "When inserts, updates and deletes have a _________ write concern, write operations return quickly.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strong",
            "b) weak",
            "c) average",
            "d) very strong"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: With stronger write concerns, clients wait after sending a write operation for MongoDB to confirm the write operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "The mongo shell and the MongoDB drivers use __________ as the default write concern.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nacknowledged",
            "b) Acknowledgement",
            "c) Acknowledged",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB allows clients to read documents inserted or modified before it commits these modifications to disk, regardless of write concern level or journaling configuration."
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When a query does not include a shard key, the mongos can use cluster metadata from the config database to route the queries to shards",
            "b) On larger clusters, scatter gather queries are unfeasible for routine operations",
            "c) Replica sets use read preferences to determine where and how to route read operations to members of the replica set",
            "d) None of the mwntioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If a query does not include the shard key, the mongos must direct the query to all shards in the cluster. "
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "_____________ is used to control mongod commits in the journal.",
        "Options": [
            "a) commitIntervMs",
            "b) commitInterval",
            "c) commitIntervalMs",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For replica sets, write operations are durable only after a write replicates and commits to the journal on a majority of the voting members of the set."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "Clients can set a __________ value as part of a replica acknowledged write concern.",
        "Options": [
            "a) timeout",
            "b) wtimeout",
            "c) waittimeout",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  If the write concern is not satisfied in the specified interval, the operation returns an error, even if the write concern will eventually succeed."
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "MongoDB does not ___________ modifications made before the wtimeout interval expired.",
        "Options": [
            "a) commit",
            "b) rollback",
            "c) save",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The driver’s ability to detect network errors depends on the system’s networking configuration."
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "With an __________ write concern, MongoDB does not acknowledge the receipt of write operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nacknowledged",
            "b) Acknowledgement",
            "c) Acknowledged",
            "d) Unacknowledged"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Unacknowledged is similar to errors ignored."
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "With a receipt acknowledged write concern, the _________confirms that it received the write operation and applied the change to the in-memory view of data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongos",
            "c) mongo",
            "d) mongoc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Acknowledged write concern allows clients to catch network, duplicate key, and other errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "Indexes are typically available in ______ or located sequentially on disk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) RAM",
            "b) ROM",
            "c) CMOS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Querying only the index can be much faster than querying documents outside of the index."
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Query selectivity refers to how well the query predicate excludes or filters out documents in a collection",
            "b) Query selectivity can determine whether or not queries can use indexes effectively or even use indexes at all",
            "c) More selective queries match a larger percentage of documents",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: More selective queries match a smaller percentage of documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "___________ is used to determine whether a query is a covered query.",
        "Options": [
            "a) explainstats()",
            "b) explain()",
            "c) explainall()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: db.collection.explain() provides information on the execution of other operations, such as db.collection.update()."
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "The ________ message is used to update a document in a collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE",
            "b) OP_UPDATE",
            "c) OP_UPDATES",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Only the OP_QUERY and OP_GET_MORE messages result in a response from the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) An equality match on the unique _id field is less selective as it can match at most one document",
            "b) The selectivity of regular expressions depends on the expressions themselves",
            "c) Less selective queries can use indexes effectively or even at all",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If an index exists for the field, then MongoDB matches the regular expression against the values in the index, which can be faster than a collection scan."
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "_____  can modify specific fields of an existing document or documents or replace an existing document entirely, depending on the update parameter.",
        "Options": [
            "a) modify()",
            "b) update()",
            "c) find()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By default, the update() method updates a single document."
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "The update() method uses the _______ command, which uses the default write concern.",
        "Options": [
            "a) find",
            "b) read",
            "c) update",
            "d) modify"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The update() method returns an object that contains the status of the operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "_________ is used to view statistics about the query plan for a given query.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.explain()",
            "b) cursor.explain()",
            "c) cursor.explainstats()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This information can help as you develop indexing strategies."
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "A ________ query plan has returned a threshold number of matching results.",
        "Options": [
            "a) execution",
            "b) unordered",
            "c) ordered",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: An ordered query plan has returned all the matching results."
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "A query _______ consists of a combination of query, sort, and projection specifications.",
        "Options": [
            "a) plan",
            "b) shape",
            "c) stats",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Index filters determine which indexes the optimizer evaluates for a query shape."
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "________ store the relationships between data by including links or references from one document to another.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Capped",
            "b) Embedded",
            "c) External",
            "d) References"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Applications can resolve these references to access the related data. Broadly, these are normalized data models."
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In practice, the documents in a collection share a different structure",
            "b) Data in MongoDB has a flexible schema",
            "c) The key challenge in data modeling is balancing the needs of the application, the performance characteristics of the database engine, and the data retrieval patterns",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB’s collections do not enforce document structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "In MongoDB, write operations are atomic at the __________ level.",
        "Options": [
            "a) collection",
            "b) document",
            "c) row",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: No single write operation can atomically affect more than one document or more than one collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "______________ documents capture relationships between data by storing related data in a single document structure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Capped",
            "b) Embedded",
            "c) External",
            "d) Internal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB documents make it possible to embed document structures in a field or array within a document. "
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The key decision in designing data models for MongoDB applications revolves around the structure of documents and how the application represents relationships between data",
            "b) There are two tools that allow applications to represent these relationships: references and embedded documents",
            "c) When designing data models, always consider the application usage of the data (i.e. queries, updates, and processing of the data) as well as the inherent structure of the data itself",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Denormalized data models allow applications to retrieve and manipulate related data in a single database operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "A ____________ data model with embedded data combines all related data for a represented entity in a single document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) normalized",
            "b) denormalized",
            "c) non relational",
            "d) relational"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This facilitates atomic write operations since a single write operation can insert or update the data for an entity. "
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "For the __________ storage engine, if the document size exceeds the allocated space for that document, MongoDB relocates the document on disk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MAPv1",
            "b) MAPv2",
            "c) MAPv3",
            "d) MAPv4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Normalizing the data would split the data across multiple collections and would require multiple write operations that are not atomic collectively."
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "With MongoDB 3.0.0, the default use of the Power of _________ Allocations minimizes the occurrences of re-allocations as well as allows for the effective reuse of the freed record space.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 Sized",
            "b) 3 Sized",
            "c) 4 Sized",
            "d) 5 Sized"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When using MMAPv1, if your applications require updates that will frequently cause document growth to exceeds the current power of 2 allocation, you may want to refactor your data model to use references between data in distinct documents rather than a denormalized data model."
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "___________ strategy is used to explicitly avoid document growth.",
        "Options": [
            "a) deallocation",
            "b) allocation",
            "c) pre-allocation",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A data model that embeds related data in a single document facilitates atomic operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "Each index in MongoDB requires at least _________ of data space.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8KB",
            "b) 28KB",
            "c) 68KB",
            "d) 108KB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Adding an index has some negative performance impact for write operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "___________ data models allow applications to store related pieces of information in the same database record.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reference",
            "b) Embedded",
            "c) External",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As a result, applications may need to issue fewer queries and updates to complete common operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) With MongoDB, you cannot embed related data in a single structure or document",
            "b) The key consideration for the structure of your documents is the decision to embed or to use references",
            "c) Reference schema is generally known as “denormalized” models",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Effective data models support your application needs."
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "Embedded data model is used when you have _________ relationships between entities.",
        "Options": [
            "a) contains",
            "b) isa",
            "c) inheritance",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Embedding provides better performance for read operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "Normalized data models describe relationships using ___________ between documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) relativeness",
            "b) references",
            "c) evaluation",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Normalized data models can require more round trips to the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Embedded data models make it possible to update related data in a single atomic write operation",
            "b) Embedding related data in documents may lead to situations where documents grow after creation",
            "c) With the MMAPv1 storage engine, document growth can impact write performance and lead to data fragmentation",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In version 3.0.0, MongoDB uses Power of 2 Sized Allocations as the default allocation strategy for MMAPv1 in order to account for document growth, minimizing the likelihood of data fragmentation."
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "To interact with embedded documents, use ___________ notation to “reach into” embedded documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) period",
            "b) dot",
            "c) comma",
            "d) colon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: References provides more flexibility than embedding."
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "MongoDB using the mmapv1 storage engine has limits on the number of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) namespaces",
            "b) collections",
            "c) documents",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  The namespace file defaults to 16 MB."
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "To get the current number of namespaces in the mongo shell, use ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.system.namespaces.countc()",
            "b) db.system.namespaces.count(*)",
            "c) db.system.namespaces.count()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The limit on the number of namespaces depend on the <database>.ns size."
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "The __________ feature of collections expires documents after a period of time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) TEL",
            "b) TTL",
            "c) TPL",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Consider using the TTL feature if your application requires some data to persist in the database for a limited period of time."
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "Capped collections provide __________ management of inserted documents in MongoDB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) FIFO",
            "b) LIFO",
            "c) LRU",
            "d) MRU"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Capped collections efficiently support operations that insert and read documents based on insertion order."
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "_______________ is a specification for storing and retrieving files that exceed the BSON-document size limit of 16MB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DataFS",
            "b) GridFS",
            "c) ReadFS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Instead of storing a file in a single document, GridFS divides a file into parts, or chunks."
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) By default GridFS limits chunk size to 255k",
            "b) GridFS is useful only for storing files that exceed 16MB",
            "c) When you query a GridFS store for a file, the driver or client will reassemble the chunks as needed",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: GridFS is useful not only for storing files that exceed 16MB but also for storing any files for which you want to access without having to load the entire file into memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "How many does collections GridFS use to store files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: One collection stores the file chunks, and the other stores file metadata."
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "The default chunk size is changed from 256k to 255k in which version?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.0",
            "b) 2.4.9",
            "c) 2.4.10",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The use of the term chunks in the context of GridFS is not related to the use of the term chunks in the context of sharding."
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Client libraries provide a convenient, injection free, process to build these objects",
            "b) MongoDB represents queries as BSON objects",
            "c) Field names in MongoDB’s query language have semantic meaning",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If you need to use db.eval() with user supplied values, you can either use a CodeWScope or you can supply extra arguments to your function."
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "Which of the collection in GridFS stores the binary chunks?",
        "Options": [
            "a) chunks",
            "b) files",
            "c) data",
            "d) log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: GridFS places the collections in a common bucket by prefixing each with the bucket name."
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "___________  is the _id is of the data type chosen for the original document in files collections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) files._id",
            "b) file._id",
            "c) fileobj._id",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The default type for MongoDB documents is BSON ObjectId."
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "Which of the following checks and repairs errors and inconsistencies in data storage?",
        "Options": [
            "a) repairDatabase",
            "b) repairedDatabase",
            "c) recoverDatabase",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: repairDatabase is analogous to an fsck command for file systems. "
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "The files_id field contains the _id of the chunk’s __________ document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) parent",
            "b) child",
            "c) top",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: GridFS uses a unique, compound index on the chunks collection for the files_id and n fields."
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "Which of the following field allows efficient retrieval of chunks?",
        "Options": [
            "a) n",
            "b) name",
            "c) object",
            "d) 2n"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The GridFS index allows efficient retrieval of chunks using the files_id and n values."
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "Which of the following relationship uses references to describe documents between connected data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) One-to-One Relationships with Embedded Documents",
            "b) One-to-Many Relationships with Embedded Documents",
            "c) One-to-Many Relationships with Document References",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: One-to-Many Relationships with document references presents a data model that uses references to describe one-to-many relationships between documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) One-to-One Relationships with embedded documents presents a data model that uses embedded documents to describe one-to-one relationships between connected data",
            "b) One-to-One Relationships with document references presents a data model that uses embedded documents to describe one-to-one relationships between connected data",
            "c) One-to-Many Relationships with embedded documents presents a data model that uses embedded documents to describe one-to-one relationships between connected data",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One-to-Many Relationships with embedded documents presents a data model that uses embedded documents to describe one-to-many relationships between connected data."
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to avoid the repetition of data in MongoDB schema?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DeReferences",
            "b) References",
            "c) Cursor",
            "d) Collectors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: With the embedded data model, your application can retrieve the complete patron information with one query."
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Decisions that affect how you model data can affect application performance and database capacity",
            "b) Collections do enforce document structure",
            "c) Data in MongoDB has a flexible schema",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When using references, the growth of the relationships determine where to store the reference."
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "__________ define what records to select for read, update, and delete operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Query optimizer",
            "b) Query selector",
            "c) Update definitions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Collections do not enforce document structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "The ___________ JavaScript shell and the MongoDB language drivers translate between BSON and the language-specific document representation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongo",
            "c) json",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In this one-to-many relationship between patron and address data, the patron has multiple address entities."
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect about documents in MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The field names cannot start with the dollar sign ($) character",
            "b) The field names cannot contain the dot (.) character",
            "c) The field names cannot contain the null character",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To avoid mutable, growing arrays, store the publisher reference inside the book document."
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "The ________ References pattern stores each tree node in a document; in addition to the tree node, the document stores the id of the node’s parent.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Child",
            "b) Parent",
            "c) Root",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Data model that describes a tree-like structure in MongoDB documents by storing references to “parent” nodes in children nodes."
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The query to retrieve the parent of a node is fast and straightforward",
            "b) The query to retrieve the parent of a node is slow and straightforward",
            "c) The query to retrieve the parent of a node is slow and complex",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can create an index on the field to enable fast search by the parent node."
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "The ________ Links pattern provides a simple solution to tree storage but requires multiple queries to retrieve subtrees.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Child",
            "b) Parent",
            "c) Root",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can query by the parent field to find its immediate children nodes."
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "The _________ References pattern stores each tree node in array the id(s) of the node’s children.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Child",
            "b) Parent",
            "c) Root",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In addition to the tree node, document stores in an array the id(s) of the node’s children."
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You cannot query for a node in the children field to find its parent node only",
            "b) You can query for a node in the children field to find its parent node as well as its siblings",
            "c) You can query for a node in the children field to find its siblings only",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Child References pattern provides a suitable solution to tree storage as long as no operations on subtrees are necessary."
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "Which of the following pattern may provide a suitable solution for storing graphs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Child",
            "b) Parent",
            "c) Root",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Node may have multiple parents for Child Parents."
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "Which of the following pattern is more straightforward to use?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Materialized Paths",
            "b) Array of Ancestors",
            "c) Nested Sets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Array of Ancestors pattern stores each tree node in a document; in addition to the tree node, document stores in an array the id(s) of the node’s ancestors or path."
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "The Array of Ancestors pattern is slightly slower than the ________________ pattern.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Materialized Paths",
            "b) Array of Ancestors",
            "c) Nested Sets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Array of Ancestors pattern provides a fast and efficient solution to find the descendants and the ancestors of a node by creating an index on the elements of the ancestors field."
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "The ____________ pattern identifies each node in the tree as stops in a round-trip traversal of the tree.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Materialized Paths",
            "b) Array of Ancestors",
            "c) Nested Sets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Nested Sets pattern stores each tree node in a document; in addition to the tree node, document stores the id of node’s parent, the node’s initial stop in the left field, and its return stop in the right field."
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "____________ pattern requires additional steps of working with strings and regular expressions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Materialized Paths",
            "b) Array of Ancestors",
            "c) Nested Sets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Materialized Paths pattern stores each tree node in a document; in addition to the tree node, document stores as a string the id(s) of the node’s ancestors or path."
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "Which of the following pattern is best for static trees that do not change?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Child",
            "b) Parent",
            "c) Root",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Nested Sets pattern provides a fast and efficient solution for finding subtrees but is inefficient for modifying the tree structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $regex is used for regular expression pattern matches",
            "b) $like is used for regular expression pattern matches",
            "c) $reg is used for regular expression pattern matches",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If your application needs to perform queries on the content of a field that holds text you can perform exact matches on the text."
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "Which of the following operations are atomic on document level?",
        "Options": [
            "a) update",
            "b) remove",
            "c) findAndModify",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MongoDB, write operations, e.g. db.collection.update(), db.collection.findAndModify(), db.collection.remove(), are atomic on the level of a single document."
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "___________ bulk indexes may be more efficient for some kinds of content and workloads in real time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Synchronous",
            "b) Asynchronous",
            "c) Unique",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  MongoDB can support keyword searches using specific data models and multi-key indexes;"
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) An array with a large number of elements will incur greater indexing costs on insertion",
            "b) An array with a large number of elements will incur smaller indexing costs on updates",
            "c) An array with a small number of elements will incur greater indexing costs on insertion",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An array with a large number of elements, such as one with several hundred or thousands of keywords will incur greater indexing costs on insertion."
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "________ indexes can include any field whose value is a string or an array of string elements.",
        "Options": [
            "a) text",
            "b) string",
            "c) char",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  MongoDB provides text indexes to support text search of string content in documents of a collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "Which of the following is related to document that do not provide a way to weight results?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stemming",
            "b) Synonyms",
            "c) Ranking",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The keyword look ups described in this document do not provide a way to weight results."
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "Which of the following is related to document that provide support for synonym or related queries in the application layer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stemming",
            "b) Synonyms",
            "c) Ranking",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  MongoDB can support keyword searches using specific data models and multi-key indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "Which of the following is related to the parsing of document for root?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stemming",
            "b) Synonyms",
            "c) Ranking",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Keyword queries in MongoDB can not parse keywords for root or related words."
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "To add structures to your document to support keyword-based queries add the keywords as ______ in the array.",
        "Options": [
            "a) number",
            "b) strings",
            "c) character",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can then create a multi-key index on the array and create queries that select values from the array."
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "__________ precision multiplies the monetary value by a power of 10.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exact",
            "b) Accurate",
            "c) Ambiguity",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  MongoDB stores numeric data as either IEEE 754 standard 64-bit floating point numbers or as 32-bit or 64-bit signed integers."
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Applications that handle monetary data often require capturing fractional units of currency",
            "b) Applications that handle time data often require capturing fractional units of currency",
            "c)  Applications that handle temporal and spatial data often require capturing fractional units of currency",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Some fractional numeric quantities, such as one third and one tenth, have no exact representation in binary floating point numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "Which of the following precision uses two values for the field?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exact",
            "b) Accurate",
            "c) Ambiguity",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Arbitrary Precision which uses two fields for the value: one field to store the exact monetary value as a non-numeric and another field to store a floating point approximation of the value."
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "MongoDB stores times in _____ by default, and will convert any local time representations into this form.",
        "Options": [
            "a) UTC",
            "b) GMT",
            "c) IST",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Applications that must operate or report on some unmodified local time value may store the time zone alongside the UTC timestamp, and compute the original local time in their application logic."
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If you need to query the database for exact, mathematically valid matches, use Exact Precision",
            "b) If you regularly need to perform server-side arithmetic on monetary data, the exact precision model may be appropriate",
            "c) If you need to query the database for exact, mathematically valid matches, use Ambiguity Precision",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If you need to be able to do server-side arithmetic, e.g., $inc, $mul, and aggregation framework arithmetic, use Exact Precision."
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to handle arbitrary or unforeseen number of precision?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exact",
            "b) Accurate",
            "c) Ambiguity",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If there is no need to perform server-side arithmetic on monetary data, modeling monetary data using the arbitrary precision model may be suitable."
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "Use of the approximation field for the query and sort operations requires that applications perform _______ side post-processing.",
        "Options": [
            "a) client",
            "b) server",
            "c) application",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Client side processing is used to decode the non-numeric representation of the exact value and then filter out the returned documents based on the exact monetary value."
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "The ______ factor is a constant and known property of the currency.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rank",
            "b) scale",
            "c) high",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Applications can determine the scale factor from the currency."
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "In one field, exact monetary value is encoded as a _________ data type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) numeric",
            "b) character",
            "c) non numeric",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  In one field, exact monetary value is encoded as a non-numeric data type; e.g., BinData or a string."
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "___________ is a specification for storing and retrieving files that exceed the BSON-document size limit of 16MB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) FSpec",
            "b) GridFS",
            "c) Grid",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Instead of storing a file in a single document, GridFS divides a file into parts, or chunks."
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) GridFS uses two collections to store files",
            "b) You cannot perform range queries on files stored through GridFS",
            "c) Applications that handle temporal and spatial data often require capturing fractional units of currency",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One collection stores the file chunks, and the other stores file metadata."
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "By default GridFS limits chunk size to ______ k.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 225",
            "b) 255",
            "c) 256",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  GridFS is useful not only for storing files that exceed 16MB but also for storing any files for which you want access without having to load the entire file into memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "When you query a GridFS store for a file, the _______ will reassemble the chunks as needed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) client",
            "b) Server",
            "c) Agent",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You also can access information from arbitrary sections of files, which allows you to “skip” into the middle of a video or audio file."
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Chunks in the context of GridFS is related to the use of the term chunks in the context of sharding",
            "b) The default chunk size changed from 256k to 255k",
            "c) If you need to query the database for exact, mathematically valid matches, use Ambiguity Precision",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: By default, GridFS uses two collections with names prefixed by fs bucket."
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": "MongoDB represents queries as ___________ objects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BSON",
            "b) JSON",
            "c) GSON",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: As a client program assembles a query in MongoDB, it builds a BSON object, not a string."
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "Each document in the __________ collection represents a distinct chunk of a file as represented in the GridFS store.",
        "Options": [
            "a) chunks",
            "b) files",
            "c) bson",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Each chunk is identified by its unique ObjectId stored in its _id field."
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "GridFS uses a _________ index on the chunks collection for the files_id and n fields.",
        "Options": [
            "a) unique",
            "b) single",
            "c) non unique",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The files_id field contains the _id of the chunk’s “parent” document. "
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": "The ___ field contains the sequence number of the chunk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) x",
            "b) array",
            "c) field",
            "d) n"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  GridFS numbers all chunks, starting with 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "The GridFS index allows efficient retrieval of __________ using the files_id and n values.",
        "Options": [
            "a) chunks",
            "b) files",
            "c) bson",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  When you query for a large file, GridFS automatically reassembles the smaller files into the original large file."
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "_________ is a binary serialization format used to store documents and make remote procedure calls in MongoDB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BSON",
            "b) GridFS",
            "c) JSON",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: BSON supports many data types as values in documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ObjectIds are small, likely unique, fast to generate, and ordered",
            "b) ObjectIds are large, likely unique, and ordered",
            "c) ObjectIds values consists of 18-byte",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MongoDB, documents stored in a collection require a unique _id field that acts as a primary key."
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "Which of the following data type is depreciated?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Double",
            "b) String",
            "c) Object",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  MongoDB treats some types as an equivalent for comparison purposes. "
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Each data type has a corresponding number that can be used with the _______ operator to query documents by BSON type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $type",
            "b) $server",
            "c) $agent",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: $type selects the documents where the value of the field is an instance of the specified numeric BSON type."
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BSON Date is a 32-bit integer that represents the number of milliseconds",
            "b) The BSON timestamp type is for internal MongoDB use",
            "c) If you need to query the database for exact, mathematically valid matches, use Ambiguity Precision",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This results in a representable date range of about 290 million years into the past and future."
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "There is _________ byte counter in BSON, starting with a random value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  ObjectId is a 12-byte BSON type"
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "In the mongo shell, you can access the creation time of the ObjectId, using the ______ method.",
        "Options": [
            "a) getTime()",
            "b) getTimestamp()",
            "c) Timestamp()",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  MongoDB clients should add an _id field with a unique ObjectId."
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "Object_Id is similar to _________ key in Relational Databases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) composite",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Object_Id is unique and cannot be changed."
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "Which of the field is reserved for use as a primary key?",
        "Options": [
            "a) _id",
            "b) _uid",
            "c) _uuid",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ID value value must be unique in the collection, is immutable, and may be of any type other than an array."
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The field names cannot start with the dollar sign ($) character",
            "b) The field names cannot contain the dot (.) character",
            "c) The field names cannot contain the null character",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Documents have certain restrictions on field names."
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "To ensure functioning replication, do not store values that are of the _______ regular expression type in the _id field.",
        "Options": [
            "a) JSON",
            "b) XML",
            "c) JScript",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The _id field may contain values of any BSON data type, other than an array."
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "The ______ field is always the first field in the document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) _id",
            "b) id",
            "c) Ob_id",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Updates that include renaming of field names may result in the reordering of fields in the document."
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "__________ returns the JavaScript representation in the form of a string literal.",
        "Options": [
            "a) toStringJava()",
            "b) toString()",
            "c) String()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In previous versions, toString() returns the hexadecimal string representation, which as of version 2.2 can be retrieved by the str property."
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "Which of the following query is used to generate a new ObjectId, use the ObjectId() constructor with no argument?",
        "Options": [
            "a) x = ObjectIdAdd()",
            "b) x = addObjectId()",
            "c) x = ObjectId()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  ObjectId() constructor is used with no argument for new object."
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "The __________ JavaScript shell and the MongoDB language drivers translate between BSON and the language-specific document representation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongo",
            "c) iscript",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The value of a field can be any of the BSON data types."
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB stores chunks on disk in the XML serialization format",
            "b) MongoDB stores documents on disk in the BSON serialization format",
            "c) MongoDB stores documents on RAM in the JSON serialization format",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  BSON documents may have more than one field with the same name."
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "BSON is a binary representation of ________ documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) JSON",
            "b) XML",
            "c) JScript",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  BSON contains more data types than JSON."
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "MongoDB documents are composed of field-and-value pairs and have the following structure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) field1:; value1",
            "b) field1: value1;",
            "c) field1: value1",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The value of a field can be any of the BSON data types, including other documents, arrays, and arrays of documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Some documents created by internal MongoDB processes may have duplicate fields",
            "b) no MongoDB process will ever add duplicate fields to an existing user document",
            "c) The maximum BSON document size is 16 megabytes",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The maximum document size helps ensure that a single document cannot use excessive amount of RAM or, during transmission, excessive amount of bandwidth."
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Question": "To store documents larger than the maximum size, MongoDB provides the _______ API.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Grid",
            "b) MMS",
            "c) GridFS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  MongoDB preserves the order of the document fields following write operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "Index keys that are of the _______ type are more efficiently stored in the index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Materialized Paths",
            "b) BinData",
            "c) String",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Most MongoDB driver clients will include the _id field and generate an ObjectId before sending the insert operation to MongoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "MongoDB uses the ________ notation to access the elements of an array and to access the fields of an embedded document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dot",
            "b) Array",
            "c) Nested Sets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To access an element of an array by the zero-based index position, concatenate the array name with the dot (.) and zero-based index position, and enclose in quotes."
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "Which of the following data structures are documents in MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) All database records",
            "b) Query selectors",
            "c) Update definitions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Most user-accessible data structures in MongoDB are documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Update definitions define what fields to modify during an update",
            "b) Query specifications, which define what fields to index",
            "c) Index selectors, which define what records to select for read, update, and delete operations",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB stores all data in documents, which are JSON-style data structures composed of field-and-value pairs."
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "An application communicates with MongoDB by way of a client library, called _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Driver",
            "b) Parent",
            "c) Rank",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Driver handles all interaction with the database in a language appropriate to the application."
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "User-defined indexes on multiple fields is called ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) composite index",
            "b) secondary index",
            "c) compound index",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The order of fields listed in a compound index has significance. "
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "If your driver has a version number of 2.9.1, What is the major version?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 9",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Driver version numbers use semantic versioning or “major.minor.patch” versioning system. "
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "Updates that include _________ of field names may result in the reordering of fields in the document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Renaming",
            "b) Joining",
            "c) Nesting",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The $rename operator updates the name of a field."
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Question": "The $rename operator logically performs a _______ of both the old name and the new name.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $unset",
            "b) $set",
            "c) $Nested",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the field to rename does not exist in a document, $rename does nothing."
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "To get a correct snapshot of a running mongod process, you must have _________ enabled.",
        "Options": [
            "a) journaling",
            "b) replication",
            "c) MMS",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Without journaling enabled, there is no guarantee that the snapshot will be consistent or valid."
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Journal must reside on the same logical volume as the other MongoDB data files",
            "b) To get a consistent snapshot of a sharded system, you must disable the balancer",
            "c) Backups produced by copying the underlying data do not support point in time recovery",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: They are difficult to manage for larger sharded clusters."
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "The _______ tool reads data from a MongoDB database and creates high fidelity BSON files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mdump",
            "b) mongodump",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongodump is a utility for creating a binary export of the contents of a database."
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "If your storage system does not support snapshots, you can copy the files directly using ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) cp",
            "b) copy",
            "c) snap",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since copying multiple files is not an atomic operation, you must stop all writes to the mongod before copying the files."
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB Cloud Manager Backup offers point in time recovery of MongoDB replica sets",
            "b) MongoDB Cloud Manager continually backs up MongoDB replica sets",
            "c) MMS achieves point in time recovery by storing oplog data",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB Cloud Manager Backup also offers a consistent snapshot of sharded clusters."
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "The _________ tool can populate a MongoDB database with the data from these BSON files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostore",
            "b) mongorestore",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This tool is not ideal for capturing backups of larger systems."
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "mongodump and mongorestore can operate against a running _______ process.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostore",
            "b) mongorestore",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: By default, mongodump does not capture the contents of the local database."
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "For replica sets, mongodump also supports a point in time feature with the ________ option.",
        "Options": [
            "a) –oplog",
            "b) –log",
            "c) –op",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  To restore a point in time backup created with –oplog, use mongorestore with the –oplogReplay option."
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "If applications modify data while mongodump is creating a backup _________ will compete for resources with those applications.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostore",
            "b) mongorestore",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) mongodump"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Applications may continue modifying data while mongodump captures the output."
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "The MongoDB ______ supports the backing up and restoring of MongoDB deployments.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cloud Manager",
            "b) MMS",
            "c) MonitorMMS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB Cloud Manager continually backs up MongoDB replica sets and sharded clusters by reading the oplog data from your MongoDB deployment."
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "On Linux the ______ manager can create a snapshot.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LVM",
            "b) SVM",
            "c) MMS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can create a backup by copying MongoDB’s underlying data files."
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The mechanics of snapshots depend on the underlying storage system",
            "b) To get a consistent snapshot of a sharded system, you must disable the balancer",
            "c) If your storage system does not support snapshots, you can copy the files directly using cp, rsync, or a similar tool",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Backups produced by copying the underlying data do not support point in time recovery for replica sets and are difficult to manage for larger sharded clusters."
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "When connected to a MongoDB instance, mongodump can adversely affect ______ performance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mdump",
            "b) mongodump",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If your data is larger than system memory, the queries will push the working set out of memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "To mitigate the impact of mongodump on the performance of the replica set, use mongodump to capture backups from a _________ member of a replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) snaphot",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Alternatively, you can shut down a secondary and use mongodump with the data files directly. "
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If you shut down a secondary to capture data with mongodump ensure that the operation can complete before its oplog becomes too stale to continue replicating",
            "b) MongoDB Cloud Manager continually backs up MongoDB replica sets",
            "c) Sharded cluster snapshots are easy to achieve with other MongoDB backup methods",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Sharded cluster snapshots are difficult to achieve with other MongoDB backup methods."
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "________ an on-premise solution, has similar functionality to the cloud version.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Opscore Manager",
            "b) Ops Manager",
            "c) Mongod",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This tool is available with Enterprise Advanced subscriptions."
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "Ops Manager provides Ops Manager ________ and Ops Manager Backup, which helps users optimize clusters and mitigate operational risk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance",
            "b) Administration",
            "c) Monitoring",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Ops Manager is a package for managing MongoDB deployments."
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "Ops Manager _________ provides an interface for configuring MongoDB nodes and clusters and for upgrading your MongoDB deployment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Automation",
            "b) Performance",
            "c) Monitoring",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ops Manager Monitoring provides real-time reporting, visualization, and alerting on key database and hardware indicators."
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "Ops Manager ______ provides scheduled snapshots and point-in-time recovery of your MongoDB replica sets and sharded clusters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Automation",
            "b) Performance",
            "c) Monitoring",
            "d) Backup"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Backup can also create snapshots of standalones that are run as single-member replica sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "Sharded clusters snapshots temporarily stop the balancer via ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mongod",
            "b) MMS",
            "c) MonitorMMS",
            "d) mongos"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Backup takes and stores snapshots based on a user-defined snapshot retention policy."
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "Ops Manager reads directly from the Backup Blockstore database and transfers files either through ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) TCP",
            "b) HTTPS",
            "c) MMS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Ops Manager Backup lets you restore data from a scheduled snapshot or from a selected point between snapshots."
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The amount of oplog to keep per backup is configurable and affects the time window available for checkpoint and point-in-time restores",
            "b) To get a consistent snapshot of a sharded system, you must enable the balancer",
            "c) Backups produced by copying the underlying data do support point in time recovery",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you restore from a checkpoint or point in time, Ops Manager first creates a local restore of a snapshot from the blockstore and then applies stored oplogs until the specified point is reached."
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Question": "Ops Manager maintains one _____ database for each backed-up replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mdump",
            "b) head",
            "c) tail",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The head database is consistent with the original primary up to the last oplog supplied by the agent."
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "The agent ships initial sync and oplog data over HTTPS back to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Opscore Manager",
            "b) Ops Manager",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Backup performs the initial sync and the tailing of the oplog using standard MongoDB queries."
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": "Backup can also create snapshots of _________ that are run as single-member replica sets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) documents",
            "b) standalones",
            "c) backups",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A lightweight Backup Agent runs within your infrastructure and backs up data from the MongoDB processes you have specified."
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "Ops Manager _________ provides an interface for configuring MongoDB nodes and clusters and for upgrading your MongoDB deployment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Automation",
            "b) Performance",
            "c) Monitoring",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ops Manager Monitoring provides real-time reporting, visualization, and alerting on key database and hardware indicators."
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "Which of the following command returns quickly and does not impact MongoDB performance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbStats",
            "b) db.serverStatus()",
            "c) db.stats()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: serverStatus outputs an account of the state of a MongoDB instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "Which of the following document details the state and configuration of the replica set and statistics about its members?",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetGetStatus",
            "b) db.serverStatus()",
            "c) db.stats()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The replSetGetStatus command (rs.status() from the shell) returns an overview of your replica set’s status."
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "___________ captures and returns the counts of database operations by type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostat",
            "b) mongod",
            "c) mms",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use mongostat to understand the distribution of operation types and to inform capacity planning."
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database commands cannot return statistics regarding the current database state with greater fidelity",
            "b) Monitoring is a critical component of all database administration",
            "c) The MongoDB distribution does not include utilities that quickly return statistics about instances’ performance and activity",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This is useful for diagnosing issues and assessing normal operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "_________ tracks and reports the current read and write activity of a MongoDB instance, and reports these statistics on a per collection basis.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostat",
            "b) mongod",
            "c) mongotop",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Use mongotop to check if your database activity and use match your expectations."
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "_______ method is useful tool for identifying the database instance’s in-progress operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.current",
            "b) db.currentOp",
            "c) db.Op",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB includes a number of commands that report on the state of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MMS offers point in time recovery of MongoDB replica sets",
            "b) MongoDB provides a web interface that exposes diagnostic and monitoring information in a simple web page",
            "c) db.Status() outputs an account of the state of a MongoDB instance",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The web interface is accessible at localhost:<port>, where the <port> number is 1000 more than the mongod port."
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "___________ returns a general overview of the status of the database, detailing disk usage, memory use, connection, journaling, and index access.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbStats",
            "b) db.serverStatus()",
            "c) db.stats()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This command is rarely run directly."
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "The ________ reflect the amount of storage used, the quantity of data contained in the database, and object, collection, and index counters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbStats",
            "b) db.serverStatus()",
            "c) db.statserver()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The dbStats command, or db.stats() from the shell, returns a document that addresses storage use and data volumes."
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "________ provides statistics that resemble dbStats on the collection level.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbStats",
            "b) db.serverStatus()",
            "c) db.statserver()",
            "d) collstats"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It also includes count of the objects in the collection, the size of the collection, the amount of disk space used by the collection, and information about its indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "Replica set configuration requires that the _______ have a value that is consistent among all members of the set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetName",
            "b) instance",
            "c) MMS",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use descriptive names for sets. Once configured, use the mongo shell to add hosts to the replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Replica set configuration is straightforward",
            "b) Keyfile must be less than one kilobyte in size",
            "c) Keyfile may only contain characters in the base64 set and the file must not have group or “world” permissions on UNIX systems",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To enable authentication for the replica set, add the keyFile option."
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "Setting _______ enables authentication and specifies a key file for the replica set member use to when authenticating to each other.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostat",
            "b) mongod",
            "c) keyFile",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The content of the key file is arbitrary, but must be the same on all members of the replica set and mongos instances that connect to the set."
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Question": "_______ is /srv/mongodb, which specifies where MongoDB will store its data files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbPath",
            "b) dbPathSts",
            "c) db.Op",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The user account that mongod runs under will need read and write access to this directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Config servers are not replica sets",
            "b) Sharding requires a number of mongod instances with different configurations",
            "c) The config servers store the cluster’s metadata, while the cluster distributes data among one or more shard servers",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The command line and configuration file interfaces provide MongoDB administrators with a large number of options and settings for controlling the operation of the database system."
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "_____  bit builds of mongod enable journaling by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 32",
            "d) 64"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Journaling ensures single instance write-durability. "
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "Which of the following provide acceptable performance levels for multiple mongod instances?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GridFS",
            "b) SST",
            "c) MMS",
            "d) SSD"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Additionally, you may find that multiple databases with small working sets may function acceptably on a single system."
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "What is the size of Chunk by default?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 64 MB",
            "b) 64 GB",
            "c) 64 KB",
            "d) 32 MB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Default chunk size provides the ideal balance between the most even distribution of data, for which smaller chunk sizes are best, and minimizing chunk migration, for which larger chunk sizes are optimal."
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "Which of the following sets the database profiler level?",
        "Options": [
            "a) systemLog.verbosity",
            "b) operationProfiling.mode",
            "c) operationProfiling.slowOpThresholdMs",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The profiler is not active by default because of the possible impact on the profiler itself on performance. "
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "Which of the following document configures the threshold which determines whether a query is “slow” for the purpose of the logging system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) systemLog.verbosity",
            "b) operationProfiling.mode",
            "c) operationProfiling.slowOpThresholdMs",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: systemLog.verbosity controls the amount of logging output that mongod write to the log."
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "________ contains a counter of the total number of clients with active operations in progress or queued.",
        "Options": [
            "a) globalLock.active",
            "b) localLock.activeClients",
            "c) globalLock.activeClients",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The activeClients data structure provides more granular information about the number of connected clients and the operation types (e.g. read or write) performed by these clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In MongoDB 3.0, cursor.explain() returns the indexOnly field to indicate whether the index covered a query",
            "b) When an index covers a query, MongoDB can both match the query conditions and return the results using only the index keys",
            "c) For read-heavy applications, deploy sharding and add one or more shards to a sharded cluster to distribute load among mongod instances",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB does not need to examine documents from the collection to return the results."
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "The ___________ collection stores custom roles that administrators create and assign to users to provide access to specific resources.",
        "Options": [
            "a) admin.system.role",
            "b) admin.system.roles",
            "c) admin.system.roleasign",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: System collections include these collections stored in the admin database"
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "The _________ field provides the amount of resident memory in use.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mem.resident",
            "b) memory.resident",
            "c) mem.resident",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If this exceeds the amount of system memory and there is a significant amount of data on disk that isn’t in RAM, you may have exceeded the capacity of your system."
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB distributions are currently available for Mac OS X, Linux, Windows Server 2012, Windows Server 2008 R2 64bit, Windows 7 (64 bit), Windows Vista, and Solaris",
            "b) The MongoDB distribution for Solaris include support for the WiredTiger storage engine",
            "c) mongod will not start if dbPath contains data files created by a storage engine",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  The MongoDB distribution for Solaris does not include support for the WiredTiger storage engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "When the TTL thread is active, you will see _______ operations in the output of db.currentOp().",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) update",
            "c) delete",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When you build a TTL index in the background, the TTL thread can begin deleting documents while the index is building."
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "MongoDB stores tag sets in the replica set configuration object, which is the document returned by _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.config()",
            "b) rs.conf()",
            "c) rs.confstats()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Custom read preferences and write concerns evaluate tags sets in different ways."
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "Which of the following represents Shared lock?",
        "Options": [
            "a) R",
            "b) w",
            "c) r",
            "d) W"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: W represents Exclusive (X) lock."
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "On Linux, use the ______ command to check if disk I/O is a bottleneck for your database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) stat",
            "b) iostats",
            "c) iostat",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Specify the number of seconds when running iostat to avoid displaying stats covering the time since server boot."
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "Which of the following document configures the threshold which determines whether a query is “slow” for the purpose of the logging system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) systemLog.verbosity",
            "b) operationProfiling.mode",
            "c) operationProfiling.slowOpThresholdMs",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: systemLog.verbosity controls the amount of logging output that mongod write to the log."
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "Which of the following storage engine is supported by default?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MMAPv1",
            "b) WiredTiger",
            "c) WirelessTiger",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  MongoDB includes support for two storage engines: MMAPv1, the storage engine available in previous versions of MongoDB, and WiredTiger."
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Replica set configuration is complex",
            "b) MongoDB includes support for two storage engines",
            "c) MongoDB includes support for more than three storage engines",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MMAPv1 provides collection-level locking."
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "All collections have a unique ________ lock that allows multiple clients to modify documents in different collections at the same time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) writer",
            "b) readers-writer",
            "c) readers",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Each database has a readers-writer lock that allows concurrent read access to a database, but gives exclusive access to a single write operation per database."
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": "_________ supports concurrent access by readers and writers to the documents in a collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MMAPv1",
            "b) WiredTiger",
            "c) WirelessTiger",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Clients can read documents while write operations are in progress, and multiple threads can modify different documents in a collection at the same time."
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "MongoDB uses ________ logging to an on-disk journal.",
        "Options": [
            "a) write ahead",
            "b) read ahead",
            "c) write once",
            "d) read only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Leave journaling enabled in order to ensure that mongod will be able to recover its data files and keep the data files in a valid state following a crash."
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "_______ concern describes the guarantee that MongoDB provides when reporting on the success of a write operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Write",
            "b) Read",
            "c) Read only",
            "d) SSD"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The strength of the write concerns determine the level of guarantee. "
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "The ________ command returns information regarding the number of open connections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) connPoolStats",
            "b) connStats",
            "c) serverstats",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To avoid overloading the connection resources of a single mongod or mongos instance, ensure that clients maintain reasonable connection pool sizes."
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "________ do not typically provide sufficient performance to support a MongoDB deployment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) RAID-5",
            "b) RAID-10",
            "c) RAID-7",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Most MongoDB deployments should use disks backed by RAID-10."
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "Which of the following should be avoided with MongoDB Deployments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RAID-5",
            "b) RAID-10",
            "c) RAID-7",
            "d) RAID-0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: While RAID-0 provides good write performance, it also provides limited availability and can lead to reduced performance on read operations, particularly when using Amazon’s EBS volumes."
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "With the WiredTiger storage engine, use of _______ is strongly recommended to avoid performance issues.",
        "Options": [
            "a) XFS",
            "b) SSD",
            "c) SST",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Some Linux distributions require different versions of the kernel to support using XFS."
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) With the MMAPv1 storage engine, MongoDB preallocates its database files before using them and often creates large files",
            "b) zlib provides better compression rate but has a higher performance cost",
            "c) MongoDB includes support for many storage engines",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: WiredTiger uses prefix compression on all indexes by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "MongoDB requires a filesystem that supports ______ on directories.",
        "Options": [
            "a) fsynconce()",
            "b) fsync()",
            "c) sync()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: HGFS and Virtual Box’s shared folders do not support this operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "MongoDB Cloud Manager provides integration with Amazon Web Services (AWS) and lets you deploy new ______ instances directly from MongoDB Cloud Manager.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ECS",
            "b) EC2",
            "c) EC3",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB is compatible with EC2."
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When running MongoDB in production on Linux, it is recommended that you use Linux kernel version 2.6.36 or later",
            "b) The MongoDB distribution for Solaris include support for the WiredTiger storage engine",
            "c) By default, WiredTiger uses zip compression library",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: By default, WiredTiger uses snappy compression library."
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "WiredTiger can compress collection data using either snappy or zlib compression library.",
        "Options": [
            "a) snappy",
            "b) zip",
            "c) lib",
            "d) Kit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: snappy provides a lower compression rate but has little performance cost"
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "Which of the following is especially important in Sharded Clusters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NSS",
            "b) STP",
            "c) NTP",
            "d) SSD"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use the Network Time Protocol (NTP) to synchronize time among your hosts."
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Question": "The TCP keepalive on the Azure load balancer is ______ seconds by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100",
            "b) 200",
            "c) 240",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You should set tcp_keepalive_time to 120 to ameliorate this problem."
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "_____ is a command-line tool for monitoring network use.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bwm-ng",
            "b) bwm-g",
            "c) bwm-n",
            "d) bwm-ngs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If you suspect a network-based bottleneck, you may use bwm-ng to begin your diagnostic process."
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "MongoDB supports tagging a range of _______ key values to associate that range with a shard or group of shards.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) shard",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Those shards receive all inserts within the tagged range."
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Shard key range tags are distinct from replica set member tags",
            "b) Balancer does not obey tagged range associations",
            "c) Hash-based sharding only supports tag-aware sharding on an entire collection",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Tag sets let you customize write concern and read preferences for a replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "The _______ migrates chunks of documents in a sharded collection to the shards associated with a tag.",
        "Options": [
            "a) balancer",
            "b) compounder",
            "c) fixer",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: During balancing rounds, if the balancer detects that any chunks violate configured tags, the balancer migrates those chunks to shards associated with those tags."
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "MongoDB stores tag sets in the replica set configuration object, which is the document returned by ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.config()",
            "b) rs.conf()",
            "c) rs.confstats()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Custom read preferences and write concerns evaluate tags sets in different ways."
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Read preferences consider the value of a tag when selecting a member to read from",
            "b) Shard ranges are always exclusive of the lower value and inclusive of the upper boundary",
            "c) Write concerns do not use the value of a tag to select a member except to consider whether or not the value is unique",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Shard ranges are always inclusive of the lower value and exclusive of the upper boundary."
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "By default, an application directs its ______ operations to the primary member in a replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) read and write",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Read preference describes how MongoDB clients route read operations to the members of a replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "Which of the following should not be used to provide extra capacity for reads?",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) primaryPreferred",
            "c) secondary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Use primaryPreferred if you want an application to read from the primary under normal circumstances."
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "Read preference modes are also available to clients connecting to a sharded cluster through ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) MMS",
            "b) mongos",
            "c) mongod",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mongos instance obeys specified read preferences when connecting to the replica set that provides each shard in the cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "All read preference modes except _______ may return stale data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) primaryPreferred",
            "c) secondary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ensure that your application can tolerate stale data if you choose to use a non-primary mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "Which of the following preference does not affect the visibility of data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) read and write",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Regardless of write concern, other clients can see the result of the write operations before the write operation is acknowledged to the issuing client."
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "Which of the following collections work in a way similar to circular buffers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Capped",
            "b) Secondary",
            "c) Sharded",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Once a collection fills its allocated space, it makes room for new documents by overwriting the oldest documents in the collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Capped collections automatically remove the oldest documents in the collection without requiring scripts or explicit remove operations",
            "b) Capped collections do not guarantee that insertion order is identical to the order on disk",
            "c) Capped collections does not allow updates that fit the original document size",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Document does not change its location on disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "_________ stores a log of the operations in a replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) oplog.rs",
            "b) log.rs",
            "c) oplog",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Built-in first-in-first-out property maintains the order of events while managing storage use."
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "___________ is also used to pre-allocate space for an ordinary collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.createCollection.",
            "b) db.create",
            "c) db.createColl",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB creates a collection implicitly when the collection is first referenced in a command."
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Queries need an index to return documents in insertion order",
            "b) The options document creates a capped collection or preallocates space in a new ordinary collection",
            "c) Capped collections have maximum size or document counts that prevent them from growing beyond maximum thresholds",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Capped collections guarantee preservation of the insertion order."
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "If you perform a ________ on a capped collection with no ordering specified, MongoDB guarantees that the ordering of results is the same as the insertion order.",
        "Options": [
            "a) find()",
            "b) write()",
            "c) modify()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To retrieve documents in reverse insertion order, issue find() along with the sort() method with the $natural parameter set to -1."
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "Which of the following should is used to check whether collection is capped or not?",
        "Options": [
            "a) isCAP()",
            "b) isCapped()",
            "c) isColl()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Use the isCapped() method to determine if a collection is capped, as: db.collection.isCapped()."
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "___________ convert a non-capped collection to a capped collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ToCapped",
            "b) convertToCap",
            "c) convertToCapped",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: convertToCapped takes an existing collection (<collection>) and transforms it into a capped collection with a maximum size in bytes, specified by the size argument (<capped size>)."
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "_________ command creates the capped collection and imports the data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CollectionAsCapped",
            "b) cloneCollection",
            "c) cloneCollectionAsCapped",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB does not support the convertToCapped command in a sharded cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "Which of the following command obtains a global write lock and will block other operations until it has completed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ToCapped",
            "b) isCapped",
            "c) convertToCapped",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the capped size specified for the capped collection is smaller than the size of the original uncapped collection, then MongoDB will overwrite documents in the capped collection based on the insertion order, or first in, first out order."
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Question": "Which of the following collection do not support the TTL property?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compound indexes",
            "b) Primary indexes",
            "c) Composite indexes",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The TTL index is a single field index."
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data expiration is useful for some classes of information, including machine generated event data, logs, and session information",
            "b) A special TTL index property supports the implementation of TTL collections",
            "c) TTL collections make it possible to store data in MongoDB and have the mongod automatically remove data after a specified number of seconds or at a specific clock time",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  The TTL feature relies on a background thread in mongod that reads the date-typed values in the index and removes expired documents from the collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "If the indexed field in a document is not a _____ or an array that holds a date value(s), the document will not expire.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DATE",
            "b) TIME",
            "c) DATETIME",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Built-in first-in-first-out property maintains the order of events while managing storage use."
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) TTL indexes expire documents after the specified number of seconds has passed since the indexed field value",
            "b) TTL indexes are special compound indexes",
            "c) If a document does not contain the indexed field, the document will expire",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The expiration threshold is the indexed field value plus the specified number of seconds."
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "Secondary members replicate _________ operations from the primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Update",
            "b) Drop",
            "c) Insert",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: On replica sets, the TTL background thread only deletes documents on the primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Question": "A collection with a TTL index has __________ enabled.",
        "Options": [
            "a) usePowerOf3Sizes",
            "b) usePowerOf2Sizes",
            "c) usePowerOf4Sizes",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  As a result of enabling usePowerOf2Sizes, MongoDB must allocate more disk space relative to data size."
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "Which field does not support TTL indexes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) _identity",
            "b) _option",
            "c) _id",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You cannot create a TTL index on a capped collection because MongoDB cannot remove documents from a capped collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "You cannot use _________ to change the value of expireAfterSeconds of an existing index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) createIndex()",
            "b) dropIndex()",
            "c) removeIndex()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Instead use the collMod database command in conjunction with the index collection flag. Otherwise, to change the value of the option of an existing index, you must drop the index first and recreate."
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "You cannot create a TTL index on a ________ collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sharded",
            "b) Capped",
            "c) Primary",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB cannot remove documents from a capped collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "Which of the following setting defines what constitutes a “slow” operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) slowOpThresholdGs",
            "b) fastOpThresholdMs",
            "c) slowOpThresholdMs",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The operationProfiling.slowOpThresholdMs setting is available only for mongod."
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB uses a locking system to ensure data set consistency",
            "b) If certain operations are long-running or a queue forms, performance will degrade as requests and operations wait for the lock",
            "c) Long queries can result from ineffective use of indexes",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Lock-related slowdowns can be intermittent."
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "________ provide the number of times the lock acquisitions encountered deadlocks.",
        "Options": [
            "a) locks.deadlock",
            "b) lock.deadlockCount",
            "c) locks.deadlockCount",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The globalLock data structure contains information regarding the database’s current lock state, historical lock status, current operation queue, and the number of active clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "If __________ is high relative to uptime, the database has existed in a lock state for a significant amount of time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) globalLock.halfTime",
            "b) globalLock.totalTime",
            "c) globalLock.downTime",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The value of totalTime represents the time, in microseconds, since the database last started and creation of the globalLock."
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The storage.wiredTiger.indexConfig.prefixCompression setting does not affect all indexes created",
            "b) Database profiling can impact database performance",
            "c) The default storage.wiredTiger.engineConfig.cacheSizeGB setting assumes that there is a single mongod instance per node",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If you change the value of storage.wiredTiger.indexConfig.prefixCompression on an existing MongoDB deployment, all new indexes will use prefix compression."
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "The __________ data structure value provides more granular information concerning the number of operations queued because of a lock.",
        "Options": [
            "a) currentQueue",
            "b) curQueue",
            "c) currentQu",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The serverStatus command returns a document that provides an overview of the database process’s state"
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "serverStatus includes all fields by default, except _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) rangeDeleter",
            "b) rangeDelete",
            "c) rangeDEL",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  You may only dynamically include top-level fields from the serverStatus document that are not included by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "______ field contains total number of current clients that connect to the database instance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) available",
            "b) current",
            "c) always avail",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: available contains the total number of unused connections available for new clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "MongoDB’s _______ is a database profiling system that can help identify inefficient queries and operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reporter",
            "b) Executer",
            "c) Profiler",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enable the profiler by setting the profile value using the following command in the mongo shell."
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "With the _______ storage engine, MongoDB uses memory-mapped files to store data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MMAPv2",
            "b) MMAPv1",
            "c) WiredTiger",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Given a data set of sufficient size, the mongod process will allocate all available memory on the system for its use."
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Spikes in the number of available connections can also be the result of application or driver errors",
            "b) For read-heavy applications, increase the size of your replica set and distribute read operations to secondary members",
            "c) For read-heavy applications, deploy sharding and add one or more shards to a sharded cluster to distribute load among mongod instances",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Extremely high numbers of connections, particularly without corresponding workload is often indicative of a driver or other configuration error."
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "The memory usage statuses metrics of the _________ output can provide insight into MongoDB’s memory use.",
        "Options": [
            "a) globalstats",
            "b) serverStatus",
            "c) locks.deadlockCount",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The serverStatus command returns a document that provides an overview of the database process’s state."
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A single page fault completes slowly and is problematic",
            "b) Increasing the amount of RAM accessible to MongoDB may help reduce the frequency of page faults",
            "c) Page faults also can occur while accessing large data sets or scanning an entire collection",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: However, in aggregate, large volumes of page faults typically indicate that MongoDB is reading too much data from disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "You can inspect __________ to check the amount of mapped memory that mongod is using.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mem.mapped",
            "b) memory.resident",
            "c) mem.resident",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If this value is greater than the amount of system memory, some operations will require a page faults to read data from disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "MongoDB reports its triggered page faults as the total number of page faults in ________ second.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 100",
            "c) 1000",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Rapid increases in the MongoDB page fault counter may indicate that the server has too little physical memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "Which of the operator is used to access the query field of documents within system.profile?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $select",
            "b) $retrieve",
            "c) $query",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can view the output of the profiler in the system.profile collection of your database by issuing the show profile command."
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "____________ returns information on the query plan for aggregate function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reporter",
            "b) db.collection.explain()",
            "c) db.collection.explainplan()",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB runs the query optimizer to choose the winning plan for the operation under evaluation."
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "By default, db.collection.explain() runs in ___________ verbosity mode.",
        "Options": [
            "a) VerbosityMode",
            "b) queryPlanner",
            "c) executeStats",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: db.collection.explain() returns the queryPlanner information for the evaluated method."
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "____________ does not provide query execution information for the rejected plans.",
        "Options": [
            "a) serverstats",
            "b) queryPlanner",
            "c) executionStats",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: executionStats contains statistics that describe the completed query execution for the winning plan."
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "Which of the following provides information on the MongoDB instance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) serverInfo",
            "b) queryPlanner",
            "c) executeStats",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The verbosity mode (i.e. queryPlanner, executionStats, allPlansExecution) determines whether the results include executionStats and whether executionStats includes data captured during plan selection."
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "_________ corresponds to the millis field returned by cursor.explain() in earlier versions of MongoDB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) executionMillis",
            "b) executionTimeMillis",
            "c) timemillis",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  explain.executionStats.executionTimeMillis is total time in milliseconds required for query plan selection and query execution."
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "For sharded collections, explain returns the __________ for each accessed shard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) clientInfo",
            "b) serverInfo",
            "c) serverplan",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For sharded collections, explain returns the core query planner and server information for each accessed shard in the shards field"
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If MongoDB can use an index scan to obtain the requested sort order, the result will not include a SORT stage",
            "b) In previous versions of MongoDB, cursor.explain() returned the scanAndOrder field to specify whether MongoDB could use the index order to return sorted results",
            "c) If MongoDB uses indexes for a $and expression, the result will include the AND stage with an inputStages array that details the replicata sets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If MongoDB uses indexes for a $or expression, the result will include the OR stage with an inputStages array that details the indexes"
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "If the query planner selects a collection scan, the explain result includes a _________ stage.",
        "Options": [
            "a) COLLSCAN",
            "b) TABLESCAN",
            "c) ROWSCAN",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The format and fields of the explain results have changed from previous versions."
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "Which of the following parameter specifies the verbosity mode for the explain output?",
        "Options": [
            "a) verbosity",
            "b) verbose",
            "c) queryPlanner",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mode affects the behavior of explain() and determines the amount of information to return. "
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "In _____________ mode, MongoDB returns statistics describing the execution of the winning plan as well as statistics for the other candidate plans captured during plan selection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) somePlansExecution",
            "b) allPlansExecution",
            "c) rejPlansExecution",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: cursor.explain() returns the queryPlanner and executionStats information for the evaluated method."
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "If the query planner selects a _________ the explain result includes an IXSCAN stage.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Index",
            "b) Replica Set",
            "c) Document",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB runs the query optimizer to choose the winning plan for the operation under evaluation."
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "MongoDB stores additional instance-local metadata in the _______ database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Master",
            "b) Model",
            "c) Local",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is stored specifically for replication purposes."
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can limit the number of incoming connections using the maxConnections run-time option",
            "b) mongos instances maintain a connection pool to each shard so that the mongos can reuse connections",
            "c) You can use the limit command at the system prompt to check system limits",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This would quickly fulfill requests without needing to create new connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "In replica sets, each ________ maintains a connection to all other members of the set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) serverInfo",
            "b) mongod",
            "c) mongos",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongod uses background threads for a number of internal processes, including TTL collections, replication, and replica set health checks, which may require a small number of additional resources."
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "The ___________ collection stores the user’s authentication credentials as well as any roles assigned to the user.",
        "Options": [
            "a) admin.system.auth",
            "b) admin.system.users",
            "c) admin.system.usersauth",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Users may define authorization roles in the admin.system.roles collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The “hard” ulimit refers to the maximum number of processes that a user can have active at any time",
            "b) The “soft” ulimit refers to the minimum number of processes that a user can have active at any time",
            "c) ulimit will modify both “hard” and “soft” values unless the -H or -S modifiers are specified when modifying limit values",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are both “hard” and the “soft” ulimits that affect MongoDB’s performance."
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "The <database>.system.indexes collection lists all the _________ in the database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) serverinfo",
            "b) indexes",
            "c) profiling",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The <database>.system.profile collection stores database profiling information. For information on profiling."
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "Which of the following The collection holds special JavaScript code for use in server side JavaScript?",
        "Options": [
            "a) <database>.system.jserver",
            "b) <database>.system.jscript",
            "c) <database>.system.js",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Do not store application logic in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "Which of the following can store JavaScript functions for reuse?",
        "Options": [
            "a) store.js",
            "b) system.js",
            "c) system.store.js",
            "d) save.js"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To store a function, you can use the db.collection.save()."
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "______ is used to load all the scripts saved in the system.js collection for the current database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.loadServerScripts()",
            "b) db.loadScripts()",
            "c) db.loadServerScriptsjs()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The documents in the system.js collection provide functions that your applications can use in any JavaScript context with MongoDB in this database."
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "Which of the following information is captured by database profiler?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Read operations",
            "b) Write operations",
            "c) Cursor Operations",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The database profiler captures data information about read and write operations, cursor operations, and database commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A limit() value of 0 (i.e. .limit(0)) is equivalent to setting no limit",
            "b) The behavior of limit() is undefined for values less than -231 and greater than 231",
            "c) You can use the ulimit command at the system prompt to check system limits",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Use limit() to maximize performance and prevent MongoDB from returning more results than required for processing."
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "Which of the following collection is capped?",
        "Options": [
            "a) system.index",
            "b) system.replica",
            "c) system.profile",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The database profiler writes data in the system.profile collection, which is a capped collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "The ___________ provides information for various lock types and lock modes held during the operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) admin.system.authlocks",
            "b) system.profile.locks",
            "c) admin.system.locks",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB uses reader-writer locks that allow concurrent readers shared access to a resource, such as a database or collection, but give exclusive access to a single write operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Beginning with version 3.0, MongoDB ships with the WiredTiger storage engine",
            "b) Some global operations, typically short lived operations involving multiple databases, still require a global “instance-wide” lock",
            "c) The MMAPv1 storage engine uses collection-level locking",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MongoDB operations can also yield locks between individual document modifications in write operations that affect multiple documents like update() with the multi parameter."
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "Which of the following keyword represents lock on the collection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database",
            "b) Collection",
            "c) Metadata",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Database represents database lock."
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "How many types of locking modes exist in MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) More than 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are four possible locking modes for the lock types."
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "Which of the following represents number of times the operation acquired the lock in the specified mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) system.profile.locks.acquireCount",
            "b) system.profile.locks.acquireWaitCount",
            "c) system.profile.locks.Count",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: system.profile.locks.acquireWaitCount is number of times the operation had to wait for the acquireCount lock acquisitions because the locks were held in a conflicting mode. acquireWaitCount is less than or equal to acquireCount.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "__________ can be used to limit the size of the result document for a query operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) limit()",
            "b) aggregate()",
            "c) skip()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: limit() is analogous to the LIMIT statement in a SQL database."
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "Which of the following code is used for the successful exit of task?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 0 is returned by MongoDB applications upon successful exit."
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 is returned by mongod if there is a mismatch between hostnames specified on the command line and in the local.sources collection",
            "b) When an index covers a query, MongoDB can both match the query conditions and return the results using only the index keys",
            "c) Both 2 and 4 are returned by mongod if there is a mismatch between hostnames specified on the command line and in the local.sources collection",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  mongod may also return this status if oplog collection in the local database is not readable."
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "Instance exits cleanly are represented by ___ exit code.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Restart mongod with the –upgrade option to upgrade the database to the version supported by this mongod instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "Which of the following code is returned by mongod if a moveChunk operation fails to confirm a commit?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 7",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Exit codes 6 and 7 does not exist."
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exit code 10 is for abnormal exit",
            "b) 4 is returned when the version of the database is different from the version supported by the mongod (or mongod.exe) instance",
            "c) The server socket is on port 27017 by default",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Exit code 10 is not in use."
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "Which of the following code represents exit cleanly following a large clock skew (32768 milliseconds) event?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 45",
            "b) 20",
            "c) 47",
            "d) 100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 100 is returned by mongod when the process throws an uncaught exception."
    },
    {
        "id": 418,
        "Question": "49 code is returned by mongod from _________ Service control Manager.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linux",
            "b) Windows",
            "c) Ubuntu",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Custom read preferences and write concerns evaluate tags sets in different ways."
    },
    {
        "id": 419,
        "Question": "Which of the following code is returned when a MongoDB application cannot open a file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 45",
            "b) 20",
            "c) 47",
            "d) 100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 45 is returned when a MongoDB application cannot open a file or cannot obtain a lock on a file."
    },
    {
        "id": 420,
        "Question": "Identify the message returned by MongoDB applications for Windows due to failures installing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Message: ERROR: wsastartup failed <reason>",
            "b) Message: NT Service Error",
            "c) Message: wsastartup failed <reason>",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 20 is returned by MongoDB applications for Windows due to failures installing, starting or removing the NT Service for the application"
    },
    {
        "id": 421,
        "Question": "Which of the following document represents uncaught exception?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 45",
            "b) 49",
            "c) 47",
            "d) 100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 49 is returned by mongod.exe or mongos.exe on Windows when either receives a shutdown message from the Windows Service Control Manager.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 422,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is used for managing user?",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.createUser()",
            "b) db.User()",
            "c) db.superuser()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB provides the db.createUser() to add and manage user information."
    },
    {
        "id": 423,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Authentication is the process of verifying the identity of a client",
            "b) When access control is enabled, MongoDB requires all clients to authenticate themselves first in order to determine the access for the client",
            "c) Authentication and authorization are closely connected",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Authentication is distinct from authorization."
    },
    {
        "id": 424,
        "Question": "MongoDB stores user information in the _________ collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) system.allusers",
            "b) system.users",
            "c) system.superusers",
            "d) system.usersnone"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB stores all user information, including name, password, and the user’s database, in the system.users collection in the admin database."
    },
    {
        "id": 425,
        "Question": "Which of the following authentication method is used by default by MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SCRAM-SHA-1",
            "b) LDAP",
            "c) MONGODB-CR",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SCRAM-SHA-1 verifies supplied user credentials against the user’s name, password and database."
    },
    {
        "id": 426,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Authorization determines the verified user’s access to resources and operations",
            "b) MongoDB does not support authentication mechanisms",
            "c) To authenticate a client in MongoDB, you must add a corresponding user to MongoDB",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In addition to verifying the identity of a client, MongoDB can require members of replica sets and sharded clusters to authenticate their membership."
    },
    {
        "id": 427,
        "Question": "_________ is a challenge-response mechanism that authenticates users through passwords.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SCRAM-SHA-1",
            "b) LDAP",
            "c) MONGODB-CR",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Using key files, you can also use MONGODB-CR authentication for the internal member authentication of replica set members and sharded cluster members."
    },
    {
        "id": 428,
        "Question": "MongoDB supports _________ certificate authentication for use with a secure TLS/SSL connection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) x.590",
            "b) x.509",
            "c) x.950",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To authenticate to servers, clients can use x.509 certificates instead of usernames and passwords."
    },
    {
        "id": 429,
        "Question": "MongoDB __________ supports authentication using a Kerberos service.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Standard",
            "b) Express",
            "c) Enterprise",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Kerberos is an industry standard authentication protocol for large client/server systems."
    },
    {
        "id": 430,
        "Question": "MongoDB Enterprise supports proxy authentication through ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SCRAM-SHA-1",
            "b) LDAP",
            "c) MONGODB-CR",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB does not support LDAP authentication in mixed sharded cluster deployments that contain both version 2.4 and version 2.6 shards."
    },
    {
        "id": 431,
        "Question": "Every MongoDB mongod and mongos instance (or mongod.exe or mongos.exe on Windows) must have an associated ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) service replica",
            "b) service sets",
            "c) service principal",
            "d) service principle"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Service principal names must be reachable over the network using the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) part of its service principal name.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 432,
        "Question": "MongoDB employs _________ to govern access to a MongoDB system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) RBAS",
            "b) RBAC",
            "c) RBCC",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: RBAC stands for Role-Based Access Control."
    },
    {
        "id": 433,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB provides built-in roles, each with a dedicated purpose for a common use case",
            "b) MongoDB does not enable authorization by default",
            "c) Administrators also can create new roles and privileges to cater to operational needs",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can enable authorization using the –auth or the –keyFile options, or if using a configuration file, with the security.authorization or the security.keyFile settings."
    },
    {
        "id": 434,
        "Question": "__________ consists of a specified resource and the actions permitted on the resource.",
        "Options": [
            "a) privilege",
            "b) action",
            "c) command",
            "d) right"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A privilege resource is either a database, collection, set of collections, or the cluster. "
    },
    {
        "id": 435,
        "Question": "_________ provides all the privileges of the read role.",
        "Options": [
            "a) delete",
            "b) update",
            "c) readWrite",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The role provides the ability to modify data on all non-system collections and the system.js collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 436,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When granted a role, a user receives all the privileges of that role",
            "b) A role consists of privileges that pair resources with not allowed operations",
            "c) User cannot have several roles in MongoDB",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  A user can have several roles concurrently, in which case the user receives the union of all the privileges of the respective roles."
    },
    {
        "id": 437,
        "Question": "MongoDB stores user credentials in the protected admin.system._________",
        "Options": [
            "a) user",
            "b) capped",
            "c) cappeduser",
            "d) users"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The admin.system.users collection stores the user’s authentication credentials as well as any roles assigned to the user."
    },
    {
        "id": 438,
        "Question": "You must have the _______ action on a database to create a new user on that database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) createUser",
            "b) createSuperUser",
            "c) createSuUser",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To provide user administrators, MongoDB has userAdmin and userAdminAnyDatabase roles."
    },
    {
        "id": 439,
        "Question": "Data of  <database>.system.indexes can be accessed using ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) listallIndexes",
            "b) listIndexes",
            "c) ViewIndexes",
            "d) SelectIndexes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Kerberos is an industry standard authentication protocol for large client/server systems."
    },
    {
        "id": 440,
        "Question": "You must have the __________ action on a role’s database to grant the role to another user.",
        "Options": [
            "a) grantRole",
            "b) grantRoleAdm",
            "c) grantRolePrivilege",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: listIndexes returns information about the indexes on the specified collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 441,
        "Question": "Command listIndexes.ok returning value 1 indicates ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) failure",
            "b) success",
            "c) abnormal exit",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A value of 1 indicates success."
    },
    {
        "id": 442,
        "Question": "Administrators can implement collection-level access control through user-defined __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) roles",
            "b) replica sets",
            "c) shards",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: By creating a role with privileges that are scoped to a specific collection in a particular database, administrators can provision users with roles that grant privileges on a collection level."
    },
    {
        "id": 443,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A rule consists of actions and the resources upon which the actions are permissible",
            "b) Document-level access control allows developers to grant users privileges that are scoped to specific record",
            "c) Each privilege action in a role can be scoped to a different record",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Collection-level access control allows administrators to grant users privileges that are scoped to specific collections."
    },
    {
        "id": 444,
        "Question": "User can grant any role in the database to any user from any database in the system through _________ action.",
        "Options": [
            "a) grantRole",
            "b) viewRole",
            "c) killCursors",
            "d) unlock"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Apply this action to database resources."
    },
    {
        "id": 445,
        "Question": "User can remove any role from any user from any database in the system through _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) grantRole",
            "b) viewRole",
            "c) killCursors",
            "d) revokeRole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: User can view information about any role in the given database through viewRole."
    },
    {
        "id": 446,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB uses the combination of the database name and the role name to uniquely define a role",
            "b) A role consists of privileges that pair resources with not allowed operations",
            "c) Roles grant users access to MongoDB resources",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Except for roles created in the admin database, a role can only include privileges that apply to its database and can only inherit from other roles in its database."
    },
    {
        "id": 447,
        "Question": "_________ terminates an operation as specified by the operation ID.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.killOp()",
            "b) db.kill()",
            "c) db.remove()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Only use db.killOp() to terminate operations initiated by clients and do not terminate internal database operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 448,
        "Question": "Which of the following allows the user to view the information of any user in the given database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) createUser",
            "b) viewUser",
            "c) killCursors",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To provide user administrators, MongoDB has userAdmin and userAdminAnyDatabase roles."
    },
    {
        "id": 449,
        "Question": "_________ deletes from a shard the orphaned documents whose shard key values fall into a single continuous range.",
        "Options": [
            "a) listallshards",
            "b) cleanup",
            "c) cleanupOrphaned",
            "d) SelectIndexes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If two contiguous ranges do not belong to the shard, the cleanupOrphaned examines both ranges for orphaned documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 450,
        "Question": "Which of the following flushes user information from in-memory cache?",
        "Options": [
            "a) grantCache",
            "b) invalidateUserCache",
            "c) validateUserCache",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: invalidateUserCache allows you to purge the cache at any given moment, regardless of the interval set in the userCacheInvalidationIntervalSecs parameter."
    },
    {
        "id": 451,
        "Question": "__________ displays the cached query plans for the specified query shape.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CacheListPlans",
            "b) displayCacheListPlans",
            "c) planCacheListPlans",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The query optimizer only caches the plans for those query shapes that can have more than one viable plan."
    },
    {
        "id": 452,
        "Question": "The enabled setting for mongod and mongos instances disables the __________ status page.",
        "Options": [
            "a) home",
            "b) primary",
            "c) secondary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The mongod and mongos instances run with the http interface disabled by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 453,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The status interface is write-only by default",
            "b) Default port for the status page is 28117",
            "c) Authentication does not control or affect access to this interface",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If you enable this interface, you should only allow trusted clients to access this port."
    },
    {
        "id": 454,
        "Question": "The net.http.RESTInterfaceEnabled setting for mongod enables a fully interactive administrative __________ interface, which is disabled by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Restful",
            "b) Rest",
            "c) WebService",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The REST interface does not support any authentication and you should always restrict access to this interface to only allow trusted clients to connect to this port."
    },
    {
        "id": 455,
        "Question": "The ________ setting for mongod and mongos instances limits the network interfaces on which MongoDB programs will listen for incoming connections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bindIpmongo",
            "b) bind",
            "c) bindIp",
            "d) revokeip"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can also specify a number of interfaces by passing bindIp a comma separated list of IP addresses."
    },
    {
        "id": 456,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Changing the port does not meaningfully reduce risk or limit exposure",
            "b) You can use the mongod –bind_ip and mongos –bind_ip option on the command line at run time to limit the network accessibility of a MongoDB program",
            "c) The net.http.RESTInterfaceEnabled configuration makes the http status interface, which is read-only by default, fully interactive",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If your system has more than one network interface, bind MongoDB programs to the private or internal network interface."
    },
    {
        "id": 457,
        "Question": "The ________ setting for mongod and mongos instances changes the main port on which the mongod or mongos instance listens for connections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) portp",
            "b) port",
            "c) portIP",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Setting port also indirectly sets the port for the HTTP status interface, which is always available on the port numbered 1000 greater than the primary mongod port."
    },
    {
        "id": 458,
        "Question": "On Linux systems, the ________ interface provides access to the underlying netfilter firewall.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ssip",
            "b) iptables",
            "c) dns",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Firewalls allow administrators to filter and control access to a system by providing granular control over what network communications."
    },
    {
        "id": 459,
        "Question": "On Windows systems _________ command line interface provides access to the underlying Windows Firewall.",
        "Options": [
            "a) netsh",
            "b) netstat",
            "c) netln",
            "d) SelectIndexes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To minimize overall exposure, ensure that only traffic from trusted sources can reach mongod and mongos instances and that the mongod and mongos instances can only connect to trusted outputs."
    },
    {
        "id": 460,
        "Question": "MongoDB users who use VPNs use ________ rather than IPSEC VPNs for performance issues.",
        "Options": [
            "a) TTS",
            "b) SSL",
            "c) LTS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Virtual private networks, or VPNs, make it possible to link two networks over an encrypted and limited-access trusted network."
    },
    {
        "id": 461,
        "Question": "By default, the policy in ___________ Firewall allows all outbound connections and blocks all incoming connections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windows",
            "b) Linux",
            "c) Mac",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Given the default ports of all MongoDB processes, you must configure networking rules that permit only required communication between your application and the appropriate mongod.exe and mongos.exe instances."
    },
    {
        "id": 462,
        "Question": "The mongo program can evaluate JavaScript expressions using the command line ________ option.",
        "Options": [
            "a) –opt",
            "b) –js",
            "c) –eval",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The mongo program can evaluate a JavaScript file (.js) passed directly to it (e.g. mongo someFile.js)."
    },
    {
        "id": 463,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The mongostat diagnostic tool, when running with the –mode need to be able to reach all components of a cluster",
            "b) All shards in a cluster need to be able to communicate with all other shards to facilitate chunk and balancing operations",
            "c) Authorization does not control or affect access to this interface",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can also specify the shard server option with the shardsvr value for the clusterRole setting in the configuration file. Shard members are also often conventional replica sets using the default port."
    },
    {
        "id": 464,
        "Question": "If a .mongorc.js file exists, the mongo shell will evaluate a __________ file before starting.",
        "Options": [
            "a) .mongorc.js",
            "b) .mongo.js",
            "c) .mongorc.jscript",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can disable this behavior by passing the mongo –norc option."
    },
    {
        "id": 465,
        "Question": "On _________ mongo.exe reads the .mongorc.js file from %HOME%.mongorc.js.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windows",
            "b) Linux",
            "c) Mac",
            "d) Solaris"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: On Linux and Unix systems, mongo reads the .mongorc.js file from $HOME/.mongorc.js."
    },
    {
        "id": 466,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) REST does provide administrative access, and its accessibility represents a vulnerability in a secure environment",
            "b) REST API does provide any support for insert, update, or remove operations",
            "c) The net.http.RESTInterfaceEnabled configuration makes the http status interface, which is read-only by default, fully interactive",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: REST API does not provide any support for insert, update, or remove operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 467,
        "Question": "The HTTP interface is always available on the port numbered _________ greater than the primary mongod port.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1000",
            "b) 2000",
            "c) 3000",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: By default, the HTTP interface port is 28017, but is indirectly set using the port option which allows you to configure the primary mongod port."
    },
    {
        "id": 468,
        "Question": "The _______ API to MongoDB provides additional information and write access on top of the HTTP status interface.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Web",
            "b) REST",
            "c) RestFul",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The REST interface is disabled by default, and is not recommended for production use."
    },
    {
        "id": 469,
        "Question": "________ instances provide query routing for sharded clusters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongos",
            "c) netstats",
            "d) selectindexes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Clients connect to mongos instances, which behave from the client’s perspective as mongod instances."
    },
    {
        "id": 470,
        "Question": "Config servers, host the _______ database that stores metadata for sharded clusters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) head",
            "b) master",
            "c) config",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Each production cluster has three config servers, initiated using the mongod –configsvr option."
    },
    {
        "id": 471,
        "Question": "Config servers listen for connections on port __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 27011",
            "b) 27019",
            "c) 27107",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You also can run a config server by using the configsvr value for the clusterRole setting in a configuration file."
    },
    {
        "id": 472,
        "Question": "The auditing facility can write audit events to the console, the _________ a JSON file, or a BSON file.",
        "Options": [
            "a) oplog",
            "b) syslog",
            "c) evallog",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  MongoDB provides an option to send output to the host’s syslog system."
    },
    {
        "id": 473,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When a process writes to a resource, it takes an exclusive write lock to prevent other processes from writing to or reading from that resource",
            "b) As clients insert new documents into the capped collection, the tailable cursor continues to retrieve documents",
            "c) Write concern allows your application to detect insertion errors or unavailable mongod instances",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  MongoDB Enterprise includes an auditing capability for mongod and mongos instances."
    },
    {
        "id": 474,
        "Question": " _________ contains the local ip address and the port number of the running instance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ts",
            "b) local",
            "c) remote",
            "d) users"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Remote document contains the remote ip address and the port number of the incoming connection associated with the event."
    },
    {
        "id": 475,
        "Question": "Enabling _____________ degrades performance more than logging only the authorization failures.",
        "Options": [
            "a) auditAuthorizationFailure",
            "b) auditAuthorizationSuccess",
            "c) auditAuthorizationlog",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: System Event Audit Message is available only in MongoDB Enterprise."
    },
    {
        "id": 476,
        "Question": "Use the ____________ option to enable auditing and specify where to output the audit events.",
        "Options": [
            "a) –auditLocation",
            "b) –auditOutput",
            "c) –auditDestination",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For sharded clusters, if you enable auditing on mongos instances, you must enable auditing on all mongod instances in the cluster, i.e. shards and config servers."
    },
    {
        "id": 477,
        "Question": "The audit file rotates at the same time as the ________ log file.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Client",
            "b) Server",
            "c) Application",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Printing audit events to a file in JSON format degrades server performance more than printing to a file in BSON format."
    },
    {
        "id": 478,
        "Question": "To view the contents of the file, pass the file to the MongoDB utility ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) bsonlog",
            "b) bsonout",
            "c) bsondump",
            "d) SelectIndexes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The following converts the audit log into a human-readable form and output to the terminal: bsondump data/db/auditLog.bson ."
    },
    {
        "id": 479,
        "Question": "The _____________ option accepts either full path name or relative path name.",
        "Options": [
            "a) –auditPathLog",
            "b) –logPath",
            "c) –auditPath",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To enable auditing and print audit events to a file in BSON binary format, specify file for the –auditDestination setting, BSON for the –auditFormat setting, and the output filename for the –auditPath."
    },
    {
        "id": 480,
        "Question": "The _________ message limit can result in the truncation of the audit messages.",
        "Options": [
            "a) oplog",
            "b) syslog",
            "c) evallog",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The auditing system will neither detect the truncation nor error upon its occurrence."
    },
    {
        "id": 481,
        "Question": "For each _______ the Kerberos Key Distribution Center (KDC) maintains a database of the realm’s principal and the principal’s associated “secret keys”.",
        "Options": [
            "a) key",
            "b) realm",
            "c) document",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Principals belong to administrative units called realms."
    },
    {
        "id": 482,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB Enterprise provides support for Kerberos authentication of MongoDB clients to mongod and mongos",
            "b) Kerberos is an industry standard authentication protocol for large client/server systems",
            "c) Kerberos allows MongoDB and applications to take advantage of existing authentication infrastructure and processes",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In a Kerberos-based system, every participant in the authenticated communication is known as a “principal”, and every principal must have a unique name."
    },
    {
        "id": 483,
        "Question": "For a client-server authentication, the client requests from the KDC a ________ for access to a specific asset.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ticket",
            "b) local",
            "c) token",
            "d) user"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: KDC uses the client’s secret and the server’s secret to construct the ticket which allows the client and server to mutually authenticate each other, while keeping the secrets hidden."
    },
    {
        "id": 484,
        "Question": "To authenticate using Kerberos, you must add the Kerberos user principals to MongoDB to the _________ database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $internal",
            "b) $external",
            "c) $extern",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For every user you want to authenticate using Kerberos, you must create a corresponding user in MongoDB in the $external database."
    },
    {
        "id": 485,
        "Question": "To specify a different value for <service>, use ________ during the start up of mongod.",
        "Options": [
            "a) servicepwd",
            "b) serviceName",
            "c) servicelogin",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mongo shell or other clients may also specify a different service principal name using serviceName."
    },
    {
        "id": 486,
        "Question": "Linux systems can store Kerberos authentication keys for a service principal in ______ files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Client",
            "b) Server",
            "c) keytab",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To keep keytab files secure, use file permissions that restrict access to only the user that runs the mongod or mongos process."
    },
    {
        "id": 487,
        "Question": "On Linux, MongoDB clients can use Kerberos’s _______ program to initialize a credential cache for authenticating the user principal to servers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) knight",
            "b) kinit",
            "c) Knite",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Unlike on Linux systems, mongod and mongos instances running on Windows do not require access to keytab files."
    },
    {
        "id": 488,
        "Question": "The MongoDB _________ Console interface does not support Kerberos authentication.",
        "Options": [
            "a) TCP",
            "b) HTTP",
            "c) HTTPS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Each host that runs a mongod or mongos instance must have both A and PTR DNS records to provide forward and reverse lookup."
    },
    {
        "id": 489,
        "Question": "Use __________ to encrypt communication between mongod and mongos components of a MongoDB client as well as between all applications and MongoDB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSD",
            "b) TLS",
            "c) MEAN",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Create roles that define the exact access a set of users needs."
    },
    {
        "id": 490,
        "Question": "With ___________ enabled, MongoDB forces all clients to identify themselves before granting access to the server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) access",
            "b) authentication",
            "c) authorization",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: KDC uses the client’s secret and the server’s secret to construct the ticket which allows the client and server to mutually authenticate each other, while keeping the secrets hidden."
    },
    {
        "id": 491,
        "Question": "___________ allows administrators to define and limit the resources and operations that a user can access.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Access",
            "b) Authentication",
            "c) Authorization",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Using authentication and authorization is a key part of a complete security strategy."
    },
    {
        "id": 492,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) User principal names have the form: <userpwd>@<KERBEROS PRINCIPAL>",
            "b) For MongoDB, the <service> defaults to mongodb",
            "c) Every MongoDB mongod and mongos instance must have an associated service principal",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: User principal names have the form: <userpwd>@<KERBEROS PRINCIPAL>."
    },
    {
        "id": 493,
        "Question": "Use the __________ option to ensure that MongoDB listens for connections from applications on configured addresses.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bind_ipadd",
            "b) bind_ip",
            "c) bind_service",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For a geographically distributed replica sets, ensure that the majority of the set’s mongod instances reside in the primary site."
    },
    {
        "id": 494,
        "Question": "To generate pseudo-random data to use for a keyfile, issue the following __________ command.",
        "Options": [
            "a) openhss",
            "b) openssd",
            "c) openssl",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Always ensure that the password stored in the key file is both long and contains a high amount of entropy. Using openssl in this manner helps generate such a key."
    },
    {
        "id": 495,
        "Question": "_____________ is used to initiate relica member set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.rep()",
            "b) rs.init()",
            "c) rs.initiate()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  MongoDB initiates a set that consists of the current member and that uses the default replica set configuration."
    },
    {
        "id": 496,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to display the replica set configuration object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.config",
            "b) rs.conf",
            "c) rs.confrepl",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: rs.conf() returns a document that contains the current replica set configuration."
    },
    {
        "id": 497,
        "Question": "MongoDB supports the execution of JavaScript code for certain server-side operations like ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) where",
            "b) group",
            "c) mapreduce",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If you do not use these operations, disable server-side scripting by using the –noscripting option on the command line."
    },
    {
        "id": 498,
        "Question": "If you create the user administrator before enabling access control, MongoDB disables the ________ exception.",
        "Options": [
            "a) localhost",
            "b) server",
            "c) runtime",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The localhost exception allows you to enable authorization before creating the first user in the system."
    },
    {
        "id": 499,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) After you create the user administrator, the localhost exception is no longer available",
            "b) Enabling access control on a MongoDB instance restricts access to the instance by requiring that users identify themselves when connecting",
            "c) The mongo shell executes a number of commands at start up",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: As a result, when you log in as the user administrator, you may see authentication errors from one or more commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 500,
        "Question": "If you use the localhost exception when deploying a new MongoDB system, the first user you create must be in the ________ database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) head",
            "b) local",
            "c) admin",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the case of a sharded cluster, the localhost exception applies to each shard individually as well as to the cluster as a whole. "
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "Question": "If you need to disable access control for any reason, restart the process with ______ setting.",
        "Options": [
            "a) KeyFile",
            "b) Authentication",
            "c) Authorization",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Login in with the user administrator’s credentials and create additional users."
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Authentication does not require an authentication mechanism",
            "b) To enable authentication on a sharded cluster, you must enable authentication individually on each component of the cluster",
            "c) The content of the key file must be the same on all cluster members",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Authentication requires an authentication mechanism and, in most cases, a key file. "
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "Question": "The ________ client authentication allows clients to authenticate to servers with certificates rather than with a username and password.",
        "Options": [
            "a) x.209",
            "b) x.509",
            "c) x.709",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB supports x.509 certificate authentication for use with a secure TLS/SSL connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "Question": "enableLocalhostAuthBypass is not available using _________ database command.",
        "Options": [
            "a) setParameter",
            "b) enableParameter",
            "c) removeParameter",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Use the setParameter option in the configuration file or the –setParameter option on the command line."
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "Question": "______________ enables a set of internal commands useful for internal testing operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) enableTestAll",
            "b) enableTest",
            "c) enableTestCommands",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: enableTestCommands is only available when starting mongod and you cannot use setParameter to modify this parameter."
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "Question": "To view a role’s information, you must be explicitly granted the role or must have the _________ action on the role’s database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) viewUser",
            "b) viewRole",
            "c) grantRole",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The localhost exception allows you to enable authorization before creating the first user in the system."
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To provide user administrators, MongoDB has userAdmin and userAdminAnyDatabase roles",
            "b) A user administrator can grant any privilege in the database and can create new ones",
            "c) Specifically, a user with the userAdmin role can grant itself any privilege in the database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A user assigned either the userAdmin role on the admin database or the userAdminAnyDatabase can grant itself any privilege in the system."
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "Question": "Grant the user the role using the ________ method.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.grantRole()",
            "b) db.grantRolesToUser()",
            "c) db.grantToUser()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the user requires additional privileges, grant to the user the role, or roles, with the required set of privileges. "
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is used to identify the privileges granted by the roles?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rolesUser",
            "b) rolesInfo",
            "c) rolesView",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: db.getRole() wraps the rolesInfo command."
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You must have the createUser action on a database to create a new user on that database",
            "b) You must have the grantRole action on a role’s database to grant the role to another user",
            "c) If your MongoDB deployment has no users, you must connect to mongod using the localhost exception",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can use –noauth option when starting mongod to gain full access the system."
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "Question": "____________ removes a one or more roles from a user on the current database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.revokeRolesUser()",
            "b) db.revokeRoles()",
            "c) db.revokeRolesFromUser()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To specify a role that exists in the same database where db.revokeRolesFromUser() runs, you can either specify the role with the name of the role."
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "Question": "You must have the __________ action on a database to revoke a role on that database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) revokePrivelege",
            "b) revokeUser",
            "c) revokeRole",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: User can remove any role from any user from any database in the system."
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "Question": "You must have the _________ action on a database to modify the password of any user on that database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) changePassword",
            "b) changeAnyPassword",
            "c) removePassword",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To change your own password, you must have the changeOwnPassword action on your database."
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be used to generate unique strings for use in passwords?",
        "Options": [
            "a) openssl",
            "b) openssd",
            "c) oppstringpwd",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can use the openssl program to generate unique strings for use in passwords, as in the following command: openssl rand -base64 48"
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "Question": "The ________ field contains optional custom information about the user.",
        "Options": [
            "a) customDataAll",
            "b) OptmData",
            "c) customData",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The system.users collection in the admin database stores user authentication and authorization information."
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "Question": "____________ are operations that process data records and return computed results.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ReplicaAgg",
            "b) SumCalculation",
            "c) Aggregations",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MongoDB provides a rich set of aggregation operations that examine and perform calculations on the data sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Map-reduce cannot have a finalize stage to make final modifications to the result",
            "b) Map-reduce is less efficient and more complex than the aggregation pipeline",
            "c) Specifically, a user with the userAdmin role can grant itself any privilege in the database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In general, map-reduce operations have two phases: a map stage that processes each document and emits one or more objects for each input document, and reduce phase that combines the output of the map operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "Question": "Running data aggregation on the ________ instance simplifies application code and limits resource requirements.",
        "Options": [
            "a) document",
            "b) mongod",
            "c) mongos",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Like queries, aggregation operations in MongoDB use collections of documents as an input and return results in the form of one or more documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "Question": "Documents enter a multi-stage __________ that transforms the documents into an aggregated result.",
        "Options": [
            "a) pipeline",
            "b) pipelineView",
            "c) pipelineUser",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB 2.2 introduced a new aggregation framework, modeled on the concept of data processing pipelines."
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB also provides map-reduce operations to perform aggregation",
            "b) The pipeline provides efficient data aggregation using native operations within MongoDB",
            "c) Map-reduce can specify a query condition to select the input documents as well as sort and limit the results",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Aggregation is the preferred method for data aggregation in MongoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 521,
        "Question": "The most basic pipeline stages provide __________ that operate like queries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) methods",
            "b) filters",
            "c) stored procedure",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Other pipeline operations provide tools for grouping and sorting documents by specific field."
    },
    {
        "id": 522,
        "Question": "Pipeline stages can use __________ for tasks such as calculating the average or concatenating a string.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replicas",
            "b) operators",
            "c) roles",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: User can remove any role from any user from any database in the system."
    },
    {
        "id": 523,
        "Question": "Map-reduce uses custom __________ functions to perform the map and reduce operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Java",
            "b) Javascript",
            "c) JSON",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  JavaScript provide great flexibility compared to the aggregation pipeline."
    },
    {
        "id": 524,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation can be optionally used for map reduce?",
        "Options": [
            "a) finally",
            "b) final",
            "c) static",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Certain mongo shell functions and properties are inaccessible in map-reduce operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 525,
        "Question": "The aggregation pipeline can use ___________ to improve its performance during some of its stages.",
        "Options": [
            "a) indexes",
            "b) OptmData",
            "c) functions",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Both the aggregation pipeline and map-reduce can operate on a sharded collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 526,
        "Question": "Aggregation pipeline was introduced in MongoDB version ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.1",
            "b) 2.2",
            "c) 2.4",
            "d) 3.0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The aggregation pipeline provides an alternative to map-reduce."
    },
    {
        "id": 527,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aggregation pipeline have some limitations on value types and result size",
            "b) The aggregation pipeline is a framework for data aggregation modeled on the concept of data processing pipelines",
            "c) Documents enter a multi-stage pipeline that transforms the documents into an aggregated results",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The MongoDB aggregation pipeline consists of stages."
    },
    {
        "id": 528,
        "Question": "________ calculates aggregate values for the data in a collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.collection.aggregate",
            "b) db.collection.agg",
            "c) db.collection.pipeline",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the mongo shell, if the cursor returned from the db.collection.aggregate() is not assigned to a variable using the var keyword, then the mongo shell automatically iterates the cursor up to 20 times."
    },
    {
        "id": 529,
        "Question": "Cursors returned from aggregation only supports cursor methods like ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) cursor.hasNext()",
            "b) cursor.Next()",
            "c) cursor.has()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  cursor.hasNext() returns true if the cursor returned by the db.collection.find() query can iterate further to return more documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 530,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Some pipeline stages may generate new documents or filter out documents",
            "b) Pipeline stages do need to produce one output document for every input document",
            "c) Pipeline stages can appear multiple times in the pipeline",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pipeline stages do need to produce one output document for every input document."
    },
    {
        "id": 531,
        "Question": "______ can be used to iterate the cursor of document results returned by db.collection.find().",
        "Options": [
            "a) it",
            "b) next",
            "c) cur",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The mongo shell iterates the returned cursor automatically to print the results. "
    },
    {
        "id": 532,
        "Question": "To handle large datasets, set _________ option to true to enable writing data to temporary files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) enableDiskUse",
            "b) allowDiskUse",
            "c) validateDiksUse",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the mongo shell, when you assign the cursor returned from the find() method to a variable using the var keyword, the cursor does not automatically iterate."
    },
    {
        "id": 533,
        "Question": "Syntax for specifying an initial batch size for the cursor is ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) cursor: { batchSize: <string> }",
            "b) cursor: { batchSize: <int> }",
            "c) cur: { batchSize: <int> }",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A batchSize of 0 means an empty first batch and is useful for quickly returning a cursor or failure message without doing significant server-side work."
    },
    {
        "id": 534,
        "Question": "Query shape consists of a combination of query, sort, and _________ specifications.",
        "Options": [
            "a) selection",
            "b) projection",
            "c) collection",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If an index filter exists for a given query shape, the optimizer only considers those indexes specified in the filter."
    },
    {
        "id": 535,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is overrided by Index filters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) hint",
            "b) plan",
            "c) execute",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When an index filter exists for the query shape, MongoDB ignores the hint()."
    },
    {
        "id": 536,
        "Question": "Which of the following database command is used for mapreduce function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mapReduce",
            "b) mapperRed",
            "c) redmap",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  For map-reduce operations, MongoDB provides the mapReduce database command."
    },
    {
        "id": 537,
        "Question": "MongoDB applies the _____ phase to each input document in mapreduce.",
        "Options": [
            "a) map",
            "b) reduce",
            "c) mapper",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The map function emits key-value pairs."
    },
    {
        "id": 538,
        "Question": "MongoDB applies the _________ phase, which collects and condenses the aggregated data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) map",
            "b) reduce",
            "c) mapper",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB then stores the results in a collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 539,
        "Question": "The output of the reduce function may pass through a ______ function to further condense or process the results of the aggregation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) finalize",
            "b) filter",
            "c) procedure",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  The input and the output collections may be sharded."
    },
    {
        "id": 540,
        "Question": "_________ can return the results of a map-reduce operation as a document, or may write the results to collections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mapReduce",
            "b) mapperRed",
            "c) RedMap",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Map-reduce operations take the documents of a single collection as the input and can perform any arbitrary sorting and limiting before beginning the map stage."
    },
    {
        "id": 541,
        "Question": "Map-reduce uses custom __________ functions to perform the map and reduce operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Java",
            "b) Javascript",
            "c) JSON",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  JavaScript provide great flexibility compared to the aggregation pipeline."
    },
    {
        "id": 542,
        "Question": "For most aggregation operations, the ______ Pipeline provides better performance and more coherent interface.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aggregate",
            "b) Replication",
            "c) Sharding",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Map-reduce operations provide some flexibility that is not presently available in the aggregation pipeline."
    },
    {
        "id": 543,
        "Question": "What would be the maximum document size for results of mapreduce operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15 MB",
            "b) 16 MB",
            "c) 17 MB",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When returning the results of a map reduce operation inline, the result documents must be within the BSON Document Size limit, which is currently 16 megabytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 544,
        "Question": "_______ filters the document stream to allow only matching documents to pass unmodified into the next pipeline stage.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $regex",
            "b) $reg",
            "c) $match",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $match uses standard MongoDB queries. For each input document, outputs either one document (a match) or zero documents (no match)."
    },
    {
        "id": 545,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Documents do not pass through the stages in sequence",
            "b) Pipeline stages appear in an multi dimensional array",
            "c) $project reshapes each document in the stream, such as by adding new fields or removing existing fields",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For each input document, outputs one document."
    },
    {
        "id": 546,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be used to implement field level redaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $skip",
            "b) $limit",
            "c) $match",
            "d) $redact"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: $redact reshapes each document in the stream by restricting the content for each document based on information stored in the documents themselves."
    },
    {
        "id": 547,
        "Question": "________ passes the first n documents unmodified to the pipeline where n is the specified limit.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $skip",
            "b) $limit",
            "c) $match",
            "d) $redact"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For each input document, outputs either one document (for the first n documents) or zero documents (after the first n documents)."
    },
    {
        "id": 548,
        "Question": "_______ reorders the document stream by a specified sort key.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $skip",
            "b) $limit",
            "c) $sort",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Only the order changes; the documents remain unmodified."
    },
    {
        "id": 549,
        "Question": "Which of the following operator incorporates the functionality of $match, $sort, and $limit for geospatial data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $geoSpatial",
            "b) $geoNear",
            "c) $geoRear",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output documents include an additional distance field and can include a location identifier field."
    },
    {
        "id": 550,
        "Question": "_____ Writes the resulting documents of the aggregation pipeline to a collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $out",
            "b) $in",
            "c) $output",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To use the $out stage, it must be the last stage in the pipeline."
    },
    {
        "id": 551,
        "Question": "________ deconstructs an array field from the input documents to output a document for each element.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $unwindelem",
            "b) $unwind",
            "c) $unwin",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Each output document replaces the array with an element value."
    },
    {
        "id": 552,
        "Question": "Which of the following operator is related to geography of data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $geoSpatial",
            "b) $geoNear",
            "c) $geoRear",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $geoNear returns an ordered stream of documents based on the proximity to a geospatial point."
    },
    {
        "id": 553,
        "Question": "Which of the following stages cannot appear multiple times in a pipeline?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $regex",
            "b) $reg",
            "c) $match",
            "d) $out"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To use the $out stage, it must be the last stage in the pipeline."
    },
    {
        "id": 554,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To access variables in expressions, use a string that prefixes the variable name with $$$",
            "b) Expressions can include field paths and system variables, literals, expression objects, and expression operators",
            "c) To specify a field path, use a string that prefixes with a dollar sign % the field name or the dotted field name",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Expressions can be nested."
    },
    {
        "id": 555,
        "Question": "Aggregation expressions use ______ path to access fields in the input documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mpath",
            "b) dbpath",
            "c) lpath",
            "d) field"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To specify a field path, use a string that prefixes with a dollar sign $ the field name or the dotted field name, if the field is in embedded document."
    },
    {
        "id": 556,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is equivalent to “$$CURRENT.<field>”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) “$%<field>”",
            "b) “%<field>”",
            "c) “$$<field>”",
            "d) “$<field>”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: CURRENT is a system variable that defaults to the root of the current object in the most stages, unless stated otherwise in specific stages."
    },
    {
        "id": 557,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Literals can be of any type",
            "b) CURRENT cannot be rebound",
            "c) MongoDB parses string literals that start with a dollar sign $",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Along with the CURRENT system variable, other system variables are also available for use in expressions."
    },
    {
        "id": 558,
        "Question": "______ binds variables for use in the specified expression.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $skip",
            "b) $let",
            "c) $bind",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $let also returns the result of the expression."
    },
    {
        "id": 559,
        "Question": "________ applies an expression to each item in an array and returns an array with the applied results.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $map",
            "b) $geo",
            "c) $geoRear",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The $map expression has the following syntax: { $map: { input: <expressi>, as: <string>, in: <expression> } }"
    },
    {
        "id": 560,
        "Question": "In the vars assignment block, ________ refers to the value of an externally defined variable low.",
        "Options": [
            "a) “$$low”",
            "b) “$$lowin”",
            "c) “$$1”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If low is not defined outside this $let expression block, the expression is invalid."
    },
    {
        "id": 561,
        "Question": "To avoid treating numeric or boolean literals as projection flags, use the _______ expression to wrap the numeric or boolean literals.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $literal",
            "b) $bool",
            "c) $unwin",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The $literal expression has the following syntax: { $literal: <value> }"
    },
    {
        "id": 562,
        "Question": "MongoDB treats the literals as projection flags, valid only in the _______ stage.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $project",
            "b) $gmap",
            "c) $match",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Projection flags can be 1 or true to include the field."
    },
    {
        "id": 563,
        "Question": "______ expressions ignores the duplicate entries in each input array and the order of the elements.",
        "Options": [
            "a) set",
            "b) boolean",
            "c) aggregate",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the set operation returns a set, the operation filters out duplicates in the result to output an array that contains only unique entries."
    },
    {
        "id": 564,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To avoid parsing ambiguity if the argument is a literal array, you must wrap the literal array in a $lits expression or keep the outer array that designates the argument list",
            "b) Expressions cannot include field paths and system variables, literals, expression objects, and expression operators",
            "c) Operator expressions are similar to functions that take arguments",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In general, these expressions take an array of arguments and have the following form: { <operator>: [ <argument1>, <argument2> … ] }"
    },
    {
        "id": 565,
        "Question": "________ returns true if the input sets have the same distinct elements.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setUnion",
            "b) $setDifference",
            "c) $setEquals",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:$setEquals accepts two or more argument expressions."
    },
    {
        "id": 566,
        "Question": "Which of the following accepts any number of argument expression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setIntersection",
            "b) $setDifference",
            "c) $setEquals",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:$setIntersection returns a set with elements that appear in all of the input sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 567,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Boolean expressions evaluate their argument expressions as booleans and return a boolean as the result",
            "b) In addition to the false boolean value, Boolean expression evaluates as false the following: null, 0, and undefined values",
            "c) Set expressions performs set operation on arrays, treating arrays as sets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Boolean expression evaluates all other values as true, including non-zero numeric values and arrays."
    },
    {
        "id": 568,
        "Question": "________ returns a set with elements that appear in any of the input sets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setIntersection",
            "b) $setDifference",
            "c) $setEquals",
            "d) $setUnion"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:$setUnion performs set operation on arrays, treating arrays as sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 569,
        "Question": "Which of the following performs a relative complement of the second set relative to the first?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setIntersection",
            "b) $setDifference",
            "c) $setEquals",
            "d) $setUnion"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:$setDifference returns a set with elements that appear in the first set but not in the second set."
    },
    {
        "id": 570,
        "Question": "$setIsSubset\treturns _______ if all elements of the first set appear in the second set, including when the first set equals the second set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Null",
            "b) True",
            "c) False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:$setIsSubset accepts exactly two argument expressions."
    },
    {
        "id": 571,
        "Question": "_______ accepts only single argument expression.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setIsSubset",
            "b) $bool",
            "c) $anyElementTrue",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:$anyElementTrue returns true if any elements of a set evaluate to true; otherwise, returns false."
    },
    {
        "id": 572,
        "Question": "$allElementsTrue returns true if no element of a set evaluates to ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) false",
            "b) true",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An empty array returns true."
    },
    {
        "id": 573,
        "Question": "Comparison expressions return a boolean except for ________ which returns a number.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $copy",
            "b) $cmp",
            "c) $num",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The $cmp compares both value and type, using the specified BSON comparison order for values of different types."
    },
    {
        "id": 574,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The comparison expressions take two argument expressions and compare both value and type, using the specified Java comparison order for values of different types",
            "b) $gte\treturns true if the first value is greater than the second",
            "c) $gte\treturns true if the first value is greater than or equal to the second",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In general, these expressions take an array of arguments and have the following form: { <operator>: [ <argument1>, <argument2> … ] }"
    },
    {
        "id": 575,
        "Question": "______ returns true if the first value is less than the second.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $lte",
            "b) $lt",
            "c) $setEquals",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:$lte returns true if the first value is less than or equal to the second."
    },
    {
        "id": 576,
        "Question": "$ne returns true if the values are not _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) equivalent",
            "b) null",
            "c) 0",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:$ne compares two values and returns false when the values are equivalent."
    },
    {
        "id": 577,
        "Question": "$multiply __________ numbers to return the result.",
        "Options": [
            "a) multiplies",
            "b) divides",
            "c) comapres",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:$multiply accepts any number of argument expressions."
    },
    {
        "id": 578,
        "Question": "_______ adds numbers to return the sum, or adds numbers and a date to return a new date.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $addnum",
            "b) $setadd",
            "c) $adds",
            "d) $add"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If adding numbers and a date, treats the numbers as milliseconds."
    },
    {
        "id": 579,
        "Question": "_______ returns the remainder of the first number divided by the second.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rem",
            "b) $mod",
            "c) $div",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:$divide returns the result of dividing the first number by the second."
    },
    {
        "id": 580,
        "Question": "String expressions, with the exception of ________ only have a well-defined behavior for strings of ASCII characters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setcon",
            "b) $concatenation",
            "c) $concat",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:$concat behavior is well-defined regardless of the characters used."
    },
    {
        "id": 581,
        "Question": "________ subtracts two dates to return the difference in milliseconds.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rem",
            "b) $mod",
            "c) $div",
            "d) $subtract"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The $subtract expression has the following syntax: { $subtract: [ <expression1>, <expression2> ] }."
    },
    {
        "id": 582,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns a substring of a string?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $subs",
            "b) $substring",
            "c) $substr",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $substr accepts three expressions as arguments: the first argument must resolve to a string, and the second and third arguments must resolve to integers."
    },
    {
        "id": 583,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $substr ends at a specified index position up to a specified length",
            "b) $toLower converts a string to lowercase",
            "c) $gtle returns true if the first value is greater than or equal to the second",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the argument resolves to null, $toLower returns an empty string “”."
    },
    {
        "id": 584,
        "Question": "Which of the following accepts a single argument expression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $toLow",
            "b) $toUpper",
            "c) $toEqual",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $toUpper converts a string to uppercase."
    },
    {
        "id": 585,
        "Question": "Which of the following performs case-insensitive string comparison?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $strcasecmpequals",
            "b) $strcasecmp",
            "c) $strcmp",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: $strcasecmp returns 0 if two strings are equivalent."
    },
    {
        "id": 586,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) { $meta: “textScore” } expression is only meaningful in a pipeline that includes a $match stage with a $text query",
            "b) The { $meta: “textScore” } expression is the only expression that the $sort stage accepts",
            "c) $toLower only has a well-defined behavior for strings of ASCII characters",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A $meta expression has the following syntax:{ $meta: <metaDataKeyword> }."
    },
    {
        "id": 587,
        "Question": "_______ is used for access text search metadata.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $text",
            "b) $metades",
            "c) $meta",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $meta returns the metadata associated with a document in a pipeline operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 588,
        "Question": "Which of the following accepts named parameters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $reduce",
            "b) $letnum",
            "c) $let",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: $let defines variables for use within the scope of a subexpression and returns the result of the subexpression."
    },
    {
        "id": 589,
        "Question": "_______ returns the number of elements in the array.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $number",
            "b) $size",
            "c) $div",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The argument for $size can be any expression as long as it resolves to an array."
    },
    {
        "id": 590,
        "Question": "_________ returns a value without parsing.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $string",
            "b) $literal",
            "c) $characters",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Use for values that the aggregation pipeline may interpret as an expression."
    },
    {
        "id": 591,
        "Question": "db.collection.aggregate() returns a _______ and can return result sets of any size.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replica",
            "b) cursor",
            "c) document",
            "d) $subtract"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The aggregate command can return results as a cursor or store the results in a collection, which are not subject to the size limit."
    },
    {
        "id": 592,
        "Question": "The _____ JavaScript engine allows multiple JavaScript operations to execute at the same time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) V8",
            "b) V12",
            "c) V7",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: V8 JavaScript engine became the default engine in 2.4 version."
    },
    {
        "id": 593,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The read phase takes a exclusive lock",
            "b) The map-reduce operation is composed of many tasks",
            "c) Prior to version 3, JavaScript code executed in a single thread",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It includes reads from the input collection, executions of the map function, executions of the reduce function, writes to a temporary collection during processing, and writes to the output collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 594,
        "Question": "If the ______ field for mapReduce has the sharded value, MongoDB shards the output collection using the _id field as the shard key.",
        "Options": [
            "a) input",
            "b) $in",
            "c) $out",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: During the post-processing, each shard will pull the results for its own chunks from the other shards, run the final reduce/finalize, and write locally to the output collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 595,
        "Question": "In MongoDB __________ mongos retrieves the results from each shard, performs a merge sort to order the results.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.0",
            "b) 2.0",
            "c) 1.0",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This model requires only a small amount of memory, even for large data sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 596,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If the output collection does not exist, MongoDB creates and shards the collection on the _id field",
            "b) Map-reduce supports operations on sharded collections, both as an input and as an output",
            "c) mongos dispatches, in parallel, a map-reduce post-processing job to every shard that owns a chunk",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: When using sharded collection as the input for a map-reduce operation, mongos will automatically dispatch the map-reduce job to each shard in parallel."
    },
    {
        "id": 597,
        "Question": "Which of the following function follows the reduce method and modifies the output?",
        "Options": [
            "a) finalize",
            "b) final",
            "c) max",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Finalize fucntion is optional for mapreduce operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 598,
        "Question": "__________ specifies global variables that are accessible in the map.",
        "Options": [
            "a) jsMode",
            "b) scope",
            "c) finalize",
            "d) Min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It can also access reduce functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 599,
        "Question": "MongoDB converts the JavaScript objects emitted by the map function to ________ objects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BSON",
            "b) JSON",
            "c) Javascript",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: These BSON objects are then converted back to JavaScript objects when calling the reduce function."
    },
    {
        "id": 600,
        "Question": "You can only use jsMode for result sets with fewer than 500,000 distinct key arguments to the mapper’s _______ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) emit()",
            "b) emitter()",
            "c) emitted()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A single emit can only hold half of MongoDB’s maximum BSON document size."
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "Question": "Which of the following mode defaults to false?",
        "Options": [
            "a) jsMode",
            "b) scope",
            "c) finalize",
            "d) min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Internally, the JavaScript objects emitted during map function remain as JavaScript objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "Question": "$dayOfMonth returns the day of the month for a date as a number between ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 and 31",
            "b) 1 and 30",
            "c) 1 and 28",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The $dayOfMonth expression has the following syntax: { $dayOfMonth:  }."
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $second returns the seconds for a date as a number between 0 and 60 (leap seconds)",
            "b) $minute returns the minute for a date as a number between 0 and 59",
            "c) $millis returns the milliseconds of a date as a number between 0 and 1000",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $millisecond returns the milliseconds of a date as a number between 0 and 999."
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "Question": "__________ returns the day of the year for a date as a number between 1 and 366.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dayofWeekend",
            "b) $dayOfWeek",
            "c) $dayOfYear",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The $dayOfYear expression has the following syntax:{ $dayOfYear:  }."
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns year for particular date?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $year",
            "b) $yearday",
            "c) $syearofmonth",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: $year returns the year for a date as a number (e.g. 2014)."
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $weekDay returns the week number for a date as a number between 0 and 53 (leap year)",
            "b) $cond accepts either two expressions in an ordered list or three named parameters",
            "c) $toLower only has a well-defined behavior for strings of ASCII characters",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $cond is a ternary operator that evaluates one expression, and depending on the result, returns the value of one of the other two expressions."
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns the hour for a date as a number between 0 and 23?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $minute",
            "b) $hour",
            "c) $seconds",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The argument in hour statement can be any expression as long as it resolves to a date."
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "Question": "__________ returns the date as a formatted string.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $toString",
            "b) $dateToString",
            "c) $letString",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $dateToString converts a date object to a string according to a user-specified format."
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "Question": "_______ result encompasses instances of undefined values or missing fields.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number",
            "b) String",
            "c) Null",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Null value does not imply zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "Question": "___________ returns either the non-null result of the first expression.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $Null",
            "b) $ifNull",
            "c) $ElseNull",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:$ifNull returns the result of the second expression if the first expression results in a null result."
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "Question": "__________ take as input a single expression, evaluating the expression once for each input document, and maintain their state for the group of documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Computer",
            "b) Monitors",
            "c) Accumulators",
            "d) Performoner"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Accumulators are available only for the $group stage."
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "Question": "$sum is an accumulator operator available only in the _______ stage.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $group",
            "b) $sets",
            "c) $accumulator",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: $sum calculates and returns the sum of all the numeric values."
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $avg is an accumulator operator available only in the $group stage",
            "b) $sum accumulator can be used to compute the total amount and count for each group of documents",
            "c) $avg ignores numeric values",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $avg returns the average value of the numeric values that result from applying a specified expression to each document in a group of documents that share the same group by key."
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "Question": "Which of the following ignores non numeric values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $order",
            "b) $sum",
            "c) $asc",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $sum returns a sum for each group. Ignores non-numeric values."
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "Question": "When using $first in a $group stage, the $group stage should follow a _______ stage to have the input documents in a defined order.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $order",
            "b) $sort",
            "c) $asc",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $sort takes a document that specifies the field(s) to sort by and the respective sort order."
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns the value that results from applying an expression to the last document?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $end",
            "b) $last",
            "c) $max",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $last has the following syntax: { $last: <expression> }."
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "Question": "__________ returns the highest value from the group of values in documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $end",
            "b) $last",
            "c) $max",
            "d) $maximum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $max returns the highest value that results from applying an expression to each document in a group of documents that share the same group by key."
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "Question": "Which of the following is syntax for calculating minimum value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) { $minimum: <int> }",
            "b) { $min: <expression>}",
            "c) { $minimum: <expression> }",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $min returns the lowest value that results from applying an expression to each document in a group of documents that share the same group by key."
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "Question": "If all documents for the $min operation have null value for the field or are missing the field, the $min operator returns ____ for the minimum value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) null",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If some, but not all, documents for the $min operation have either a null value for the field or are missing the field, the $min operator only considers the non-null and the non-missing values for the field."
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "Question": "$addToSet returns an array of all _______ values that results from applying an expression to each document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) unique",
            "b) non unique",
            "c) distinct",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Order of the elements in the output array is unspecified."
    },
    {
        "id": 621,
        "Question": "__________ references the root document, i.e. the top-level document, currently being processed in the aggregation pipeline stage.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CURRENT",
            "b) ROOT",
            "c) PRUNE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: CURRENT is modifiable."
    },
    {
        "id": 622,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Variables can hold any BSON type data",
            "b) Aggregation expressions can use both user-defined and system variables",
            "c) To access the value of the variable, use a string with the variable name prefixed with double dollar signs ($$)",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If the variable references an object, to access a specific field in the object, use the dot notation; i.e. “$$<variable>.<field>”."
    },
    {
        "id": 623,
        "Question": "Which of the operator is similar to order by clause in RDBMS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $sort",
            "b) $match",
            "c) $sortby",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the mongo shell, when you assign the cursor returned from the find() method to a variable using the var keyword, the cursor does not automatically iterate."
    },
    {
        "id": 624,
        "Question": "Which of the following provides similar functionality to join?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $unwindelem",
            "b) $unwind",
            "c) $unwin",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $unwind operator allows for somewhat similar functionality like join, but with fields embedded within the document."
    },
    {
        "id": 625,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CURRENT references the start of the field path being processed in the aggregation pipeline stage",
            "b) All stages start with CURRENT the same as ROOT",
            "c) DESCENDING is one of the allowed results of a $let expression",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: However, since $<field> is equivalent to $$CURRENT.<field>, rebinding CURRENT changes the meaning of $ accesses."
    },
    {
        "id": 626,
        "Question": "________ limits the number of documents in result set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $project",
            "b) $geo",
            "c) $limit",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $limit takes a positive integer that specifies the maximum number of documents to pass along."
    },
    {
        "id": 627,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to retrieve like SELECT clause in SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $reduce",
            "b) $select",
            "c) $project",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The $project takes a document that can specify the inclusion of fields, the suppression of the _id field, the addition of new fields, and the resetting the values of existing fields."
    },
    {
        "id": 628,
        "Question": "_______ groups documents by some specified expression and outputs to the next stage a document for each distinct grouping.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setcon",
            "b) $group",
            "c) $match",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $group works similar to group by clause in SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 629,
        "Question": "____________ works similar to HAVING clause in SQL.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $setcon",
            "b) $group",
            "c) $match",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Place the $match as early in the aggregation pipeline as possible."
    },
    {
        "id": 630,
        "Question": "COUNT function is provided by _________ in MongoDB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $end",
            "b) $sum",
            "c) $max",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: $sum ignores non-numeric values just like SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 631,
        "Question": "MongoDB indexes use a _______ data structure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hash",
            "b) Map",
            "c) B-tree",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB provides a number of different index types to support specific types of data and queries."
    },
    {
        "id": 632,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If an appropriate index exists for a query, MongoDB cannot use the index to limit the number of documents it must inspect",
            "b) Indexes support the efficient execution of queries in MongoDB",
            "c) The index stores the location of a specific field or set of fields, ordered by the value of the field",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Without indexes, MongoDB must perform a collection scan."
    },
    {
        "id": 633,
        "Question": "MongoDB supports the creation of user-defined ascending/descending indexes on a ______ field of a document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Single",
            "b) Non Unique",
            "c) Compound",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If applications do not specify a value for _id the driver or the mongod will create an _id field with an ObjectId value."
    },
    {
        "id": 634,
        "Question": "The ______ index is unique and prevents clients from inserting two documents with the same value for the _id field.",
        "Options": [
            "a) _id",
            "b) $default",
            "c) _def",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: All MongoDB collections have an index on the _id field that exists by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 635,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB can return sorted results by using the ordering in the index",
            "b) MongoDB defines indexes at the collection level and supports indexes on any field or sub-field of the documents in a MongoDB collection",
            "c) Fundamentally, indexes in MongoDB is different to indexes in other database systems",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Indexes are special data structures that store a small portion of the collection’s data set in an easy to traverse form. "
    },
    {
        "id": 636,
        "Question": "MongoDB also supports user-defined indexes on multiple fields called ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) compound",
            "b) composite",
            "c) candidate",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The order of fields listed in a compound index has significance."
    },
    {
        "id": 637,
        "Question": "MongoDB uses ______ indexes to index the content stored in arrays.",
        "Options": [
            "a) singlekey",
            "b) multikey",
            "c) compkey",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If you index a field that holds an array value, MongoDB creates separate index entries for every element of the array."
    },
    {
        "id": 638,
        "Question": "___________ indexes use spherical geometry to return results.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3dsphere",
            "b) 2dsphere",
            "c) 1dsphere",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To support efficient queries of geospatial coordinate data, MongoDB provides two special indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 639,
        "Question": "MongoDB provides a ________ index type that supports searching for string content in a collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) string",
            "b) text",
            "c) char",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: These text indexes do not store language-specific stop words (e.g. “the”, “a”, “or”) and stem the words in a collection to only store root words."
    },
    {
        "id": 640,
        "Question": "_____ indexes uses planar geometry when returning results.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2d",
            "b) 1d",
            "c) 3d",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  MongoDB computes geohash values for the coordinate pairs within the specified location range and then indexes the geohash values."
    },
    {
        "id": 641,
        "Question": "To support ________ based sharding, MongoDB provides a hashed index type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) root",
            "c) hash",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: These indexes have a more random distribution of values along their range, but only support equality matches and cannot support range-based queries."
    },
    {
        "id": 642,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Whether the use of a compound index or the use of an index intersection is more efficient depends on the particular query and the system",
            "b) Certain restrictions apply to indexes, such as the length of the index keys or the number of indexes per collection",
            "c) For queries that specify compound query conditions, if one index can fulfill a part of a query condition, and another index can fulfill another part of the query condition, then MongoDB can use the intersection of the two indexes to fulfill the query",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In general, each index intersection involves two indexes; however, MongoDB can employ multiple/nested index intersections to resolve a query."
    },
    {
        "id": 643,
        "Question": "________ index type, which indexes the hash of the value of a field.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Multikey",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Hashed indexes support equality matches and cannot support range-based queries."
    },
    {
        "id": 644,
        "Question": "The _________ property for an index causes MongoDB to reject duplicate values for the indexed field.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Multikey",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Other than the unique constraint, unique indexes are functionally interchangeable with other MongoDB indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 645,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) TTL index is ideal for certain types of information like machine generated event data, logs, and session information that only need to persist in a database for a finite amount of time",
            "b) You cannot combine the sparse index option with the unique index option",
            "c) TTL indexes are special indexes that MongoDB can use to automatically remove documents from a collection after a certain amount of time",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can combine to reject documents that have duplicate values for a field but ignore documents that do not have the indexed key."
    },
    {
        "id": 646,
        "Question": "The ______ property of an index ensures that the index only contain entries for documents that have the indexed field.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Sparse",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The index skips documents that do not have the indexed field."
    },
    {
        "id": 647,
        "Question": "MongoDB can use the _________ of indexes to fulfill queries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) union",
            "b) intersection",
            "c) projection",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The $project takes a document that can specify the inclusion of fields, the suppression of the _id field, the addition of new fields, and the resetting the values of existing fields."
    },
    {
        "id": 648,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is to verify whether MongoDB used index intersection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) explain()",
            "b) analyze()",
            "c) intersect()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To determine if MongoDB used index intersection, run explain(); the results of explain() will include either an AND_SORTED stage or an AND_HASH stage."
    },
    {
        "id": 649,
        "Question": "An index prefix is a subset of a ______ index, consisting of one or more keys starting from the beginning of the index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Sparse",
            "d) Compound"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: With index intersection, MongoDB can use an intersection of either the entire index or the index prefix."
    },
    {
        "id": 650,
        "Question": "Index __________ does not eliminate the need for creating compound indexes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) union",
            "b) addition",
            "c) intersection",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Compound index may not support a query condition that does not include the index prefix keys or that specifies a different sort order."
    },
    {
        "id": 651,
        "Question": "Before version _______ capped collections did not have an _id field.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.1",
            "b) 2.4",
            "c) 3.0",
            "d) 2.2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In version 2.2 and newer, capped collections do have an _id field, except those in the local database."
    },
    {
        "id": 652,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can create indexes on fields within embedded documents",
            "b) Indexes on embedded fields are similar to indexes on embedded documents",
            "c) Indexes on embedded fields allow you to use a “dot notation,” to introspect into embedded documents",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Indexes on embedded fields differ from indexes on embedded documents, which include the full content up to the maximum index size of the embedded document in the index. "
    },
    {
        "id": 653,
        "Question": "For a _____ multikey index, each indexed document can have at most one indexed field whose value is an array.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Multikey",
            "d) compound"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: As such, you cannot create a compound multikey index if more than one to-be-indexed field of a document is an array."
    },
    {
        "id": 654,
        "Question": "Which of the following indexes cannot be multikey?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Multikey",
            "d) compound"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You cannot specify a multikey index as the shard key index."
    },
    {
        "id": 655,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You may not create compound indexes that have hashed index fields",
            "b) The order of the fields in a compound index is very important",
            "c) You will receive a warning if you attempt to create a compound index that includes a hashed index",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You will receive an error if you attempt to create a compound index that includes a hashed index."
    },
    {
        "id": 656,
        "Question": "To calculate geometry over an Earth-like sphere, store your location data on a spherical surface and use _____ index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2dsphere",
            "b) 2d",
            "c) geoHaystack",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Secondary members replicate deletion operations from the primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 657,
        "Question": "______ indexes can be constructed over arrays that hold both scalar values (e.g. strings, numbers) and nested documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Multikey",
            "d) Compound"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Store your location data as GeoJSON objects with this coordinate-axis order: longitude, latitude."
    },
    {
        "id": 658,
        "Question": "The coordinate reference system for GeoJSON uses the _____ datum.",
        "Options": [
            "a) WGS88",
            "b) WGS84",
            "c) JGS88",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Before storing your location data and writing queries, you must decide the type of surface to use to perform calculations."
    },
    {
        "id": 659,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to calculate distances on a Euclidean plane?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2dsph",
            "b) 2d",
            "c) geoHaystack",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Store your location data as legacy coordinate pairs "
    },
    {
        "id": 660,
        "Question": "Queries on ________ objects always calculate on a sphere.",
        "Options": [
            "a) GeoBSON",
            "b) GeoJSON",
            "c) geoJSONB",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Support for GeoJSON storage and queries is new in version 2.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 661,
        "Question": "Which of the following GeoJSON object is not supported in MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Point",
            "b) LineString",
            "c) MultiPoint",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In version 2.2 and newer, capped collections do have an _id field, except those in the local database."
    },
    {
        "id": 662,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB can query for locations contained entirely within a specified polygon",
            "b) MongoDB require an index for inclusion queries; however, such indexes will improve query performance",
            "c) Indexes on embedded fields allow you to use a “dot notation,” to introspect into embedded documents",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Both 2d and 2dsphere indexes can support inclusion queries."
    },
    {
        "id": 663,
        "Question": "MongoDB supports spherical surface calculations on legacy coordinate pairs using a _______ index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2dsphere",
            "b) 2d",
            "c) geoHaystack",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If you choose flat surface calculations via a 2d index, you can store data only as legacy coordinate pairs."
    },
    {
        "id": 664,
        "Question": "Inclusion queries use the _________ operator in MongoDB.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $geokey",
            "b) $geoin",
            "c) $geoWithin",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $geoWithin selects documents with geospatial data that exists entirely within a specified shape."
    },
    {
        "id": 665,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) For $geoSphere queries that specify GeoJSON geometries with areas greater than a single hemisphere, the use of the default CRS results in queries for the complementary geometries",
            "b) When determining inclusion, MongoDB considers the border of a shape to be part of the shape, subject to the precision of floating point numbers",
            "c) The custom MongoDB CRS uses a anti-clockwise winding order",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The specified shape can be either a GeoJSON Polygon, a GeoJSON MultiPolygon, or a shape defined by legacy coordinate pairs. "
    },
    {
        "id": 666,
        "Question": "The $geoWithin operator uses the _______ operator to specify the GeoJSON object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $sphere",
            "b) $geoin",
            "c) $geometry",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For $geoWithin, if you specify a single-ringed polygon that has an area greater than a single hemisphere, include the custom MongoDB coordinate reference system in the $geometry expression."
    },
    {
        "id": 667,
        "Question": "If the specified polygon is _______ than a single hemisphere, the behavior of $geoWithin with the MongoDB CRS is the same as with the default CRS.",
        "Options": [
            "a) smaller",
            "b) bigger",
            "c) equal",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  For all other GeoJSON polygons with areas greater than a hemisphere, $geoWithin queries for the complementary geometry."
    },
    {
        "id": 668,
        "Question": "To query with a single-ringed GeoJSON polygon whose area is greater than a single hemisphere, the $geometry expression must specify the custom MongoDB ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CRS",
            "b) CDS",
            "c) CLS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CRS stands for coordinate reference system."
    },
    {
        "id": 669,
        "Question": "$geoWithin replaces _______ in MongoDB 2.4.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $withing",
            "b) $gwithin",
            "c) $within",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: $within is deprecated since version 2.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 670,
        "Question": "When used with the _____ operator, $geoWithin returns documents based on grid coordinates and does not query for GeoJSON shapes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $box",
            "b) $circle",
            "c) $shape",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: $box specifies a rectangle for a geospatial $geoWithin query to return documents that are within the bounds of the rectangle, according to their point-based location data."
    },
    {
        "id": 671,
        "Question": "________ indexes expire documents after the specified number of seconds has passed since the indexed field value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Multikey",
            "d) TTL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The expiration threshold is the indexed field value plus the specified number of seconds."
    },
    {
        "id": 672,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If you build a TTL index in the foreground, MongoDB does not remove expired documents as soon as the index finishes building",
            "b) The TTL index does guarantee that expired data will be deleted immediately upon expiration",
            "c) Duration of the removal operation depends on the workload of your mongod instance",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: There may be a delay between the time a document expires and the time that MongoDB removes the document from the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 673,
        "Question": "When the TTL thread is active, you will see _______ operations in the output of db.currentOp().",
        "Options": [
            "a) delete",
            "b) update",
            "c) insert",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A background thread in mongod reads the values in the index and removes expired documents from the collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 674,
        "Question": "The background task that removes expired documents runs every ________ seconds.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15",
            "b) 45",
            "c) 60",
            "d) 120"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: As a result, documents may remain in a collection during the period between the expiration of the document and the running of the background task."
    },
    {
        "id": 675,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The unique constraint applies to separate documents in the collection",
            "b) Unique index prevents separate documents from having the same value for the indexed key",
            "c) Index does prevent a document from having multiple elements or embedded documents in an indexed array from having the same value",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the case of a single document with repeating values, the repeated value is inserted into the index only once."
    },
    {
        "id": 676,
        "Question": "On replica sets, the TTL background thread only deletes documents on _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) upadte",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Secondary members replicate deletion operations from the primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 677,
        "Question": "You can combine the ________ constraint with the sparse index to filter these null values from the unique index and avoid the error.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Sparse",
            "d) Compound"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If a document does not have a value for the indexed field in a unique index, the index will store a null value for this document."
    },
    {
        "id": 678,
        "Question": "You may not specify a unique constraint on a ______ index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed",
            "b) Unique",
            "c) Sparse",
            "d) Compound"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Because of the unique constraint, MongoDB will only permit one document that lacks the indexed field."
    },
    {
        "id": 679,
        "Question": "Which of the following indexes are always sparse?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2dsphere",
            "b) 2d",
            "c) geoHaystack",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 2dsphere (version 2), 2d, geoHaystack, and text indexes are always sparse."
    },
    {
        "id": 680,
        "Question": "To modify an existing index, you cannot just re-issue the _________ method with the updated specification of the index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dropIndex()",
            "b) modIndex()",
            "c) createIndex()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To modify the index, you must drop the index first."
    },
    {
        "id": 681,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To modify an existing index, you need to drop and recreate the index",
            "b) Your client library may have a different or additional interface for this operation",
            "c) To see the status of an indexing process, you can use the db.statusOp() method in the mongo shell",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To see the status of an indexing process, you can use the db.currentOp() method in the mongo shell. "
    },
    {
        "id": 682,
        "Question": "If you need to rebuild indexes for a collection you can use the _________ method to rebuild all indexes on a collection in a single operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.collection.Index()",
            "b) db.collection.reIndex()",
            "c) db.collection.rebuildIndex()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This operation drops all indexes, including the _id index, and then rebuilds all indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 683,
        "Question": "To terminate an ongoing index build, use the __________ method in the mongo shell.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.currentOp()",
            "b) db.killOp()",
            "c) db.removeOp()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For index builds, the effects of db.killOp() may not be immediate and may occur well after much of the index build operation has completed."
    },
    {
        "id": 684,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) After 4.0, you cannot terminate both background index builds and foreground index builds",
            "b) Before MongoDB 2.1, you could only terminate background index builds",
            "c) After 2.4, you can terminate both background index builds and foreground index builds",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You cannot terminate a replicated index build on secondary members of a replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 685,
        "Question": "In the mongo shell, you can use the ______ method to return a list of the indexes on a collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) getallIndexes()",
            "b) getretIndexes()",
            "c) getIndexes()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When performing maintenance you may want to check which indexes exist on a collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 686,
        "Question": "__________ views partial execution statistics collected during plan selection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) curs.explain()",
            "b) cursor.explain()",
            "c) cursr.explain()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Run db.collection.explain() or the cursor.explain() method in allPlansExecution mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 687,
        "Question": "The __________ operator constrains the results of a geospatial $near or $nearSphere query to the specified distance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $center",
            "b) $maxDistance",
            "c) $minDistance",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The measuring units for the maximum distance are determined by the coordinate system in use."
    },
    {
        "id": 688,
        "Question": "To force MongoDB to use a particular index for a db.collection.________ operation, specify the index with the hint() method.",
        "Options": [
            "a) query()",
            "b) find()",
            "c) index()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Append the hint() method to the find() method."
    },
    {
        "id": 689,
        "Question": "Specify the ______ operator to the hint() method to prevent MongoDB from using any index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $unique",
            "b) $natural",
            "c) $spatial",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To view the execution statistics for a specific index, append to the db.collection.find() the hint() method followed by cursor.explain()."
    },
    {
        "id": 690,
        "Question": "___________ selects geometries that intersect with a GeoJSON geometry.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $near",
            "b) $nearsphere",
            "c) $geoIntersect",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The 2dsphere index supports $geoIntersects."
    },
    {
        "id": 691,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If $near or $nearSphere query specifies the center point as a GeoJSON point, specify the distance as a non-negative number in meters",
            "b) If $nearSphere query specifies the center point as legacy coordinate pair, specify the distance as a non-negative number in radians",
            "c) $near can only use the 2dsphere index if the query specifies the center point as a GeoJSON point",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:$minDistance filters the results of a geospatial $near or $nearSphere query to those documents that are at least the specified distance from the center point."
    },
    {
        "id": 692,
        "Question": "_______ returns geospatial objects in proximity to a point.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $near",
            "b) $nearsphere",
            "c) $geoIntersect",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:$near requires a geospatial index."
    },
    {
        "id": 693,
        "Question": "_________ specifies a geometry in GeoJSON format to geospatial query operators.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $sphere",
            "b) $geoin",
            "c) $geometry",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:$geometry uses EPSG:4326 as the default coordinate reference system (CRS)."
    },
    {
        "id": 694,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Both 2dsphere and 2d geospatial indexes support $geoWithin",
            "b) $geoWithin does not require a geospatial index",
            "c) The $geoWithin operator does not return sorted results",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: However, a geospatial index will improve query performance."
    },
    {
        "id": 695,
        "Question": "_________ returns geospatial objects in proximity to a point on a sphere. Requires a geospatial index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $near",
            "b) $nearsphere",
            "c) $geoIntersect",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The 2dsphere and 2d indexes support $nearSphere."
    },
    {
        "id": 696,
        "Question": "__________ specifies a minimum distance to limit the results of $near and $nearSphere queries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $center",
            "b) $maxDistance",
            "c) $minDistance",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:$minDistance is available for use with 2dsphere index only."
    },
    {
        "id": 697,
        "Question": "The _________ operator specifies a circle for a $geoWithin query.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $within",
            "b) $gwithin",
            "c) $center",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The query returns legacy coordinate pairs that are within the bounds of the circle."
    },
    {
        "id": 698,
        "Question": "________ index must exist on a field holding coordinates before using any of the geospatial query operators.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Unique",
            "b) Geospatial",
            "c) Temporal",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Only the 2d geospatial index supports $center."
    },
    {
        "id": 699,
        "Question": "When creating a text index on multiple fields, you can specify the individual fields or you can use wildcard specifier ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) ($*)",
            "b) (**$**)",
            "c) ($**)",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can create a text index on the field or fields whose value is a string or an array of string elements."
    },
    {
        "id": 700,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In order to drop a text index, use the index name",
            "b) The default language associated with the indexed data determines the rules to parse word roots and ignore stop words",
            "c) To allow for text search on all fields with string content, use the wildcard specifier ($$$) to index all fields that contain string content",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the aggregation pipeline, text search is available via the use of the $text query operator in the $match stage."
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "Question": "The default language for the indexed data is ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) chinese",
            "b) english",
            "c) spanish",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To specify a different language, use the default_language option when creating the text index."
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "Question": "If a collection contains documents or embedded documents that are in different languages, include a field named _______ in the documents.",
        "Options": [
            "a) operator",
            "b) lang",
            "c) language",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB will use the specified language for that document or embedded document when building the text index."
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) After 2.4, you can terminate both background index builds and foreground index builds",
            "b) The specified language in the document overrides the default language for the text index",
            "c) The text index, like other indexes, should not fall within the index name length limit",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To get the names of the indexes, use the db.collection.getIndexes() method."
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "Question": "To use a field with a name other than language, include the ________ option when creating the index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) language_over",
            "b) language_override",
            "c) langoverride",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You cannot combine the $text query, which requires a special text index, with a query operator that requires a different type of special index. "
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "Question": "The default name for the index consists of each indexed field name concatenated with _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) _char",
            "b) _textc",
            "c) _text",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Whether the text index has the default name or you specified a name for the text index, to drop the text index, pass the index name to the db.collection.dropIndex() method."
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "Question": "To avoid creating an index with a name that exceeds the index name length limit, you can pass the _____ option to the db.collection.createIndex() method.",
        "Options": [
            "a) name",
            "b) lang",
            "c) number",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The measuring units for the maximum distance are determined by the coordinate system in use."
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "Question": "The default weight is ____ for the indexed fields.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To adjust the weights for the indexed fields, include the weights option in the db.collection.createIndex() method."
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "Question": "For a ______ index, the weight of an indexed field denotes the significance of the field relative to the other indexed fields in terms of the score.",
        "Options": [
            "a) unique",
            "b) natural",
            "c) text",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the compound text index includes keys preceding the text index key, to perform a $text search, the query predicate must include equality match conditions on the preceding keys."
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "Question": "_________ operations that use an index often have better performance than those that do not use an index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Select",
            "b) Update",
            "c) Delete",
            "d) Sort"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MongoDB, sort operations can obtain the sort order by retrieving documents based on the ordering in an index."
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The query scans the index and the collection",
            "b) An index supports a query when the index contains all the fields scanned by the query",
            "c) Creating indexes that support queries results in greatly increased query performance",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The query scans the index and not the collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "Question": "A prefix of a _______ index is a subset that consists of one or more keys at the start of the index key pattern.",
        "Options": [
            "a) unique",
            "b) primary",
            "c) compound",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the sort keys correspond to the index keys or an index prefix, MongoDB can use the index to sort the query results."
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "Question": "Sort operations that do not use an index will abort when they use _______ megabytes of memory.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16",
            "b) 32",
            "c) 64",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the query planner cannot obtain the sort order from an index, it will sort the results in memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If you only ever query on a single key in a given collection, then you need to create just multikey index for that collection",
            "b) If you sometimes query on only one key and at other times query on that key combined with a second key, then creating a compound index is more efficient than creating a single-key index",
            "c) The choice between creating compound indexes that support your queries or relying on index intersection is independent of specifics of your system",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB will use the compound index for both queries."
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "Question": "An index can support sort operations on a non-prefix subset of the index key pattern using _________ condition.",
        "Options": [
            "a) predicate",
            "b) selection",
            "c) equality",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Query must include equality conditions on all the prefix keys that precede the sort keys."
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "Question": "__________ method provides a wrapper around the totalIndexSize output of the collStats (i.e. db.collection.stats()) operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.collection.totalallIndexSize()",
            "b) db.collection.totalIndexSizeAll()",
            "c) db.collection.totalIndexSize()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To check the size of your indexes, use the db.collection.totalIndexSize() helper, which returns data in bytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "Question": "Indexes do not have to fit entirely into ______ in all cases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ROM",
            "b) RAM",
            "c) Secondary Storage",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are some limited cases where indexes do not need to fit in memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "Question": "________ is the ability of a query to narrow results using the index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Causality",
            "b) Cardinality",
            "c) Selectivity",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Effective indexes are more selective and allow MongoDB to use the index for a larger portion of the work associated with fulfilling the query."
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "Question": "__________ query calculates distances using flat (planar) geometry.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $center",
            "b) $centre",
            "c) $radii",
            "d) Sort"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MongoDB, sort operations can obtain the sort order by retrieving documents based on the ordering in an index."
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The query scans the index and not the collection",
            "b) If overall selectivity is high, and if MongoDB must read a number of documents to return results, then some queries may perform faster without indexes",
            "c) A better strategy, depending on your queries, would be to create a compound index that includes the high-selectivity field and another field",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To ensure selectivity, write queries that limit the number of possible documents with the indexed field. Write queries that are appropriately selective relative to your indexed data."
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "Question": "_________ defines a circle for a geospatial query that uses spherical geometry.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $center",
            "b) $centre",
            "c) $radii",
            "d) $centersphere"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: You can use the $centerSphere operator on both GeoJSON objects and legacy coordinate pairs."
    },
    {
        "id": 721,
        "Question": "When used with the $box operator, _________ returns documents based on grid coordinates and does not query for GeoJSON shapes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $geoNear",
            "b) $geoWithin",
            "c) $geoRear",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To use the $box operator, you must specify the bottom left and top right corners of the rectangle in an array object."
    },
    {
        "id": 722,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Applications can use $center without having a geospatial index",
            "b) Before 3.0, a geospatial index must exist on a field holding coordinates before using any of the geospatial query operators",
            "c) To use $centerSphere, specify an array that contains grid coordinates of the circle’s center point",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: However, geospatial indexes support much faster queries than the unindexed equivalents."
    },
    {
        "id": 723,
        "Question": "Applications can use _________ without having a geospatial index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $center",
            "b) $centre",
            "c) $radii",
            "d) $centersphere"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The query returns documents that are within the bounds of the circle."
    },
    {
        "id": 724,
        "Question": "_________ specifies a polygon for a geospatial $geoWithin query on legacy coordinate pairs.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rect",
            "b) $polygon",
            "c) $poly",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To define the polygon, specify an array of coordinate points."
    },
    {
        "id": 725,
        "Question": "Only the ______ geospatial index supports the $polygon operator.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1dsphere",
            "b) 2d",
            "c) 3d",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The $polygon operator calculates distances using flat (planar) geometry."
    },
    {
        "id": 726,
        "Question": "________ returns a document only once for a geospatial query even if the document matches the query multiple times.",
        "Options": [
            "a) $uniqueDocs",
            "b) $unique",
            "c) $Docs",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Geospatial queries no longer return duplicate results. "
    },
    {
        "id": 727,
        "Question": "A _______ set is a group of mongod instances that host the same data set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) copy",
            "b) sorted",
            "c) radii",
            "d) replica"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  One mongod, the primary, receives all write operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 728,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Replication provides redundancy and increases data availability",
            "b) Replication allows you to recover from hardware failure and service interruptions",
            "c) With multiple copies of data on different database servers, replication protects a database from the loss of a single server",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: With additional copies of the data, you can dedicate one to disaster recovery, reporting, or backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 729,
        "Question": "All other instances, secondaries, apply operations from the _________ so that they have the same data set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) center",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) primary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The primary accepts all write operations from clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 730,
        "Question": "A replica set can have only ________ primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) One",
            "b) Two",
            "c) Three",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The secondaries replicate the primary’s oplog and apply the operations to their data sets such that the secondaries’ data sets reflect the primary’s data set."
    },
    {
        "id": 731,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In all cases, you can use replication to increase read capacity",
            "b) Clients have the ability to send read and write operations to different servers",
            "c) You can also maintain copies in different data centers to increase the locality and availability of data for distributed applications",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In some cases, you can use replication to increase read capacity."
    },
    {
        "id": 732,
        "Question": "To support replication, the primary records all changes to its data sets in its _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) oplog",
            "b) adlog",
            "c) log",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the primary is unavailable, the replica set will elect a secondary to be primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 733,
        "Question": "You may add an extra mongod instance to a replica set as an __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) arbiter",
            "b) replicator",
            "c) additor",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Arbiters do not maintain a data set. "
    },
    {
        "id": 734,
        "Question": "An arbiter will always be an arbiter whereas a primary may step down and become a secondary and a _________ may become the primary during an election.",
        "Options": [
            "a) center",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) primary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  If your replica set has an even number of members, add an arbiter to obtain a majority of votes in an election for primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 735,
        "Question": "When a primary does not communicate with the other members of the set for more than ____ seconds, the replica set will attempt to select another member to become the new primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 20",
            "c) 30",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The first secondary that receives a majority of the votes becomes primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 736,
        "Question": "When a replica set has one and only one primary, reads from that primary provide ______ consistency.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strict",
            "b) partial",
            "c) weak",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Arbiters can be a good way to provide replica set quorum functionality with a cheaper resource cost than a fully functional replica set member with a data set."
    },
    {
        "id": 737,
        "Question": "How many types of members exist in replica set?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are two members in replica set-primary and secondary."
    },
    {
        "id": 738,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Replication provides scalability and increases data redundancy",
            "b) A replica set in MongoDB is a group of mongod processes that provide redundancy and high availability",
            "c) You can also maintain an arbiter as part of a replica set",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Data redundancy is reduced by replicating the copies of data."
    },
    {
        "id": 739,
        "Question": "Which of the member receives all write operations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) center",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) primary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The primary accepts all write operations from clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 740,
        "Question": "_________ replicate operations from the primary to maintain an identical data set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) center",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) primary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Secondaries may have additional configurations for special usage profiles."
    },
    {
        "id": 741,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The minimum requirements for a replica set are: A primary, a secondary, and an arbiter",
            "b) The primary is the only member in the replica set that receives write operations",
            "c) Most deployments, however, will keep three members that store data: A primary and two secondary members",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Secondary members replicate this oplog and apply the operations to their data sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 742,
        "Question": "_________ play a role in the elections that select a primary if the current primary is unavailable.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Arbiters",
            "b) Replicators",
            "c) Loggers",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Arbiters do not keep a copy of the data. "
    },
    {
        "id": 743,
        "Question": "A replica set can have up to ______ members but only 7 voting members.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 30",
            "c) 50",
            "d) 70"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  In previous versions, replica sets can have up to 12 members."
    },
    {
        "id": 744,
        "Question": "Which of the following may be non-voting or priority 0?",
        "Options": [
            "a) center",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) primary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: All members of the replica set can accept read operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 745,
        "Question": "If the current primary becomes unavailable, the replica set holds an ______ to choose which of the secondaries becomes the new primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) election",
            "b) replication",
            "c) clasification",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A secondary can become a primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 746,
        "Question": "By default, an application directs its ____ operations to the primary member.",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) read write",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A replica set can have one or more secondaries."
    },
    {
        "id": 747,
        "Question": "The architecture of a replica set affects the set’s _________ and capability.",
        "Options": [
            "a) scalability",
            "b) capacity",
            "c) performance",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Replica sets provide redundancy and fault tolerance."
    },
    {
        "id": 748,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Even number of members ensures that the replica set is always able to elect a primary",
            "b) Arbiters do not store a copy of the data and require fewer resources",
            "c) You may run an arbiter on an application server or other shared process",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If you have an even number of members, add an arbiter to get an odd number."
    },
    {
        "id": 749,
        "Question": "The standard replica set deployment for production system is a ___-member replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) two",
            "b) three",
            "c) four",
            "d) five"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Avoid complexity when possible, but let your application requirements dictate the architecture."
    },
    {
        "id": 750,
        "Question": "_________ for a replica set is the number of members that can become unavailable and still leave enough members in the set to elect a primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fault tolerance",
            "b) Reliability",
            "c) Security",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In other words, it is the difference between the number of members in the set and the majority needed to elect a primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 751,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Removing a member to the replica set does not always increase the fault tolerance",
            "b) The secondary is the only member in the replica set that receives write operations",
            "c) Fault tolerance is an effect of replica set size, but the relationship is not direct",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Additional members can provide support for dedicated functions, such as backups or reporting."
    },
    {
        "id": 752,
        "Question": "Without a primary, a replica set cannot accept ________ operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) read write",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Arbiters do not keep a copy of the data. "
    },
    {
        "id": 753,
        "Question": "_________ member is used to support dedicated functions, such as backup or reporting.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hidden",
            "b) Primary",
            "c) ViewState",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Delayed members can also support dedicated functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 754,
        "Question": "To protect your data if your main data center fails, keep at least _______ member in an alternate data center.",
        "Options": [
            "a) one",
            "b) two",
            "c) three",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Always add new members before the current demand saturates the capacity of the set."
    },
    {
        "id": 755,
        "Question": "What should be the priority of member to prevent them from becoming primary?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Always ensure that the main facility is able to elect a primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 756,
        "Question": "_________ sets also allow the routing of read operations to specific machines.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Field",
            "b) Read",
            "c) Tag",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Use replica set tag sets to ensure that operations replicate to specific data centers."
    },
    {
        "id": 757,
        "Question": "Replica sets provide high availability using automatic ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) failover",
            "b) replication",
            "c) failure",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Failover, in most situations does not require manual intervention."
    },
    {
        "id": 758,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When the primary rejoins the set as a secondary, it reverts, or “rolls back,” its write operations to maintain database consistency with the other members",
            "b) A rollback is necessary only if the primary had accepted write operations that the secondaries had not successfully replicated before the primary stepped down",
            "c) MongoDB attempts for rollbacks, which should be rare",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When a rollback does occur, it is often the result of a network partition."
    },
    {
        "id": 759,
        "Question": "Failover allows a ________ member to become primary if primary is unavailable.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hidden",
            "b) Primary",
            "c) ViewState",
            "d) Secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Replica set members keep the same data set but are otherwise independent."
    },
    {
        "id": 760,
        "Question": "Sometimes the failover process may require a ____________ during operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) savepoint",
            "b) rollback",
            "c) commit",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A rollback reverts write operations on a former primary when the member rejoins its replica set after a failover."
    },
    {
        "id": 761,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A rollback does not occur if the write operations replicate to another member of the replica set before the primary steps down",
            "b) Secondaries that can not keep up with the throughput of operations on the former primary, decrease the size and impact of the rollback",
            "c) Fault tolerance is an effect of replica set size, but the relationship is not direct",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When a rollback does occur, administrators must decide whether to apply or ignore the rollback data."
    },
    {
        "id": 762,
        "Question": "MongoDB writes the rollback data to BSON files in the rollback/ folder under the database’s ________ directory.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbPath",
            "b) logPath",
            "c) dataPath",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The storage.dbPath setting is available only for mongod."
    },
    {
        "id": 763,
        "Question": "The names of rollback files have the following form.",
        "Options": [
            "a) <database>.<collection>.<timestamp>.bson.",
            "b) <database>.<collection>.<tp>.bson.",
            "c) <database>.<collection>.<timestamp>.json.",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Administrators must apply rollback data manually after the member completes the rollback and returns to secondary status."
    },
    {
        "id": 764,
        "Question": "_________ is used to read the contents of the rollback files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bsondumpdata",
            "b) bsondp",
            "c) bsondump",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The bsondump converts BSON files into human-readable formats, including JSON."
    },
    {
        "id": 765,
        "Question": "Use ______ to apply the changes to the new primary after rollback.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongostore",
            "b) mongorestore",
            "c) restore",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mongorestore program writes data from a binary database dump created by mongodump to a MongoDB instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 766,
        "Question": "mongorestore recreates indexes recorded by _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) bsondump",
            "b) mongodump",
            "c) mongostore",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The data format used by mongodump from version 2.2 or later is incompatible with earlier versions of mongod. "
    },
    {
        "id": 767,
        "Question": "The __________ of a replica set affects the outcome of failover situations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) deployment",
            "b) architecture",
            "c) structure",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To support effective failover, ensure that one facility can elect a primary if needed."
    },
    {
        "id": 768,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Administrators must apply or discard rollback data manually",
            "b) Network partitions could not prevent the set from being able to form a majority",
            "c) Replica sets remove “rollback” data when needed without intervention",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a rollback does occur, it is often the result of a network partition."
    },
    {
        "id": 769,
        "Question": "A rollback reverts _______ operations on a former primary when the member rejoins the replica set after a failover.",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) view",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The replica set recovers from the loss of a primary by holding an election."
    },
    {
        "id": 770,
        "Question": "A priority __ member is a secondary that cannot become primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Priority 0 members cannot trigger elections."
    },
    {
        "id": 771,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Elections does not occur when the primary becomes unavailable and the replica set members autonomously select a new primary",
            "b) A priority 1 member maintains a copy of the data set, accepts read operations, and votes in elections",
            "c) In a two-member replica set, in one data center hosts the primary and a secondary.",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Configure a priority 0 member to prevent secondaries from becoming primary, which is particularly useful in multi-data center deployments."
    },
    {
        "id": 772,
        "Question": "A second data center hosts one priority 0 member that cannot become ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) write",
            "c) view",
            "d) Secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A priority 0 member can function as a standby."
    },
    {
        "id": 773,
        "Question": "A ______ member maintains a copy of the primary’s data set but is invisible to client applications.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) delayed",
            "c) hidden",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Hidden members are good for workloads with different usage patterns from the other members in the replica set. "
    },
    {
        "id": 774,
        "Question": "The db.________ method does not display hidden members.",
        "Options": [
            "a) isPrima ry()",
            "b) isMaster()",
            "c) Master()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hidden members, however, may vote in elections."
    },
    {
        "id": 775,
        "Question": "In a sharded cluster _______ do not interact with hidden members.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongos",
            "c) mongostore",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Clients will not distribute reads with the appropriate read preference to hidden members."
    },
    {
        "id": 776,
        "Question": "Which of the following members should be hidden?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Delayed",
            "b) Hidden",
            "c) Primary",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use hidden members for dedicated tasks such as reporting and backups."
    },
    {
        "id": 777,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Clients will not distribute reads with the appropriate read preference to hidden members",
            "b) Hidden members cannot vote in replica set elections",
            "c) If you stop a voting hidden member, ensure that the set has an active majority or the primary will step down",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hidden members may vote in replica set elections"
    },
    {
        "id": 778,
        "Question": "__________ operations cannot guarantee that the data files do not change.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.lockl()",
            "b) db.synclock()",
            "c) db.fsyncUnlock()",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: As a result, do not use these methods to ensure consistency for the purposes of creating backups."
    },
    {
        "id": 779,
        "Question": "_______ may block reads, including those necessary to verify authentication.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.lockall()",
            "b) db.fsyncLock()",
            "c) db,lockreads()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Such reads are necessary to establish new connections to a mongod that enforces authorization checks."
    },
    {
        "id": 780,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In MongoDB, clients cannot see the results of writes before they are made durable",
            "b) Users may configure read preference on a per-connection basis to prefer that the read operations return results from the secondary members",
            "c) Clients cannot read data which may be subsequently rolled back",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If clients configure the read preference to permit secondary reads, read operations can return data from secondary members that have not replicated more recent write operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 781,
        "Question": "________ unlocks a mongod instance to allow writes and reverses the operation of a db.fsyncLock() operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.fsyncUnlock()",
            "b) db.fsynclock()",
            "c) db.syncUnlock()",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Typically you will use db.fsyncUnlock() following a database backup operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 782,
        "Question": "Delayed members are a ________ or a running “historical” snapshot of the data set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) “rolling backup”",
            "b) “roll backup”",
            "c) “rolling commit”",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: They may help you recover from various kinds of human error."
    },
    {
        "id": 783,
        "Question": "Delayed members apply operations from the _______ on a delay.",
        "Options": [
            "a) oplog",
            "b) log",
            "c) mlog",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Always prevent applications from seeing and querying delayed members."
    },
    {
        "id": 784,
        "Question": "In sharded clusters, delayed members have limited utility when the __________ is enabled.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Balancer",
            "b) Collector",
            "c) Emitter",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Delayed members replicate chunk migrations with a delay."
    },
    {
        "id": 785,
        "Question": "A delayed member has its priority equal to 0 and hidden equal to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) flase",
            "c) true",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When you configure a delayed member, the delay applies both to replication and to the member’s oplog."
    },
    {
        "id": 786,
        "Question": "Which of the following ddds an arbiter to a replica set?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.addArb()",
            "b) rs.addArbiter()",
            "c) rs.addtoArb()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rs.addArb() adds a new arbiter to an existing replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 787,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The rs.status() method is a wrapper that runs the replSetGetStatus database command",
            "b) rs.freeze() provides a wrapper around the database command replSetFreeze",
            "c) rs.init() initializes a new replica set",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: rs.init() initializes a new replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 788,
        "Question": "_________ prevents the current member from seeking election as primary for a period of time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.freeze()",
            "b) rs.conf()",
            "c) rs.printReplicationInfo()",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rs.freeze() makes the current replica set member ineligible to become primary for the period specified."
    },
    {
        "id": 789,
        "Question": "_________ returns the replica set configuration document.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.freeze()",
            "b) rs.conf()",
            "c) rs.printReplicationInfo()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: rs.conf() returns a document that contains the current replica set configuration."
    },
    {
        "id": 790,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.printinfo() prints a formatted report of the replica set member’s oplog",
            "b) The output of rs.printReplicationInfo() is identical to that of db.printReplicationInfo()",
            "c) rs.printReplicationInfo() formats and prints the data returned by db.allReplicationInfo()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The rs.printReplicationInfo() in the mongo shell does not return JSON."
    },
    {
        "id": 791,
        "Question": "________ prints a report of the status of the replica set from the perspective of the primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.freeze()",
            "b) rs.printconf()",
            "c) rs.printReplicationInfo()",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Typically you will use db.fsyncUnlock() following a database backup operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 792,
        "Question": "_________ re-configures a replica set by applying a new replica set configuration object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.reconfig()",
            "b) rs.remove()",
            "c) rs.stepDown()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To reconfigure an existing replica set, first retrieve the current configuration with rs.conf(), modify the configuration document as needed, and then pass the modified document to rs.reconfig()."
    },
    {
        "id": 793,
        "Question": "__________ sets the member that this replica set member will sync from, overriding the default sync target selection logic.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.reconfig()",
            "b) rs.remove()",
            "c) rs.stepDown()",
            "d) rs.syncFrom()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: rs.syncFrom() provides a wrapper around the replSetSyncFrom, which allows administrators to configure the member of a replica set that the current member will pull data from."
    },
    {
        "id": 794,
        "Question": "rs.reconfig() provides a wrapper around the ___________ command.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetfinalReconfig",
            "b) replSetReconfig",
            "c) replSetReconfiguration",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The force parameter in reconfig method allows a reconfiguration command to be issued to a non-primary node."
    },
    {
        "id": 795,
        "Question": "________ sets the slaveOk property for the current connection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.reconfig()",
            "b) rs.slaveOk()",
            "c) rs.stepDown()",
            "d) rs.slave()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Use readPref() and Mongo.setReadPref() to set read preference."
    },
    {
        "id": 796,
        "Question": "Before mongod creates an oplog, you can specify its size with the __________ option.",
        "Options": [
            "a) oplogSizeMB",
            "b) oplogSizeGB",
            "c) opSizeMB",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  However, after you have started a replica set member for the first time, you can only change the size of the oplog using the Change the Size of the Oplog procedure."
    },
    {
        "id": 797,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The oplog is a special capped collection that keeps a rolling record of all operations that modify the data stored in your databases",
            "b) MongoDB applies database operations on the primary and then records the operations on the primary’s oplog",
            "c) The primary members then copy and apply these operations in an asynchronous process",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: All replica set members contain a copy of the oplog, in the local.oplog.rs collection, which allows them to maintain the current state of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 798,
        "Question": "The oplog must translate multi-updates into individual operations in order to maintain ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) availability",
            "b) idempotency",
            "c) scalability",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This can use a great deal of oplog space without a corresponding increase in data size or disk use."
    },
    {
        "id": 799,
        "Question": "Use _________ from a secondary member and the replication status output to assess the current state of replication.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.getReplInfo()",
            "b) db.getReplicationInfo()",
            "c) rs.printReplicationInfo()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This will determine if there is any unintended replication delay."
    },
    {
        "id": 800,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To facilitate replication, all replica set members send heartbeats (pings) to all other members",
            "b) For proper replication operations, entries in the oplog must be idempotent",
            "c) Any member can import oplog entries from any other member",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When you start a replica set member for the first time, MongoDB creates an oplog of a default size."
    },
    {
        "id": 801,
        "Question": "For a member to sync from another, both members must have the same value for the _________ setting.",
        "Options": [
            "a) buildIndexes",
            "b) getIndexes",
            "c) buildpriIndexes",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Beginning in version 2.2, secondaries avoid syncing from delayed members and hidden members."
    },
    {
        "id": 802,
        "Question": "Secondaries apply operations from the primary asynchronously to provide __________ consistency.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strict",
            "b) strong",
            "c) eventual",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In a replica set, the set can have at most one primary and only the primary can accept write operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 803,
        "Question": "When ______________ is true, the mongod instance saves all documents migrated from the shard to the moveChunk directory of the storage.dbPath.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sharding.archiveChunks",
            "b) sharding.archiveMovedChunks",
            "c) shards.archiveMovedChunks",
            "d) rs.syncFrom()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  MongoDB does not delete data stored in moveChunk."
    },
    {
        "id": 804,
        "Question": "Replication _______ is a delay between operation on the primary and the application of that operation from the oplog to the secondary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) lag",
            "b) delay",
            "c) latency",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Replication lag can be a significant issue and can seriously affect MongoDB replica set deployments."
    },
    {
        "id": 805,
        "Question": "A delayed member may show as 0 seconds behind the primary when the inactivity period on the primary is greater than the ________ value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) slaveDelayTime",
            "b) slaveDelay",
            "c) slaveTime",
            "d) rs.slave()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: slaveDelay is the number of seconds “behind” the primary that this replica set member should “lag”."
    },
    {
        "id": 806,
        "Question": "_________ shut down the mongod instance for one of the non-primary members of your replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.shutdown()",
            "b) db.shutdownServer()",
            "c) db.shutServer()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Restart this mongod as a standalone instance running on a different port and without the –replSet parameter."
    },
    {
        "id": 807,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To change the size of the oplog, you must perform maintenance on each member of the replica set in turn",
            "b) Always start rolling replica set maintenance with the secondaries, and finish with the maintenance on primary member",
            "c) The oplog exists internally as a capped collection",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In most cases the default oplog size is an acceptable size; however, in some situations you may need a larger or smaller oplog."
    },
    {
        "id": 808,
        "Question": "To finish the rolling maintenance operation, step down the primary with the _________ method.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.syncFrom()",
            "b) rs.stepDown()",
            "c) rs.synchrepl()",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The replica set member will recover and “catch up” before it is eligible for election to primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 809,
        "Question": "You also can force a member never to become primary by setting its priority value to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: You can force a replica set member to become primary by giving it a higher priority value than any other member in the set."
    },
    {
        "id": 810,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Replica sets allow a MongoDB deployment to remain available during the majority of a maintenance window",
            "b) Always start mongod with the same user, even when restarting a replica set member as a standalone instance",
            "c) The secondary takes time to catch up to the primary",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: From the mongo shell, use the rs.status() command to verify that the member has caught up from the RECOVERING state to the SECONDARY state."
    },
    {
        "id": 811,
        "Question": "A replica set member becomes _________ when its replication process falls so far behind that the primary overwrites oplog entries the member has not yet replicated.",
        "Options": [
            "a) stale",
            "b) state",
            "c) dead",
            "d) secondary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When this occurs, you must completely resynchronize the member by removing its data and performing an initial sync."
    },
    {
        "id": 812,
        "Question": "During initial sync, mongod will remove the content of the _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbPathSync",
            "b) Path",
            "c) dbPath",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can also force a mongod that is already a member of the set to perform initial sync by restarting the instance without the content of the dbPath."
    },
    {
        "id": 813,
        "Question": "You cannot use a _________backup for the data files, only a snapshot backup.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongorestore",
            "b) mongodump",
            "c) bsondump",
            "d) rs.syncFrom()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If copying data files, you must copy the content of the local database."
    },
    {
        "id": 814,
        "Question": "You can use the ________ setting in Replica Set Configuration to disable chained replication for situations where chained replication is causing lag.",
        "Options": [
            "a) chainingAllowed",
            "b) chainingDisAllowed",
            "c) chainingAllow",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MongoDB enables chained replication by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 815,
        "Question": "For most replica sets, the hostnames in the _________ field never change.",
        "Options": [
            "a) tag",
            "b) host",
            "c) rs",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Always use resolvable hostnames for the value of the host field in the replica set configuration to avoid confusion and complexity."
    },
    {
        "id": 816,
        "Question": "_________ prevents the current member from seeking election as primary for a period of time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetGetStatus",
            "b) replSetFreeze",
            "c) replSetInitiate",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The replSetFreeze command prevents a replica set member from seeking election for the specified number of seconds."
    },
    {
        "id": 817,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Primary capture data from the primary member to maintain an up to date copy of the sets’ data",
            "b) For some deployments, implementing a custom replication sync topology may be more effective than the default sync target selection logic",
            "c) MongoDB provides the ability to specify a host to use as a sync target",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: However, by default secondaries may automatically change their sync targets to secondary members based on changes in the ping time between members and the state of other members’ replication."
    },
    {
        "id": 818,
        "Question": "________ returns a document that reports on the status of the replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetGetStatus",
            "b) replSetFreeze",
            "c) replSetInitiate",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The replSetGetStatus command returns the status of the replica set from the point of view of the current server."
    },
    {
        "id": 819,
        "Question": "__________ enables or disables a maintenance mode, which puts a secondary node in a RECOVERING state.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetReconfig",
            "b) replSetMaintenance",
            "c) replSetStepDown",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The replSetMaintenance admin command enables or disables the maintenance mode for a secondary member of a replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 820,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To affect the sync target for the initial sync, run rs.syn() operation before initial sync",
            "b) If you run rs.syncFrom() during initial sync, MongoDB produces no error messages",
            "c) replSetSyncFrom and rs.syncFrom() provide a permanent override of default behavior",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The sync target falls more than 30 seconds behind another member of the replica set; the mongod will revert to the default sync target."
    },
    {
        "id": 821,
        "Question": "When enabled replSetMaintenance: true, the member enters the ________ state.",
        "Options": [
            "a) REPLICATING",
            "b) RECOVERING",
            "c) STALE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The member is not accessible for read operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 822,
        "Question": "________ applies a new configuration to an existing replica set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetReconfig",
            "b) replSetMaintenance",
            "c) replSetStepDown",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The replSetReconfig command modifies the configuration of an existing replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 823,
        "Question": "Which of the command is for master-slave replication only?",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetSyncFrom",
            "b) resync",
            "c) applyOps",
            "d) isMaster"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: resync forces a mongod to re-synchronize from the master."
    },
    {
        "id": 824,
        "Question": "_______ is an internal command that applies oplog entries to the current data set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetSyncFrom",
            "b) resync",
            "c) applyOps",
            "d) isMaster"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The applyOps command is primarily an internal command."
    },
    {
        "id": 825,
        "Question": "__________ explicitly override the default logic for selecting a member to replicate from.",
        "Options": [
            "a) replSetSyncFrom",
            "b) resync",
            "c) applyOps",
            "d) isMaster"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: replSetSyncFrom explicitly configures which host the current mongod pulls oplog entries from."
    },
    {
        "id": 826,
        "Question": "The ________ settings of replica set members affect the outcomes of elections for primary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) priority",
            "b) replication",
            "c) Initiate",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use this setting to ensure that some members are more likely to become primary and that others can never become primary."
    },
    {
        "id": 827,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The value of the member’s priority setting determines the member’s priority in elections",
            "b) The default value for the priority field is 3",
            "c) The value of priority can be any floating point (i.e. decimal) number between 0 and 500",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The higher the number, the higher the priority."
    },
    {
        "id": 828,
        "Question": "To modify priorities, you update the members _________ in the replica configuration object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) array",
            "b) tag",
            "c) mdimarray",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The array index begins with 0. Do not confuse this index value with the value of the replica set member’s _id field in the array."
    },
    {
        "id": 829,
        "Question": "The _________ shell method can force the current primary to step down, which causes an election.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.repliconfig()",
            "b) rs.config()",
            "c) rs.reconfig()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When the primary steps down, the mongod closes all client connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 830,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Before an election the primary opens all open client connections",
            "b) To block a member from seeking election as primary, assign it a priority of 0",
            "c) Hidden members, delayed members, and arbiters all have priority set to 0",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Reconfiguring priority can force the current primary to step down, leading to an election."
    },
    {
        "id": 831,
        "Question": "If the oplog is shorter than the slaveDelay window, the _______ member cannot successfully replicate operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) hidden",
            "b) delayed",
            "c) priority",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The length of the secondary slaveDelay must fit within the window of the oplog."
    },
    {
        "id": 832,
        "Question": "_________ members allow you to add additional members for read distribution beyond the maximum seven voting members.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Voting",
            "b) Non-voting",
            "c) Priority",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To configure a member as non-voting, set its votes value to 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 833,
        "Question": "Remove the secondary from the replica set by calling  ___________ method.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.removeRepli()",
            "b) rs.remove()",
            "c) rs.removeset()",
            "d) isMaster"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: rs.remove() removes the member described by the hostname parameter from the current replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 834,
        "Question": "______ returns basic help text for replica set functions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.printSlaveReplicationInfo()",
            "b) rs.printReplication()",
            "c) rs.help()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: rs.help() returns a basic help text for all of the replication related shell functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 835,
        "Question": "__________ prints a report of the status of the replica set from the perspective of the secondaries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rs.printSlaveReplicationInfo()",
            "b) rs.printReplication()",
            "c) rs.help()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rs.printSlaveReplicationInfo() returns a formatted report of the status of a replica set from the perspective of the secondary member of the set."
    },
    {
        "id": 836,
        "Question": "MongoDB uses _________ to support deployments with very large data sets and high throughput operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sharding",
            "b) replication",
            "c) replica sets",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sharding is a method for storing data across multiple machines."
    },
    {
        "id": 837,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) High query rates can exhaust the CPU capacity of the server",
            "b) Database systems with small data sets and high throughput applications can challenge the capacity of a single server",
            "c) Smaller data sets exceed the storage capacity of a single machine",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Working set sizes larger than the system’s RAM stress the I/O capacity of disk drives."
    },
    {
        "id": 838,
        "Question": "How many types of sharding exist in MongoDB?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB have two basic approaches: vertical scaling and sharding."
    },
    {
        "id": 839,
        "Question": "_______ scaling adds more CPU and storage resources to increase capacity.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Horizontal",
            "b) Vertical",
            "c) Partition",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When the primary steps down, the mongod closes all client connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 840,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scaling by adding capacity do not have limitations.",
            "b) cloud-based providers may only allow users to provision smaller instances",
            "c) There is a practical maximum capability for vertical scaling",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: High performance systems with large numbers of CPUs and large amount of RAM are disproportionately more expensive than smaller systems"
    },
    {
        "id": 841,
        "Question": "_______ divides the data set and distributes the data over multiple servers, or shards.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vertical",
            "b) Sharding",
            "c) Partition",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Each shard is an independent database, and collectively, the shards make up a single logical database."
    },
    {
        "id": 842,
        "Question": "MongoDB supports sharding through the configuration of a sharded ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) shapes",
            "b) clusters",
            "c) sets",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sharding reduces the number of operations each shard handles."
    },
    {
        "id": 843,
        "Question": "How many components are present in sharded cluster?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sharded cluster has the following components: shards, query routers and config servers."
    },
    {
        "id": 844,
        "Question": "To provide high availability and data consistency, in a production sharded cluster, each shard is a ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) replica set",
            "b) cluster",
            "c) partition",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Each shard stores less data as the cluster grows."
    },
    {
        "id": 845,
        "Question": "_________ interface with client applications and direct operations to the appropriate shard or shards.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Query Parsers",
            "b) Query Routers",
            "c) Query Executors",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The query router processes and targets operations to shards and then returns results to the clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 846,
        "Question": "A sharded cluster can contain __________ query router to divide the client request load.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) more than 1",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A client sends requests to one query router. Most sharded clusters have many query routers."
    },
    {
        "id": 847,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MongoDB distributes data, or shards, at the collection level",
            "b) To shard a document, you need to select a shard key",
            "c) MongoDB divides the shard key values into replica sets",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sharding partitions a collection’s data by the shard key."
    },
    {
        "id": 848,
        "Question": "________ servers store the cluster’s metadata.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Local",
            "b) Config",
            "c) Master",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This data contains a mapping of the cluster’s data set to the shards."
    },
    {
        "id": 849,
        "Question": "The query router uses __________ to target operations to specific shards.",
        "Options": [
            "a) metadata",
            "b) cluster",
            "c) replica",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For development and testing purposes only, each shard can be a single mongod instead of a replica set."
    },
    {
        "id": 850,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) For hash-based sharding, MongoDB divides the data set into ranges determined by the shard key values to provide hash based partitioning",
            "b) Cloud-based providers may only allow users to provision smaller instances",
            "c) For hash based partitioning, MongoDB computes a hash of a field’s value, and then uses these hashes to create chunks",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For range-based sharding, MongoDB divides the data set into ranges determined by the shard key values to provide range based partitioning."
    },
    {
        "id": 851,
        "Question": "Production sharded clusters have exactly ______ config servers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Do not deploy production clusters without 3 config servers."
    },
    {
        "id": 852,
        "Question": "A _________ key is either an indexed field or an indexed compound field that exists in every document in the collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cluster",
            "b) shard",
            "c) partition",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sharding partitions a collection’s data by the shard key."
    },
    {
        "id": 853,
        "Question": "To divide the shard key values into chunks, MongoDB uses _____ based partitioning.",
        "Options": [
            "a) range",
            "b) b tree",
            "c) document",
            "d) isMaster"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Hash based partitioning can also be used."
    },
    {
        "id": 854,
        "Question": "With hash based partitioning, two documents with _____ shard key values are unlikely to be part of the same chunk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) close",
            "b) open",
            "c) partially close",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This ensures a more random distribution of a collection in the cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 855,
        "Question": "_______ based partitioning, by contrast, ensures an even distribution of data at the expense of efficient range queries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hash",
            "b) Range",
            "c) Table",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hashed key values results in random distribution of data across chunks and therefore shards."
    },
    {
        "id": 856,
        "Question": "MongoDB allows administrators to direct the balancing policy using ______ aware sharding.",
        "Options": [
            "a) tag",
            "b) replica",
            "c) rack",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Administrators create and associate tags with ranges of the shard key, and then assign those tags to the shards."
    },
    {
        "id": 857,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Use sharded clusters if your data set approaches or exceeds the storage capacity of a single MongoDB instance",
            "b) Use sharded clusters if a single MongoDB instance can meet the demands of your write operations, and all other approaches have not reduced contention",
            "c) Use sharded clusters if the size of your system’s active working set will soon exceed the capacity of your system’s minimum RAM",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balancer is a background process that manages chunk migrations."
    },
    {
        "id": 858,
        "Question": "Tags are the primary mechanism to control the behavior of the _______ and the distribution of chunks in a cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Balancer",
            "b) Collector",
            "c) Compactor",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Tag aware sharding serves to improve the locality of data for sharded clusters that span multiple data centers"
    },
    {
        "id": 859,
        "Question": "How many background process runs behind balanced cluster?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB ensures a balanced cluster using two background process: splitting and the balancer."
    },
    {
        "id": 860,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To create splits, MongoDB does migrate any data or affect the shards",
            "b) The addition of new data or the addition of new servers can result in data distribution imbalances within the cluster",
            "c) The balancer can run from any of the query routers in a cluster",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balancer is a background process that manages chunk migrations."
    },
    {
        "id": 861,
        "Question": "_________ is a background process that keeps chunks from growing too large.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Splitting",
            "b) Balancing",
            "c) Chunking",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When a chunk grows beyond a specified chunk size, MongoDB splits the chunk in half. Inserts and updates triggers splits. "
    },
    {
        "id": 862,
        "Question": "The shards manage _______ migrations as a background operation between an origin shard and a destination shard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cluster",
            "b) shard",
            "c) chunk",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: During a chunk migration, the destination shard is sent all the current documents in the chunk from the origin shard."
    },
    {
        "id": 863,
        "Question": "For most deployments, the default value of chunk is _____ megabytes is ideal.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16",
            "b) 32",
            "c) 64",
            "d) 72"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Chunk size is user configurable."
    },
    {
        "id": 864,
        "Question": "The ______ instances are the routers for the cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mongod",
            "b) mongos",
            "c) collection",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Typically, deployments have one mongos instance on each application server."
    },
    {
        "id": 865,
        "Question": "A single sharded cluster must have exclusive use of its _______ servers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) local",
            "b) global",
            "c) config",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If you have multiple sharded clusters, you will need to have a group of config servers for each cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 866,
        "Question": "When a chunk grows beyond the chunk size, MongoDB attempts to split the chunk into smaller chunks, always based on ranges in the _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) replica set",
            "b) shard key",
            "c) tag sets",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Administrators create and associate tags with ranges of the shard key, and then assign those tags to the shards."
    },
    {
        "id": 867,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The shard key determines the distribution of the collection’s documents among the cluster’s shards",
            "b) The shard key is either an indexed field or an indexed compound field that exists in every document in the collection",
            "c) Each range, or chunk, defines a non-overlapping range of shard key values",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MongoDB distributes the chunks, and their documents, among the shards in the cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 868,
        "Question": "The index on the shard key cannot be a _________ index.",
        "Options": [
            "a) single",
            "b) multkikey",
            "c) unique",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Shard keys are immutable and cannot be changed after insertion."
    },
    {
        "id": 869,
        "Question": "Hashed shard keys use a ________ index of a single field as the shard key to partition data across your sharded cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) hashed",
            "b) unique",
            "c) multkikey",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The field you choose as your hashed shard key should have a good cardinality, or large number of different values."
    },
    {
        "id": 870,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hashed keys do not work well with fields that increase monotonically like ObjectId values or timestamps",
            "b) If you shard an empty collection using a hashed shard key, MongoDB will automatically create and migrate chunks so that each shard has two chunks",
            "c) Hashed keys work well with ObjectId values only",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hashed keys work well with fields that increase monotonically like ObjectId values or timestamps."
    },
    {
        "id": 871,
        "Question": "You can control how many chunks MongoDB will create with the ___________ parameter.",
        "Options": [
            "a) numChunks",
            "b) numInitialChunks",
            "c) numberofchunks",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Applications do not need to compute hashes."
    },
    {
        "id": 872,
        "Question": "MongoDB automatically computes the hashes when resolving queries using ______ indexes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) hashed",
            "b) unique",
            "c) muiltkey",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: During a chunk migration, the destination shard is sent all the current documents in the chunk from the origin shard."
    },
    {
        "id": 873,
        "Question": "MongoDB generates _______ values upon document creation to produce a unique identifier for the object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ObjectId",
            "b) CompId",
            "c) DoctId",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Some possible shard keys will allow your application to take advantage of the increased write capacity that the cluster can provide, while others do not."
    },
    {
        "id": 874,
        "Question": "A shard key that increases monotonically will not hinder performance if most of your write operations are ____ operations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) insert()",
            "b) update()",
            "c) delete()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Generally, choose shard keys that have both high cardinality and will distribute write operations across the entire cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 875,
        "Question": "The mongos provides an interface for applications to interact with sharded clusters that hides the complexity of data ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) partitioning",
            "b) replication",
            "c) sharding",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A mongos receives queries from applications, and uses metadata from the config server, to route queries to the mongod instances with the appropriate data."
    },
    {
        "id": 876,
        "Question": "The _________ process is responsible for redistributing the chunks of a sharded collection evenly among the shards for every sharded collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Balancer",
            "b) Sharder",
            "c) Replicator",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: By default, the balancer process is always enabled."
    },
    {
        "id": 877,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Splitting is the process MongoDB uses to distribute data of a sharded collection evenly across a sharded cluster",
            "b) Any mongos instance in the cluster can start a balancing round",
            "c) When a shard has too many of a sharded collection’s chunks compared to other shards, MongoDB splits balances the chunks across the shards",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a balancer process is active, the responsible mongos acquires a “lock” by modifying a document in the lock collection in the Config Database."
    },
    {
        "id": 878,
        "Question": "Use _______ migration to distribute data during bulk inserts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) automatic",
            "b) manual",
            "c) temporary",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Shard keys are immutable and cannot be changed after insertion."
    },
    {
        "id": 879,
        "Question": "The balancer process sends the _______ command to the source shard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) moveChunkShard",
            "b) migChunk",
            "c) moveChunk",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The source starts the move with an internal moveChunk command."
    },
    {
        "id": 880,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When fully synchronized, the destination shard connects to the config database and updates the cluster metadata with the new location for the chunk",
            "b) The destination shard builds any indexes required by the source that do not exist on the destination",
            "c) The destination shard begins requesting documents in the chunk and starts receiving copies of the data",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: After the destination shard completes the update of the metadata, and once there are no open cursors on the chunk, the source shard deletes its copy of the documents."
    },
    {
        "id": 881,
        "Question": "The source shard is responsible for incoming ______ operations for the chunk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) read",
            "b) write",
            "c) read-write",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: During the migration process, operations to the chunk route to the source shard."
    },
    {
        "id": 882,
        "Question": "________ can alter the behavior so that the delete phase of the current migration blocks the start of the next chunk migration.",
        "Options": [
            "a) _waitForUpdate",
            "b) _waitForDelete",
            "c) _waitForInsert",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The _waitForDelete is generally for internal testing purposes."
    },
    {
        "id": 883,
        "Question": "The default value _________ becomes true for all chunk migrations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) secThrottle",
            "b) secondaryThrottle",
            "c) primaryThrottle",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The new writeConcern field in the balancer configuration document allows you to specify a write concern semantics the _secondaryThrottle option."
    },
    {
        "id": 884,
        "Question": "You can set the _________ option on the balancer configuration to set different write concern semantics.",
        "Options": [
            "a) writeConcern",
            "b) updateConcern",
            "c) readConcern",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: By default, each document operation during chunk migration propagates to at least one secondary before the balancer proceeds with the next document"
    },
    {
        "id": 885,
        "Question": "With __________ enabled, the source shard archives the documents in the migrated chunks in a directory named after the collection namespace.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sharding.archiveChunks",
            "b) sharding.archiveMovedChunks",
            "c) shard.archiveMovedChunks",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Starting in MongoDB 2.6, sharding.archiveMovedChunks is enabled by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 886,
        "Question": "The ________ collection stores a document for each change to the metadata of a sharded collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) version",
            "b) changelog",
            "c) settings",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The config database is internal: applications and administrators should not modify or depend upon its content in the course of normal operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 887,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The local database supports sharded cluster operation",
            "b) The config database is a dependable API, and users should not write data to the config database in the course of normal operation or maintenance",
            "c) Modification of the config database on a functioning system may lead to instability or inconsistent data sets",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If you must modify the config database, use mongodump to create a full backup of the config database."
    },
    {
        "id": 888,
        "Question": "The _________ collection stores a document for each sharded collection in the cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) help",
            "b) shards",
            "c) collections",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Shard keys are immutable and cannot be changed after insertion."
    },
    {
        "id": 889,
        "Question": "You can return a list of the collections, with the following helper ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) show collects",
            "b) show collection",
            "c) show collections",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To access the config database, connect to a mongos instance in a sharded cluster, and use the following helper: use config."
    },
    {
        "id": 890,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database servers store the metadata for a sharded cluster",
            "b) Always back up the config database before doing any maintenance on the config server",
            "c) The mongos instances cache metadata and use it to route read and write operations to shards",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  The metadata reflects state and organization of the sharded data sets and system."
    },
    {
        "id": 891,
        "Question": "________ is a string that holds the address of the client, a mongos instance that initiates this change.",
        "Options": [
            "a) config.changelog.serverAddr",
            "b) config.changelog.clientAddr",
            "c) config.changelog.time",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: config.changelog.time is ISODate timestamp that reflects when the change occurred."
    },
    {
        "id": 892,
        "Question": "The _______ collection keeps track of the active components in the sharded cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) deploys",
            "b) lockpings",
            "c) locks",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The locks collection stores a distributed lock."
    },
    {
        "id": 893,
        "Question": "If the collection is empty then MongoDB will create the index as part of the ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) shardCollectionkey()",
            "b) shardCollection()",
            "c) keyCollection()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB provides no method to deactivate sharding for a collection after calling shardCollection. "
    },
    {
        "id": 894,
        "Question": "Changing the _______ option will change the port that mongod listens for incoming connections on.",
        "Options": [
            "a) –shardsrvkey",
            "b) –shardsrv",
            "c) –shard",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The single-shard cluster is now a non-sharded replica set that will accept read and write operations on the data set."
    },
    {
        "id": 895,
        "Question": "The _____________ collection holds documents for each tagged shard key range in the cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) tags",
            "b) databases",
            "c) version",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The version collection holds the current metadata version number."
    },
    {
        "id": 896,
        "Question": "Split empty chunks in your collection by manually performing the ______ command on chunks.",
        "Options": [
            "a) distrbute",
            "b) split",
            "c) change",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The config database is internal: applications and administrators should not modify or depend upon its content in the course of normal operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 897,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pre-splitting the chunk ranges in an empty sharded collection allows clients to insert data into an already partitioned collection",
            "b) MongoDB cannot create enough chunks or distribute data fast enough to support required throughput",
            "c) Chunk migration does not require copying all the data in the chunk from one shard to another",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In most situations a sharded cluster will create and distribute chunks automatically without user intervention."
    },
    {
        "id": 898,
        "Question": "MongoDB provides the _________ command to combine contiguous chunk ranges into a single chunk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) helpchunks",
            "b) moveChunks",
            "c) mergeChunks",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For a sharded collection, mergeChunks combines contiguous chunk ranges on a shard into a single chunk. Issue the mergeChunks command from a mongos instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 899,
        "Question": "Use ________ to determine the current chunk ranges across the cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.collects()",
            "b) sh.status()",
            "c) sh.results()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To access the config database, connect to a mongos instance in a sharded cluster, and use the following helper: use config"
    },
    {
        "id": 900,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If a collection already has data, MongoDB automatically splits the collection’s data when you enable sharding for the collection",
            "b) Subsequent attempts to manually create splits can lead to unpredictable chunk ranges and sizes as well as inefficient or ineffective balancing behavior",
            "c) MongoDB creates splits only after an insert operation",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The default behavior suppresses the detailed chunk information if the total number of chunks is greater than or equal to 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 901,
        "Question": "__________ splits the chunk that contains the shard key value specified by the query at the chunk’s median point.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.Find()",
            "b) sh.splitFind()",
            "c) sh.split()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sh.splitFind() creates two roughly equal chunks."
    },
    {
        "id": 902,
        "Question": "_________ splits a chunk at the shard key value specified by the query.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.Find()",
            "b) sh.splitFind()",
            "c) sh.split()",
            "d) sh.splitAt"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In most circumstances, you should leave chunk splitting to the automated processes within MongoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 903,
        "Question": "sh.splitFind () Splits the chunk that contains the shard key value specified by the query at the chunk’s ______ point.",
        "Options": [
            "a) smean",
            "b) stdev",
            "c) median",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It may be beneficial to pre-split manually an empty collection using methods such as sh.splitFind()."
    },
    {
        "id": 904,
        "Question": "The mergeChunks command requires at least _______ empty input chunk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) one",
            "b) two",
            "c) three",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  MergeChunks merge two contiguous chunks on the same shard, where at least one of the contains no data."
    },
    {
        "id": 905,
        "Question": "The chunkSize and ________ options, passed at startup to the mongos, do not affect the chunk size after you have initialized the cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) –Size",
            "b) –chunkSize",
            "c) –chunk",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Modifying the chunk size has several limitations."
    },
    {
        "id": 906,
        "Question": "The preferred way to clear the _________ flag from a chunk is to attempt to split the chunk.",
        "Options": [
            "a) boolean",
            "b) jumbo",
            "c) change",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the chunk is divisible, MongoDB removes the flag upon successful split of the chunk."
    },
    {
        "id": 907,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In some instances, MongoDB cannot split the no-longer jumbo chunk, such as a chunk with a range of single shard key value",
            "b) To ensure that mongos instances update their cluster information cache, run flushConfig in the admin database",
            "c) In a sharded cluster, you cannot use tags to associate specific ranges of a shard key with a specific shard or subset of shards",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If you clear the jumbo flag for a chunk that still exceeds the chunk size and/or the document number limit, MongoDB will re-label the chunk as jumbo when MongoDB tries to move the chunk."
    },
    {
        "id": 908,
        "Question": "_________ is used to remove tags from a particular shard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.removeTag()",
            "b) sh.removeShard()",
            "c) sh.removeShardTag()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You may remove tags from a particular shard using the sh.removeShardTag() method when connected to a mongos instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 909,
        "Question": "________ associates a shard with a tag or identifier.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.collects()",
            "b) sh.addShardTag",
            "c) sh.results()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MongoDB uses these identifiers to direct chunks that fall within a tagged range to specific shards."
    },
    {
        "id": 910,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You cannot overlap defined ranges, or tag the same range more than once",
            "b) The mongod provides a helper for removing a tag range",
            "c) The output from sh.status() lists tags associated with a shard, if any, for each shard",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mongod does not provide a helper for removing a tag range."
    },
    {
        "id": 911,
        "Question": "To assign a tag to a range of shard keys use the _________ method when connected to a mongos instance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.addTagRange()",
            "b) sh.splitFind()",
            "c) sh.Range()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You may delete tag assignment from a shard key range by removing the corresponding document from the tags collection of the config database."
    },
    {
        "id": 912,
        "Question": "Each document in the tags holds the ________ of the sharded collection and a minimum shard key value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) tag",
            "b) chunk",
            "c) namespace",
            "d) size"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In most circumstances, you should leave chunk splitting to the automated processes within MongoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 913,
        "Question": "Which of the following parameter represents minimum value of the shard key range to include in the tag?",
        "Options": [
            "a) min",
            "b) max",
            "c) maximum",
            "d) minimum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The minimum is an inclusive match."
    },
    {
        "id": 914,
        "Question": "Use ________ to ensure that the balancer migrates documents that exist within the specified range to a specific shard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.addShardTag()",
            "b) sh.addTag()",
            "c) sh.aShardTag()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Only issue sh.addTagRange() when connected to a mongos instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 915,
        "Question": "Which of the following parameter denotes name of the shard from which to remove a tag?",
        "Options": [
            "a) shard",
            "b) tag",
            "c) chunk",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Shard is of string type."
    },
    {
        "id": 916,
        "Question": "_______ runs a database command against the admin database of a mongos instance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh._checkFullName()",
            "b) sh._adminCommand()",
            "c) sh.getBalancerLockDetails()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sh._adminCommand() runs a database command against the admin database, like db.runCommand(), but can confirm that it is issued against a mongos."
    },
    {
        "id": 917,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The unique constraint on indexes ensures that only one document can have a value for a field in a collection",
            "b) MongoDB support creating new unique indexes in sharded collections",
            "c) If you use a compound shard key, you cannot enforce uniqueness on the combination of component keys in the shard key",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For sharded collections these unique indexes cannot enforce uniqueness because insert and indexing operations are local to each shard."
    },
    {
        "id": 918,
        "Question": "________ tests to see if the mongo shell is connected to a mongos instance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh._checkMongos()",
            "b) sh.addShard()",
            "c) sh._lastMigration()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The sh._checkMongos() method throws an error message if the mongo shell is not connected to a mongos instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 919,
        "Question": "_______ reports on the active balancer lock, if it exists.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh._checkFullName()",
            "b) sh._adminCommand()",
            "c) sh.getBalancerLockDetails()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sh._checkFullName() tests a namespace to determine if its well formed."
    },
    {
        "id": 920,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The best way to ensure a field has unique values is to generate universally unique identifiers (UUID,) such as MongoDB’s ‘ObjectId values",
            "b) Most deployments will not need to shard the files collection",
            "c) The files collection is typically small, and only contains metadata",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None of the required keys for GridFS lend themselves to an even distribution in a sharded situation."
    },
    {
        "id": 921,
        "Question": "_________ reports on the last chunk migration.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh._checkMongos()",
            "b) sh.addShard()",
            "c) sh._lastMigration()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The sh._lastMigration() method returns a document with details about the last migration performed on the database or collection. "
    },
    {
        "id": 922,
        "Question": "_________ removes an association between a range shard keys and a shard tag.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.removeTagRange()",
            "b) sh._checkMongos()",
            "c) sh.disableBalancing()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use sh.removeShardTag() to ensure that unused or out of date ranges are removed and hence chunks are balanced as required."
    },
    {
        "id": 923,
        "Question": "_________ disable balancing on a single collection in a sharded database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.removeTagRange()",
            "b) sh._checkMongos()",
            "c) sh.disableBalancing()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sh.disableBalancing() does not affect balancing of other collections in a sharded cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 924,
        "Question": "_______ activates the sharded collection balancer process if previously disabled using sh.disableBalancing().",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.getBalancerHost()",
            "b) sh.enableBalancing()",
            "c) sh.enableSharding()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sh.enableSharding() enables sharding on a specific database."
    },
    {
        "id": 925,
        "Question": "________ returns a boolean to report if the balancer is currently enabled.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.getBalancerHost()",
            "b) sh.enableBalancing()",
            "c) sh.getBalancerState()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sh.getBalancerState() returns true when the balancer is enabled and false if the balancer is disabled."
    },
    {
        "id": 926,
        "Question": "_______ enables the balancer and waits for balancing to start.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.waitForBalancer()",
            "b) sh.startBalancer()",
            "c) sh.waitForDLock()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sh.waitForDLock() waits for a specified distributed sharded cluster lock."
    },
    {
        "id": 927,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.deadForDLock() waits for a specified distributed sharded cluster lock",
            "b) sh.waitForBalancerOff() waits until the balancer stops running",
            "c) sh.statusserver() reports on the status of a sharded cluster, as db.printShardingStatus()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sh.stopBalancer() disables the balancer and waits for any in progress balancing rounds to complete."
    },
    {
        "id": 928,
        "Question": "_________ waits for a change in ping state from one of the mongos in the sharded cluster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sh.waitForBalancer()",
            "b) sh.startBalancer()",
            "c) sh.waitForPingChange()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sh.waitForBalancer() waits for the balancer state to change."
    },
    {
        "id": 929,
        "Question": "_______ forces an update to the cluster metadata cached by a mongos.",
        "Options": [
            "a) config",
            "b) flushconf",
            "c) flushRouterConfig",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: flushRouterConfig clears the current cluster information cached by a mongos instance and reloads all sharded cluster metadata from the config database."
    },
    {
        "id": 930,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) moveChunks provides the ability to combine chunks on a single shard",
            "b) setShardVersion is used to set the config server version",
            "c) shardCollection enables the sharding functionality for a collection, allowing the collection to be sharded",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: For a sharded collection, mergeChunks combines contiguous chunk ranges on a shard into a single chunk."
    },
    {
        "id": 931,
        "Question": "Which of the following command that validates index on shard key?",
        "Options": [
            "a) checkShardingIndex",
            "b) checkSIndex",
            "c) enableSharding",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: checkShardingIndex is an internal command that supports sharding functionality. "
    },
    {
        "id": 932,
        "Question": "Which of the following command is used to determine split points?",
        "Options": [
            "a) splitVector",
            "b) medianKey",
            "c) movePrimary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: movePrimary\treassigns the primary shard when removing a shard from a sharded cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 933,
        "Question": "You can only issue listShards against the ________ database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) local",
            "b) admin",
            "c) temp",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: listShards is only available for mongos instances."
    },
    {
        "id": 934,
        "Question": "_________ is an internal command that supports the sharding functionality.",
        "Options": [
            "a) getBalancerHost()",
            "b) getShardMap",
            "c) enableSharding()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sh.getBalancerHost() returns the name of a mongos that’s responsible for the balancer process."
    },
    {
        "id": 935,
        "Question": "________ command verifies that a process is a mongos.",
        "Options": [
            "a) medianKey",
            "b) isdbgrid",
            "c) movePrimary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The isdbgrid command is not available to mongod."
    }
]